<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<language id="33">
<page id="13" title="Boardcomp. Misc" descr="Various fragments spoken by shipboard comp. voice" voice="yes">
 <t id="1501">{17,10009}</t>
</page>
<page id="17" title="Boardcomp. objects" descr="0">
 <t id="10008">{17,80096}</t>
 <t id="10009">{17,80142}</t>
 <t id="10010">{17,80142}</t>
 <t id="10011">{17,80142}</t>
 <t id="10012">{17,80142}</t>
 <t id="10013">{17,80142}</t>
 <t id="10014">{17,10007} {1999,3}</t>
 <t id="10015">{17,10006} {1999,3}</t>
 <t id="10016">{17,80142}</t>
 <t id="10025">Explorer</t>
 <t id="10026">{9,515}{9,500}{9,517}</t>
 <t id="12191">zzPLACEHOLDER GAZZ</t>
 <t id="16391">{1000,119} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="16712">The M8 Toukon-Class Heavy-Bomber is a new addition to the Yaki fleet which is based upon the Paranid M8 Hades, having been reverse-engineered and customized to suit Yaki requirements.\n\nCompared to the Paranid M8 Hades, the Toukon is noticeably swifter, boasting improved speed, acceleration, and manoeuvrability. However, this enhanced alacrity has come at at the cost of just about every other system, with the bomber's shields and weapons being hit the hardest as the Toukon shunts all of its power into the afterburners for speed, and then whatever is left over into the inertial dampeners and gyroscopic stabilizers to prevent the ship from ripping itself apart.\n\nSuffice to say, the Toukon does not handle itself well in a dogfight.\n\nHowever, the Toukon was never intended to get involved in direct skirmishes and confrontations with other fighters at all. It was designed with one very specific mission in mind: to jump into an enemy sector, deliver its payload at targets of opportunity upon the trade-lanes, and then fade back out again before any other ships can retaliate against it.\n\nTo suit this end, the Toukon hosts a larger cargo bay than the M8 Hades, allowing it carry enough fuel to jump half-way across the galaxy and back without bringing an enemy fleet with it.\n\nThis larger holding capacity is especially useful considering that the primary target for the Toukon's aggression happens to be the Teladi Company, and whatever Profit Guild ships happen to stray into its crosshairs: for the Yaki do not forgive, and they do not forget, and the Teladi aren't the only ones who keep old debts in mind - especially debts paid in blood.</t>
 <t id="65000">{1000,2040006} &quot;{17,10771}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65001">ATF Flagship &quot;Valhalla&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65002">{1000,2040008} &quot;{17,16891}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65003">ATF Command Ship &quot;Freyja&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65004">{1000,140008} &quot;{17,4701}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65005">Argon Command Ship &quot;Atlas&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65006">{1000,140006} &quot;{17,5091}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65007">Argon Flagship &quot;Argon One&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65008">{1000,240006} &quot;{1000,1024}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65009">Boron Flagship &quot;Blue Storm&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65010">{1000,240008} &quot;{17,5521}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65011">Boron Command Ship &quot;Blue Arrow&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65012">{1000,440006} &quot;{1000,1042}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65013">Paranid Flagship &quot;Maximus's Pride&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65014">{1000,340008} &quot;{1000,1034} {1000,60005}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65015">Split Command Ship &quot;Whi's Assassin&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65016">{1000,340006} &quot;{1000,1020} {17,90208}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65017">Split Flagship &quot;Matriarch's Wolf&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65018">{1000,1050} {1000,40008} &quot;{17,6231}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65019">Talonfire Command Ship &quot;Penatron&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65020">{1000,540006} &quot;{7,30050}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65021">Teladi Flagship &quot;CEO's Investment&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65022">{1000,840008} &quot;{17,3811}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65023">Pirate Command Ship &quot;Orinoco&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65024">{1000,840006} &quot;{17,16751}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65025">Pirate Flagship &quot;Polacca&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65026">{1000,1940008} &quot;{17,6321}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65027">Yaki Command Ship &quot;Midnight Star&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65028">{1000,1940006} &quot;{17,13081}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65029">Yaki Flagship &quot;Shuri&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65030">{1000,1840008} &quot;{17,16441}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65031">Terran Command Ship &quot;Excalibur&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65032">{1000,1840006} &quot;{17,13131}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65033">Terran Flagship &quot;McCallum&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65034">{1000,640008} {9,525}</t>
 <t id="65035">Xenon Command Ship Z \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65036">{1000,540008} &quot;{17,6271}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65037">Teladi Command Ship &quot;The Wise Guy&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="65038">{1000,440008} &quot;{1000,1096} {7,1021706}&quot;</t>
 <t id="65039">Paranid Command Ship &quot;Duke's Redemption&quot;</t>
 <t id="80000">{17,3111}</t>
 <t id="80001">The Mk I Colossus was the main flag ship of the Argon fleet. Now decommissioned, it is still available for purchase from specialist ship factories on the borders of Argon space.</t>
 <t id="80002">{17,3121}</t>
 <t id="80003">The Mk I Titan was the Argon fleet's primary destroyer and was instrumental in driving back the Khaak at the Battle of Omycron Lyrae. While not as advanced as the modern Titan, the Mk I is still useful as a light destroyer and can be picked up at a bargain price from specialist retailers.</t>
 <t id="80004">{17,4111}</t>
 <t id="80005">The Mk I Centaur was the Argon military's first attempt at an M6 class corvette. Quickly replaced by the much more advanced Mk. 2, the Mk I can still be found for sale from specialist suppliers.</t>
 <t id="80006">{17,4131}</t>
 <t id="80007">The Mk I Nova was the first M3 class ship to feature a rear turret and was the mainstay heavy fighter of the Argon Fleet for many jazuras. It is not as fast or powerful as the Mk. 2 but it can still hold its own against smaller craft.</t>
 <t id="80008">{17,3141}</t>
 <t id="80009">The first incarnation of the Buster was one of the very first fighters produced by the Argon Military. Its aging design has poor speed and manoueverability compared to modern equivalents. However, the Mk I has found a niche as the bargain M4 of the galaxy and can still be seen defending stations in the distant border sectors.</t>
 <t id="80010">{17,3151}</t>
 <t id="80011">The Mk I Discoverer has a special place in the hearts of many veteran pilots as their first experience of piloting a ship. While not as fast as the current model, it is still of use as a bargain scout ship.</t>
 <t id="80012">{17,3161}</t>
 <t id="80013">The Mk I Mammoth was the first of the heavy TL class ships to come into service. Production of the Mk I did not last long as the Mk. 2 has a much larger cargo capacity. Second hand models are still in demand in border sectors with first time entrepreneurs looking for a cheap TL.</t>
 <t id="80014">{17,4171}</t>
 <t id="80015">The original model of the Mercury was underpowered, small and had little defence against the ever increasing pirate threat. It is now rarely seen in all but the most remote sectors.</t>
 <t id="80016">{17,4161}</t>
 <t id="80017">Often a favourite of veteran explorers, the Mk I Express is a reminder of by-gone days when looks were often considered more important than speed or shielding.</t>
 <t id="80018">{17,3211}</t>
 <t id="80019">The Mk I Shark was the first carrier produced by the Kingdon of Boron. However, cramped conditions and poor water recycling facilities meant it was rapidly phased out of service. It can now be found only at specialist dealers.</t>
 <t id="80020">{17,3221}</t>
 <t id="80021">When the Mk I Ray came into service it was said that the design was perfection. However, an overlooked design fault meant that the rotating tail which powered the ships water recycling needed constant maintainance to keep it operational. The Mk I is now little more than a museum piece and is often shown to young Boron engineers as an example of the dangers of over-complicating things.</t>
 <t id="80022">{17,4231}</t>
 <t id="80023">The Mk I Barracuda was the first fighter produced by the Kingdom to rely solely on Boron technology. Before it was superceded by the current model, the Mk I was regarded as one of the best all-round fighters in its class. It can still be found for sale at specialist dealers in border sectors.</t>
 <t id="80024">{17,4241}</t>
 <t id="80025">The first design of the Mako was a fusion of Boron and Argon technology. For this reason the Boron found it difficult to service the craft and it rapidly fell out of favour with the military. The Mk I still has good speed and shielding, although its weapon capabilities are not up to modern standards.</t>
 <t id="80026">{17,3251}</t>
 <t id="80027">The fastest ship in its class when it was launched, the Mk I Octopus is rarely seen today. Its aging design requires frequent servicing and parts are very difficult to come by.</t>
 <t id="80028">{17,4211}</t>
 <t id="80029">When news broke that other races were developing a new M6 class of craft, the Boron rushed out the Mk 1. Hydra. However, it was not competitive with the other races' corvette designs and the elongated spikes along its body frequent broke off during high-g manouevers. It can still be found in remote Boron sectors and is still available from specialist retailers.</t>
 <t id="80030">AP Gunner</t>
 <t id="80031">The AP Gunner is a legendary ship of old Earth Fleet design. It is revered in Gonar history as being instrumental in protecting Earth from invasion. When the ship was rediscovered a few years ago its design was copied by enthusiasts and is now available in a heavily modified and upgraded form from specialist retailers.</t>
 <t id="80032">AP Gunner - Damaged</t>
 <t id="80033">The AP Gunner is a legendary ship of old Earth Fleet design. It is revered in Gonar history as being instrumental in protecting Earth from invasion. When the ship was rediscovered a few years ago its design was copied by enthusiasts and is now available in a heavily modified and upgraded form from specialist retailers.</t>
 <t id="80034">{17,3511}</t>
 <t id="80035">The Mk I Condor was the Teladi military's first attempt at creating an M1 class carrier. True to teladi traditions the Mk I was bulky and slow, but had a very large cargo capacity and was very heavily shielded. It can still be found for sale in Teladi border sectors.</t>
 <t id="80036">{17,3521}</t>
 <t id="80037">In true Teladi style, the Mk I Phoenix was created from technology "bought" from the Boron and the Paranid. Asthetics were of little importance to the Teladi engineers as they concentrated on shielding and weapons. It is sometimes still used to defend stations in remote Teladi sectors.</t>
 <t id="80038">{17,3531}</t>
 <t id="80039">The Mk I Falcon is typical of early Teladi fighter design in that it is based on other races technology. The Mk I is a hybrid of Boron and Argon fighter design and thus is difficult to maintain. The changes made to the engines to make them compatible with the rest of the ship meant that the Mk I suffered from a major speed deficit compared to its competitors from the other races.</t>
 <t id="80040">{17,4541}</t>
 <t id="80041">Featuring a fuselage licenced from the Boron, the Mk I Buzzard was the mainstay of the Teladi fleet until its replacement with the Mk. 2. It can be purchased from specialist retailers and can still be useful as a light courier.</t>
 <t id="80042">{17,4551}</t>
 <t id="80043">The Mk I Harrier was developed to replace the Bat which was known as one of the slowest ships in the galaxy. However, the Mk I failed to improve on the Bat's speed and was quickly replaced by the Mk. 2. Due to its large cargo capacity the Mk I still has a use as courier ship in the poorer, border sectors.</t>
 <t id="80044">{17,4511}</t>
 <t id="80045">When the other races started devloping the M6 class of ship, Teladi spys managed to buy stolen plans to the prototype Argon Centaur. From this desing the Teladi devloped the Mk I Osprey. It was a Centaur at its heart and quickly became notorious for its compatiblity with early versions of the Phased Shockwave Generator. The retrofitted version available today is not longer compatible with the current model of the PSG and is thus no longer the formidable opponent it once was.</t>
 <t id="80046">{17,3311}</t>
 <t id="80047">Commissioned during the Boron Campaign the Mk I Raptor quickly became notorious because of the huge numbers of suicidal split pilots that would launch from its docking bays. Today the Mk I is still manufactured by specialist ship factories on the edge of Split space.</t>
 <t id="80048">{17,3321}</t>
 <t id="80049">Captains of the Mk I Python were reknowned as being aggressive, stubborn and, more often than not, suicidal. It was freqently known for Mk I captains to ram an opponent rather than to admit defeat. When the Mk. 2 was launched the Split government looked for more passive captains as the Split economy simply could not afford to keep manufacturing Pythons at the rate they were being destroyed. It is still something of a rite of passage for young Split captains to take a Mk I into Xenon space.</t>
 <t id="80050">{17,3331}</t>
 <t id="80051">In its day the Mk I Mamba was one of the most deadly fighters available with weapon systems that would normally only be found on much larger ships. It is highly manoueverable and fast at the expense of shielding and was a popular ship amoungst the more dare-devil dogfighter pilots.</t>
 <t id="80052">{17,3341}</t>
 <t id="80053">In true Split style the Mk I Scorpion was fast and feaured weapons normally found on M3 class fighters. Due to its poor shielding it quickly ran out of favour with the Split military and was replaced with the Mk. 2. The Mk I can still be found for sale at remote ship factories, often at bargain prices.</t>
 <t id="80054">{17,4351}</t>
 <t id="80055">One of the fastest M5 class ships ever produced the Mk I Jaguar is a popular entrant in the Classic Ship Races in Freedom's Reach. Although it is not as fast as the current Jaguar model its relative ease to maintain has kept it popular amoungst the racing fraternity.</t>
 <t id="80056">{17,4311}</t>
 <t id="80057">Often regarded as one of the most beautiful ships ever designed, the Mk I Dragon amazed the other races as being a complete departure usual Split design. However, after the Dragon Incident Split pilots regarded this ship as cursed, forcing the Split military to redesign the ship along more conventional lines. Today the Mk I is much sort after as personal yachts amoungst the playboys and celebrities of the galaxy.</t>
 <t id="80058">{17,3411}</t>
 <t id="80059">The Mk I Zeus was once the most feared Paranid ship by Argon pilots. Its huge docking bay housed several wings of fighters and its weaponry almost as good as a destroyers. The Mk I can still be found for sale at specialist retailers in remote areas of Paranid space.</t>
 <t id="80060">{17,3421}</t>
 <t id="80061">The Mk I Odysseus is a far cry from the current Odysseus's sleek design. It is bulky and ugly, but packs quite a punch and could once be frequently found making solo forrays into Xenon territory. Its weaponry and shielding are excellent and it can still hold its own against more modern ships.</t>
 <t id="80062">{17,4931}</t>
 <t id="80063">The Mk I Perseus raised a few eyebrows when it was originally commissioned, although the Paranid Government insisted any similarities between it and the other races ships was entirely accidental. The Mk I was well shielded for its time but suffered from a relatively small cargo bay making it unsuitable for any long distance flights.</t>
 <t id="80064">{17,4441}</t>
 <t id="80065">The Mk I Pericles caused an galaxy wide controversy when it first appeared, with the Boron Government insisting that it contained stolen Boron technology. Although this was denyed by the Paranid, the Mk I was rapidly replaced with a model featuring a more traditional Paranid design. It can still be found for sale at specialist retailers in the far reaches of Paranid space.</t>
 <t id="80066">{17,3451}</t>
 <t id="80067">The Mk I Pegasus was a rather conventional ship design in its time with one interesting aspect. Its engine design had a flaw which enabled them to be tuned far beyond what was considered safe at the time. The Mk I Pegasus held the gate-to-gate speed record for many jazuras before it was broken by the Arrow. Today, the parts required to over-tune the engines are no longer produced limiting the Mk I to more conventional speeds.</t>
 <t id="80068">{17,4411}</t>
 <t id="80069">The Mk I Nemesis was the Paranid Military's first attempt at a corvette class ship. Although it is well shielded and fast, its limited cargo capacity meant it was rapidly replaced with the newer Mk. 2 design. Today, the Mk I is only occasionally found in remote border sectors with the majority of owners having traded them in for newer models.</t>
 <t id="80070">{17,80104} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80071">Decommissioned Shipyards produce old, decomissioned ships. The ships designs have been retrofitted for compatibility with modern shields and weapons and are often availble at very reduced prices.</t>
 <t id="80072">{17,3611}</t>
 <t id="80073">The Mk I J was first encountered during the Xenon conflict. It has a large docking bay and is heavily armed. Although Xenon use of this design of ship has ceased, the J design has been copied by specialist retailers and is currently available for very competitive prices.</t>
 <t id="80074">{17,3621}</t>
 <t id="80075">The first design of the K, called the Mk I by Xenon researchers, was a fearsome opponent. It was heavily shielded and much faster than other ships in its class. It is rumoured that the design has been reverse engineered and that the K can now be bought from specialist retailers.</t>
 <t id="80076">{17,3631}</t>
 <t id="80077">The Mk I L was the first heavy fighter the Xenon were seen using. It is fast, manoueverable and heavily armed. It has not been seen in use by the Xenon for many jazuras, however captured ships have been retrofitted and are available from specialist ship factories.</t>
 <t id="80078">{17,3641}</t>
 <t id="80079">The Mk I M is an old class of ship used by the Xenon during the Xenon Conflict. They have now updated the design but the original ship can be found for sale at specialist retailers, retrofitted for compatiblity with modern shields and weapons.</t>
 <t id="80080">{17,3651}</t>
 <t id="80081">The Mk I N was first introduced towards the end of the Xenon Conflict. It has now been replaced by a newer design. The Mk I N was easily captured enabling Argon scientists to study Xenon technology up close. The ship can still be useful as a cheap scout ship and is available from specialist ship factories.</t>
 <t id="80082">{17,4311} {17,80096} {9,500} {17,10022}</t>
 <t id="80083">The Mk I(a) Dragon Prototype is the brain child of an ex-Split military engineer. It was reported that he was removed from his post shortly after the Dragon incident and it was he who gave the Mk1 Dragon its distinctive design. In an effort to keep his dream alive he has been developing the old design, boosting its power output, weapons, speed and shields. However, it has been rumoured that the ship is very unstable and that the aging design simply cannot handle the stresses the enhanced systems put on it.</t>
 <t id="80084">{17,5151}</t>
 <t id="80085">It has been rumoured that a Teladi gangster has managed to aquire some blueprints for many advanced and prototype military ships. Under the cover of a scrap dealer he is manufacturing and selling these ships at a high price. The military of all the races are working together to trace the location of this shipyard and close the operation down. It has been reported that the shipyard can be found in a pirate sector near the borders of Teladi space. There are nav beacons in the area to lead pilots to its location. The authorities are worried that many of these unfinished designs have already flooded the market and are a danger to anyone who purchases them.</t>
 <t id="80086">{17,10311} {17,10022}</t>
 <t id="80087">{17,10312}</t>
 <t id="80088">{17,10021} {17,10411}</t>
 <t id="80089">{17,10412}</t>
 <t id="80090">{17,10024} {17,10211}</t>
 <t id="80091">{17,10212}</t>
 <t id="80092">{17,10021} {17,10511}</t>
 <t id="80093">{17,10512}</t>
 <t id="80094">{1000,122} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80095">This is the main facility belonging to the Terran AGI Task Force (ATF). It is the home of all their intelligence gathering activities. They have recently begun selling their customised ships in a bid to raise funding to battle the ever-increasing AGI threat.</t>
 <t id="80096">Mk I</t>
 <t id="80098">{17,5141}</t>
 <t id="80099">For several Jazuras Paranid Intelligence operatives have been aquiring blueprints for many advanced and prototype military ships from all the other races in order to keep up with their latest developments. However, due to recent poor economic performance, the Paranid Government have authorised a secret shipyard to be built to manufacture these ships for resale at extortionate prices, including some of their own prototype ships. The location of this shipyard is unknown, but it is rumoured that it is under the cover of a salvage merchant in order to give the Paranid government denyability and located in one of the Paranid border sectors. It is reported that there is a gate to an unknown sector nearby so the base can be quickly evacuated and destroyed should the other races' intelligence forces discover it.</t>
 <t id="80100">{1000,109} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80101">The Goner have built this shipyard in order to give its members access to more peaceful means of space travel. As most races' ships are well armed, the Goners have shunned purchasing from standard shipyards. This new shipyard now caters for their needs.</t>
 <t id="80104">Decomissioned</t>
 <t id="80106">{17,16481}</t>
 <t id="80107">The M3B Quasar-Class Strike Bomber is a recent addition to the Argon Navy that hails from the shipyards of Omycron Lyrae. \n\nWhile less manoeuvrable than most fighters, the Quasar makes up for the difference by being able to mount an impressive amount of heavy ordinance within its distinctive frame.\n\nThough less powerful than the more conventional M8 Bombers, and unable to mount and store as many warheads as its larger counterpart, the Quasar has an added advantage of being cheaper to produce and being small enough to be deployed from carriers of variable sizes in large numbers, marking them as a substantial problem for any ship or sector that happens to be on the wrong side of the Argon Federation.</t>
 <t id="80108">{1000,121} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80109">{17,16042}</t>
 <t id="80112">{17,16531}</t>
 <t id="80113">The Boron M3B Guppy-Class Strike-Bomber is relatively recent addition to the Boron Royal Navy, and a somewhat revolutionary concept for the Kingdom of Boron itself.\n\nUsing the M3 Skate as a foundation for the chassis, the Guppy remains little more than a strike-variant of that fighter that has been retrofitted to carry a payload of missiles instead of weapons systems.\n\nWhile this deritative concept suggests naivity from the Boron compared to other Commonwealth M3B designs, the Guppy is never-the-less just as capable a strike-craft as any other, and any who would laugh at it soon find little to laugh at when their ships are crippled by resounding explosions.\n\nGenerally assigned to and deployed from carriers, the Guppy can fire deadly salvos of heavy missiles from long rangem though remains very vunerable in close quarters due to its light shielding.</t>
 <t id="80114">{17,16681}</t>
 <t id="80115">The recently comissioned M3B Acinonyx-Class Strike-Bomber enables the Split Military to bring even more firepower into the fray - often with explosive results. \n\nWhile esentially little more than cockpit mounted to a plasma-reaction engine and payload hardpoints, the Acinonyx still manages to capture many of the Split Dynasty's hallmarks in design engineering and methodology, with its sleek and angular lines capturing the hearts of many Split and Commonwealth pilots alike.\n\nHowever, this strike-bomber was never meant to look pretty - it was meant to kill, and it is a role that it performs well. \n\nIt should be noted that while it is indeed a fearsome bomber that that can strike fear into the hearts of the Boron as easily as it can strike missiles into the hearts of cruisers, it does tend to also feature the usual Split oversight of having more power than sense - and, conversely, fewer shields than sense, too. \n\nWhile the lack of adequate shielding is not usually a problem for Split fighters \(via their &quot;shoot them before they can shoot you&quot; mantra\), this is quite a problem when dealing with high-yield warheads which, when coupled with the Split tendency to get close and personal with their enemies, results in pilots of the Acinonyx often getting caught in the wake of their own destruction...\n\nIn terms of etymology, the name &quot;Acinonyx&quot; is derived from the latin genus of Earth's cheetah.</t>
 <t id="80116">{17,16631}</t>
 <t id="80117">In an effort to gain the upper-hand in the on-going spat with the Argon Federation, the Paranid Empire ushered the M3B Ariadne-Class Strike-Bomber into service. \n\nBased upon the M3+ Medusa, the Ariadne enables the Paranid Navy to conduct warfare from distance without endangering their pilots, and was developed to directly counter the Argon M3B Daedalus-Class Strike-Bomber.\n\nCompared to its Argon rival, however, the Ariadne is smaller, cheaper, and easier to produce \(and replace\) than the Daedalus. It is also faster than its main rival, thus suiting the general idea that the Ariadne was designed to hunt and kill the Daedalus and its mother-craft, if for no other reason than to rile the Argon Federation.\n\nHowever, the Daedalus boasts more shielding than the Ariadne, and is able to carry a higher payload than the Paranid offering, making both vessels well matched in many areas, and each slightly more niched to their respective roles.\n\nIn Terran Greek mythology, Ariadne was the immortal wife of the wine-god Dionysos, and assisted Theseus in his quest to slay the Minotaur.\n\n</t>
 <t id="80118">Hawk</t>
 <t id="80119">The M3B Hawk-Class Strike-Bomber is the Teladi Company's foray into the world of strike-craft, developed mostly to &quot;keep up&quot; with other Commonwealth races out of a desire to maintain appearences \(and equal footing\), rather than out of any actual need.\n\nEssentially a retrofitted Kea, the Hawk is relatively slow, but maintains very large cargo bays as a result from which it can launch a large number of heavy missiles. \n\nIt is also quite well shielded \(comparative to the Argon M3B Daedalus\) and heavily armored, demonstrating that while the Teladi Company may do things &quot;on the cheap&quot; sometimes, they do not necessarily have to sacrifice quality in the process.</t>
 <t id="80120">{17,3471}</t>
 <t id="80121">The M6 Ganymede-Class Corvette is a recent addition to the Paranid Imperial Navy, designed primarily in reaction to reports that the Yaki have been developing their own M6s based on Paranid technology (and stolen ships), and the subsequent increase in Yaki activity close to Paranid Prime as a result.\n\nDespite being rushed into service, the Ganymede is \(on paper\) an excellent craft, boasting optimised engine and weapon systems - although little thought has been given to the ship's shield systems, which suffer as a result.\n\nWhether this new innovation in corvette design will prove successful in combat remains to be seen.\n\nDocking Capacity: None</t>
 <t id="80122">{17,16491}</t>
 <t id="80123">The Boron M7 Sturgeon-Class Ion-Frigate \(nicknamed &quot;Axeface&quot; by Argon pilots\) is one of the newest designs out of the Boron shipyards, and represents a new way of thinking from the Boron Navy that seeks to exploit the full potential of their ion-based weaponry.\n\nThe Sturgeon is a vessel designed for one purpose: the annihilation of shielding on capital-class vessels, accomplishing this end with optimized ion-based weapon technology, targetting sub-systems, and shielding capabilities, at the overall cost of top-end speed.\n\nBoasting heavy shielding of its own, it is thought that the Sturgeon was born entirely out of a desire to counter Split aggression and exploit the main weakness of Spilt military vessels: the neglect of adequate shielding in favor of more speed and firepower.\n\nWith little shielding to begin with, it is the hope of the Boron Navy that removing the shielding of Split vessels entirely will curb their enthusiasm to wage war on Boron assets.\n\nDocking Capacity: None</t>
 <t id="80124">{17,12881}</t>
 <t id="80125">The M6 Tern-Class Heavy Assault Corvette is the Teladi Company's answer to increasing levels of pirate belligerence near Teladi-held border regions, and perhaps also an indication that Teladi-Pirate relations are starting to fray.\n\nBased on the Shrike design, it can mount capital class heavy weapons on its side turrets at the expense of overall speed.</t>
 <t id="80126">{17,16521}</t>
 <t id="80127">The M7C Coelacanth-Class Light Carrier is a new addition to the Boron Royal Navy, designed as a &quot;more traditional&quot; counterpart to the M7 Sturgeon-Class Ion-Frigate that can provide fighter-based operations and bomber-support to complement the Megalodon's base firepower.\n\nBased upon a modified M7M Kraken-Class Missile Frigate shell with an added internal docking bay for up to twenty-eight fighters, the Coelacanth is lightly armed, but features good speed and shielding, allowing it to excel at general sector-patrol and policing duties.\n\nDocking Capacity: 28 x Fighters.</t>
 <t id="80128">{17,10561} {17,10022}</t>
 <t id="80129">{17,10562}</t>
 <t id="80130">{17,80134} {17,80136}</t>
 <t id="80131">When it became clear that the Electro-Magnetic Plasma Cannon was too energy hungry for smaller Terran ships, USC commissioned the design of a new light weapon. The Electro-Magnetic Repeater is based on the technology of its larger sibling, but rather than fire concentrated bursts it fires its EM plasma at much lower energies. This gives it the advantage of being able to fire at a faster rate with a higher projectile speed, while only using a fraction of the ship's power.</t>
 <t id="80132">{17,80134} {17,80136} {17,80138}</t>
 <t id="80133">This forge produces the Electro-Magnetic Repeater.</t>
 <t id="80134">Electro-Magnetic</t>
 <t id="80136">Repeater</t>
 <t id="80138">Forge</t>
 <t id="80140">{17,10023} {17,80134} {17,80136}</t>
 <t id="80142"></t>
 <t id="80144">Terran Medium</t>
 <t id="80146">{17,10002}</t>
 <t id="80147">Information on this strange Kha'ak ship is extremely sketchy. It has only been spotted deep in Kha'ak territory by recon ships, but it is thought it will soon be deployed against the commonwealth. It appears to be a heavy bomber and can launch devastating barrages of deadly missiles.</t>
 <t id="80148">{1000,1043} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80149">This is the headquarters of the Paranid Trinity Corporation. They mainly deal in the mining and transportation of minerals.</t>
 <t id="80150">{1000,1040} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80151">This is the headquarters of the Paranid corporation Holy Dimensions. While maintaining a legitimate hi-tech goods supplier corporate image, it is rumoured that they also deal in illegal weapons and have connections to the Yaki Syndicate.</t>
 <t id="80152">{1000,1023} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80153">This is the headquarters of the Boron Waverider corporation. They specialise in the manufacturing of water reprocessing units for Boron starships.</t>
 <t id="80154">{1000,1051} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80155">This is the headquarters of the Teladi Creditania Group. This is a conglomerate of bankers and stock brokers, however it is aledged that they are a front for loan sharks, money laundering and racketeering.</t>
 <t id="80156">{1000,1033} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80157">This is the headquarters of Thuruk's Incorporated, a large Split owned corporation. This part-state owned corporation has a very wide range of activities from weapon and ship design to the manufacture and supply of low-tech goods.</t>
 <t id="80158">Equipment Dock</t>
 <t id="80160">Disruptor</t>
 <t id="80161">This is a new type of Kha'ak weapon. It is based on the Kha'ak scout design. Its true purpose and abilities have not yet been ascertained.</t>
 <t id="80162">{1000,1043} {17,80158}</t>
 <t id="80163">This is an equpiment dock belonging to the Paranid Trinity Corporation.</t>
 <t id="80164">{1000,1040} {17,80158}</t>
 <t id="80165">This equipment dock belongs to the large Paranid corporation Holy Dimensions.</t>
 <t id="80166">{1000,1023} {17,80158}</t>
 <t id="80167">This equipment dock is owned by the Boron Waverider corporation.</t>
 <t id="80168">{1000,1051} {17,80158}</t>
 <t id="80169">This equipment dock belongs to the Teladi Creditania Group.</t>
 <t id="80170">{1000,1033} {17,80158}</t>
 <t id="80171">This is an equipment dock belonging to the large Split corporation Thuruk's Incorporated.</t>
 <t id="80172">Corporation</t>
 <t id="80174">{17,80172} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80175">These part state owned shipyards are administered by private corporations. They serve as both research centres and ship manufacture facilities. They specialise in advanced hybrids of common commercial and military spacecraft.</t>
 <t id="80176">{17,4131} {17,10026}</t>
 <t id="80178">Orbital {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80180">{1000,101} {9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80181">PAR shipyards are a joint military and civilian venture aimed at providing independant organisations a quick and easy solution to the problem of buying and outfitting defence forces. Ships can be bought pre-outfitted and ready for deployment.</t>
 <t id="80182">{1000,102} {9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80183">PAR shipyards are a joint military and civilian venture aimed at providing independant organisations a quick and easy solution to the problem of buying and outfitting defence forces. Ships can be bought pre-outfitted and ready for deployment.</t>
 <t id="80184">{1000,103} {9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80185">PAR shipyards are a joint military and civilian venture aimed at providing independant organisations a quick and easy solution to the problem of buying and outfitting defence forces. Ships can be bought pre-outfitted and ready for deployment.</t>
 <t id="80186">{1000,104} {9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80187">PAR shipyards are a joint military and civilian venture aimed at providing independant organisations a quick and easy solution to the problem of buying and outfitting defence forces. Ships can be bought pre-outfitted and ready for deployment.</t>
 <t id="80188">{1000,105} {9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80189">PAR shipyards are a joint military and civilian venture aimed at providing independant organisations a quick and easy solution to the problem of buying and outfitting defence forces. Ships can be bought pre-outfitted and ready for deployment.</t>
 <t id="80190">{1000,121} {9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80191">PAR shipyards are a joint military and civilian venture aimed at providing independant organisations a quick and easy solution to the problem of buying and outfitting defence forces. Ships can be bought pre-outfitted and ready for deployment.</t>
 <t id="80192">{1000,1091} {1000,10021}</t>
 <t id="80193">Weapons Dealers are corporate owned docks selling military grade weapons. They stock large quantities of often hard to find weapons, including missiles. The larger stations specialise in capital ship weapons while the smaller M stations specialise in missiles.</t>
 <t id="80194">{1000,1024} {1000,10021}</t>
 <t id="80195">Weapons Dealers are corporate owned docks selling military grade weapons. They stock large quantities of often hard to find weapons, including missiles. The larger stations specialise in capital ship weapons while the smaller M stations specialise in missiles.</t>
 <t id="80196">{1000,1040} {1000,10021}</t>
 <t id="80197">Weapons Dealers are corporate owned docks selling military grade weapons. They stock large quantities of often hard to find weapons, including missiles. The larger stations specialise in capital ship weapons while the smaller M stations specialise in missiles.</t>
 <t id="80198">{1000,1098} {1000,10021}</t>
 <t id="80199">Weapons Dealers are corporate owned docks selling military grade weapons. They stock large quantities of often hard to find weapons, including missiles. The larger stations specialise in capital ship weapons while the smaller M stations specialise in missiles.</t>
 <t id="80200">{1000,1050} {1000,10021}</t>
 <t id="80201">Weapons Dealers are corporate owned docks selling military grade weapons. They stock large quantities of often hard to find weapons, including missiles. The larger stations specialise in capital ship weapons while the smaller M stations specialise in missiles.</t>
 <t id="80202">{1000,1096} {1000,10021}</t>
 <t id="80203">Weapons Dealers are corporate owned docks selling military grade weapons. They stock large quantities of often hard to find weapons, including missiles. The larger stations specialise in capital ship weapons while the smaller M stations specialise in missiles.</t>
 <t id="80204">{1000,150} {1000,10021}</t>
 <t id="80205">Weapons Dealers are corporate owned docks selling military grade weapons. They stock large quantities of often hard to find weapons, including missiles. The larger stations specialise in capital ship weapons while the smaller M stations specialise in missiles.</t>
 <t id="80206">{9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {13,1359} {13,1294}</t>
 <t id="80207">{9,515}{9,500}{9,517} {13,25}</t>
 <t id="80208">Fusion</t>
 <t id="80209">Pulse</t>
 <t id="80210">Disruptor</t>
 <t id="80212">{17,80208} {17,80209} {17,80210}</t>
 <t id="80213">The Fusion Pulse Disruptor is a new weapon developed by the USC. Designed specifically for use on corvettes and frigates, it packs a heavy punch as well as having the ability to disrupt ship systems.</t>
 <t id="80214">{17,80208} {17,80209} {17,80210} {17,80138}</t>
 <t id="80215">This factory produces the Fusion Pulse Disruptor.</t>
 <t id="80216">Maintenance</t>
 <t id="80217">Pod</t>
 <t id="80221">{17,80223} {17,80209} {17,6713}</t>
 <t id="80222">The Quantum Pulse Repair Laser is used by OTAS Maintenance Pods. Using Quantum Tubes, it generates a laser pulse. Suspended in this beam are tiny particles which seal any cracks or breaches in a ship's hull.</t>
 <t id="80223">Quantum</t>
 <t id="80224">{17,80216} {17,80217}</t>
 <t id="80225">Manufactured by OTAS, these pods assist with the regeneration of ships' hulls, using the Quantum Pulse Repair Laser to seal any cracks or breaches in the hull. \n\nIt mounts four of these repair lasers and their firing is synchronised to provide an almost constant beam. The pulse is generated using Quantum Tubes, which are rapidly depleted by the process. \n\nFor this reason, the pods have a large cargo bay for the storage of the tubes.</t>
 <t id="80226">Mobile</t>
 <t id="80227">Research Station</t>
 <t id="80228">{17,80226} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80229">A joint development between the Argon Federation, TerraCorp, and the Plutarch Mining Corporation, the TL+ Mobile Research Station is a distinctive vessel with an equally diacritic history.\n\nUnofficially dubbed the &quot;Horizon-class&quot;, the Mobile Research Station was designed with three main missions in mind: the exploration and cartography of uncharted systems; the creation and study of experimental compounds, elements, organic structures, or minerals; and the design and development of prototype weapons and systems deemed not safe enough to be tested in populated space.\n\nOn top of its broad range of scientific capabilities, the MRS is also quite a capable TL in its own right, and is more than equipped to act as a mobile base of operations - able to field fighters, resupply vessels, and keep a considerable amount of cargo locked away in its cavernous holds - just as well as any other large transport ship, regardless of the role it is assigned to.\n\nThe chosen motto of the Mobile Research Base is &quot;Cogito Ergo Sum&quot; - I Think, Therefore I Exist.\n\nDocking Capacity: 4 x TS/M6</t>
 <t id="80230">{17,16471}</t>
 <t id="80231">The M6 Nexus-Class Multi-Gun Corvette was developed with one primary assignment in mind: the hunting and killing of Kha'ak Clusters.\n\nThe Nexus was developed after the M6+ Heavy Centaur came into service, and was intended to be a vessel designed and equipped by the Argon Federation from top-to-bottom in an attempt to move away from dependency on OTAS-based solutions.\n\nTo this end, the Nexus incorporates a number of innovative systems that enable it to excel at its role of Kha'ak interdiction and elimination:\n\nAdvanced gyroscopic-stabilizers have been coupled with dedicated guidance systems to help the Nexus's overlapping turret-array handle a large number of contacts without being overwhelmed, while the turrets themselves are constructed on super-conductive polymers to prevent any potential issues with over-heating or tracking-errors from arising.\n\nCompared to the Centaur, the Nexus maintains a higher top-end speed, which permits it to catch up to its intended targets before they have a chance to leave the scene. \n\nHowever, this speed comes at the cost of less shielding, manoeuvrability, and smaller cargo holds, as much of the equipment that powers these systems in a Centaur has been removed so that the Nexus's advanced weapons-array and inter-linked systems can function at peak operating levels.\n\nDocking Capacity: None</t>
 <t id="80232">Showroom</t>
 <t id="80233">{13,9030} {17,80232}</t>
 <t id="80234">Corporate Showrooms are civilian run facilities, building and selling ships and factories. The Corporations were offered incentives by the military factions to take over production of civilian ships and factories as the military shipyards were becoming increasing stretched to keep up with the demand for military ships with the increased Xenon activity.</t>
 <t id="80235">{13,9073} {17,80232}</t>
 <t id="80236">Corporate Showrooms are civilian run facilities, building and selling ships and factories. The Corporations were offered incentives by the military factions to take over production of civilian ships and factories as the military shipyards were becoming increasing stretched to keep up with the demand for military ships with the increased Xenon activity.</t>
 <t id="80237">{1000,1033} {17,80232}</t>
 <t id="80238">Corporate Showrooms are civilian run facilities, building and selling ships and factories. The Corporations were offered incentives by the military factions to take over production of civilian ships and factories as the military shipyards were becoming increasing stretched to keep up with the demand for military ships with the increased Xenon activity.</t>
 <t id="80239">{1000,1043} {17,80232}</t>
 <t id="80240">Corporate Showrooms are civilian run facilities, building and selling ships and factories. The Corporations were offered incentives by the military factions to take over production of civilian ships and factories as the military shipyards were becoming increasing stretched to keep up with the demand for military ships with the increased Xenon activity.</t>
 <t id="80241">{1000,146} {17,80232}</t>
 <t id="80242">Corporate Showrooms are civilian run facilities, building and selling ships and factories. The Corporations were offered incentives by the military factions to take over production of civilian ships and factories as the military shipyards were becoming increasing stretched to keep up with the demand for military ships with the increased Xenon activity.</t>
 <t id="80243">{1000,150} {17,80232}</t>
 <t id="80244">Corporate Showrooms are civilian run facilities, building and selling ships and factories. The Corporations were offered incentives by the military factions to take over production of civilian ships and factories as the military shipyards were becoming increasing stretched to keep up with the demand for military ships with the increased Xenon activity.</t>
 <t id="80245">{13,9030} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80246">Research Stations are corporate facilities for advanced scientific research into a variety of fields. Due to the often questionable nature of the research they tend to be found in remote areas of border sectors and frequently alter their location. One of the major fields of research currently being undertaken by several corporations is the advancement of exsiting ship technology. You may often find these prototype ship designs for sale at the right price from blackmarket dealers living on the station. Due to the extra commerce these dealers bring, they tend to be overlooked by the corporation sponsoring the research.</t>
 <t id="80247">{1000,1023} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80248">Research Stations are corporate facilities for advanced scientific research into a variety of fields. Due to the often questionable nature of the research they tend to be found in remote areas of border sectors and frequently alter their location. One of the major fields of research currently being undertaken by several corporations is the advancement of exsiting ship technology. You may often find these prototype ship designs for sale at the right price from blackmarket dealers living on the station. Due to the extra commerce these dealers bring, they tend to be overlooked by the corporation sponsoring the research.</t>
 <t id="80249">{1000,1033} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80250">Research Stations are corporate facilities for advanced scientific research into a variety of fields. Due to the often questionable nature of the research they tend to be found in remote areas of border sectors and frequently alter their location. One of the major fields of research currently being undertaken by several corporations is the advancement of exsiting ship technology. You may often find these prototype ship designs for sale at the right price from blackmarket dealers living on the station. Due to the extra commerce these dealers bring, they tend to be overlooked by the corporation sponsoring the research.</t>
 <t id="80251">{1000,1040} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80252">Research Stations are corporate facilities for advanced scientific research into a variety of fields. Due to the often questionable nature of the research they tend to be found in remote areas of border sectors and frequently alter their location. One of the major fields of research currently being undertaken by several corporations is the advancement of exsiting ship technology. You may often find these prototype ship designs for sale at the right price from blackmarket dealers living on the station. Due to the extra commerce these dealers bring, they tend to be overlooked by the corporation sponsoring the research.</t>
 <t id="80253">{1000,1051} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80254">Research Stations are corporate facilities for advanced scientific research into a variety of fields. Due to the often questionable nature of the research they tend to be found in remote areas of border sectors and frequently alter their location. One of the major fields of research currently being undertaken by several corporations is the advancement of exsiting ship technology. You may often find these prototype ship designs for sale at the right price from blackmarket dealers living on the station. Due to the extra commerce these dealers bring, they tend to be overlooked by the corporation sponsoring the research.</t>
 <t id="80255">{1000,150} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80256">Research Stations are corporate facilities for advanced scientific research into a variety of fields. Due to the often questionable nature of the research they tend to be found in remote areas of border sectors and frequently alter their location. One of the major fields of research currently being undertaken by several corporations is the advancement of exsiting ship technology. You may often find these prototype ship designs for sale at the right price from blackmarket dealers living on the station. Due to the extra commerce these dealers bring, they tend to be overlooked by the corporation sponsoring the research.</t>
 <t id="80300">{17,12871}</t>
 <t id="80301">Originally designed as a &quot;Drone Carrier&quot;, the M7C Griffon-Class Light Carrier has been refitted to be able to support all fighter classes in its docking bays, allowing the Argon Federal Navy to project greater fighter-support when and where it is required without having to commit a Colossus to the operation.\n\nAlthough lightly armed and relatively slow, the Griffon has the unique ability to launch all 25 of its docked fighters simultaneously, enabling it to respond extremely quickly to any threat, to provide fighter-screen defense for crippled vessels as they retreat, and evacuation cover for stations, should they require the aid.\n\nDocking Capacity: 25 x Fighters.</t>
 <t id="80302">{17,12941}</t>
 <t id="80303">The Paranid M7 Agamemnon-Class Heavy Assault Frigate is one of the newer additions to the Paranid Imperial Navy that was initially dropped from mass-production due to its high construction costs. \n\nHowever, when the Argon Federal Navy began deploying the M7 Cyclops-Class Support-Frigate into active-service, the Pranid Empire suddenly found a new impetus to develop a vessel to directly rival it, and the Agamemnon was soon seeing service across all of Paranid space.\n\nCompared to the Cyclops, the Agamemnon is almost superior in every way: it boasts a higher top-end speed, 1 GJ of extra-shielding, and \(slightly\) more cargo space. \n\nHowever, the Cyclops features considerably thicker hull plating, meaning it can out-last the Agamemnon in a straight-up fight - a fact that is something of a sore topic among captains of this vessel.\n\nBe that as it may, the Agamemnon is capable of mounting anti-capital grade weapons upon its front turrets, and its shielding is still considered to be class-leading among the Commonwealth races, making it one of the most fearsome frigates to be in active service right now.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80304">{17,13141}</t>
 <t id="80305">Excelling in perimeter-defence and task-group escort duties, the M7 Astraeus-Class Multi-Gun Frigate is an essential part of the OTAS fleet.\n\nNamed for the Greek Titan-god of the dusk, Astraeus translates as &quot;dawn of the stars&quot;, and is a fitting agnomen in many aspects: the Astraeus was the first OTAS vessel to see service in the Argon Navy as a vessel purchased - rather than contracted - by the Argon Federation, and is often said to be the vessel that allowed OTAS to rise above its peers.\n\nAs the Astraeus also borrows and improves upon many of the systems from the M2 Titan-Destroyer, it could also be considered to be a more compact &quot;second-generation Titan&quot; - much like the mythical deity it is named for.\n\nDesigned to be the counterpart to the Argon Federation's M7 Cerberus-Class Frigate, the Astraeus boasts improved shielding, thicker hull plating, a higher rate of acceleration, an expanded cargo hold, and greater turret coverage than its Argon equivalent - albeit at the cost of a slower maximum speed and a slightly smaller hangar capacity.\n\nThe Astraeus remains the standard by which all OTAS vessels are designed: namely, if the Argon Navy can do it, the Optimised Technology, Armaments, and Shielding Corporation can do it better.\n\nDocking Capacity: 5 x Fighter Class; 1 x Corvette Class.</t>
 <t id="80306">{17,11101}</t>
 <t id="80307">With some sacrifices of shielding and armament for speed, the OTAS-developed M2 Boreas-class light destroyer has been designed to react quickly to developing situations within OTAS space and beyond.\n\nNamed for the greek god of the winter, the name &quot;Boreas&quot; meant &quot;North Wind&quot; or &quot;Devouring One&quot;, with Boreas himself often depicted as being very strong, with a violent temper to match - attributes that OTAS attempted to capture within their light destroyed.\n\nFamed for being the swiftest M2 in Commonwealth space, the Boreas sports a revolutionary &quot;Revelation-Class Engine Array&quot; that enables it to travel at Frigate-level speeds - a first for any Destroyer-class ship.\n\nWhen paired with a Carrier or another Destroyer, the M2 Boreas-Class Light Destroyer excels at anti-capital strike and interception roles, and doubles as a formidable blockade runner in it's own right - an essential element for navigating the &quot;Pirate Highway&quot; between Aladna Hill and Elena's Chance.\n\nHowever, the Boreas's swift manoeuvrability come at the price of a weaker shield array when compared to other ships of this class, making it less suited to prolonged stand-offs with larger M2s, and more at risk from M8 Bombers.\n\nEven so, there are many examples of experienced captains using the speed of the Boreas to run rings around slower ships, and those well versed in &quot;hit and fade&quot; operations are more than capable of using the apparent weaknesses of this ship to lure their enemy into a false sense of security.\n\nDocking Capacity: 3 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80308">{17,11121}</t>
 <t id="80309">The M3 Venti-Class Heavy Fighter is the OTAS equivalent of the Argon Federation's Nova-Class fighter, and can predominantly be found in the Light of Heart system, protecting OTAS assets from any potential invaders or smugglers - its powerful armaments making it more than suitable for this task.\n\nBrought into existence almost by accident, the original Venti prototype was designed to mostly prove a point: the Nova took two years of research and development to bring into service, and is considered to be the epitome of what the shipwrights in Omicron Lyrae could accomplish. In light of the Nova project, OTAS set out to demonstrate that they could do the same thing in far less time, and the Venti was born six-months later.\n\nOriginally designed to highlight OTAS's technological prowess, officials within both the Argon Federation and OTAS itself were so impressed with the result that they requested the fighter be mass-produced, and the Venti was brought into service as a premier fighter soon after.\n\nNamed for the Roman deities of the wind, the Venti is fast, powerful, and deadly. On a relative scale, the Venti can be compared to the Nova Raider in almost every aspect, albeit it with double the shielding at the cost of a slightly weaker hull.\n\nRanking somewhere between the Nova and the Nova Raider, the Venti continues to demonstrate OTAS's independence from the Argon Navy and lack of need for protection in their home sectors, while equally extending their willingness to remain the Argon Federation's primary military contractor.</t>
 <t id="80310">{17,11131}</t>
 <t id="80311">The M3+ Notus-Class Heavy Fighter has been developed to provide OTAS with a long-range escort and strike-support capabilities, primarily designed as an escort vessel for the M2 Boreas-Class Light Destroyer during assignments through the &quot;Pirate Highway&quot;.\n\nThe name &quot;Notus&quot; derives from the Greek god of the south wind who was thought to bring the storms of late summer and autumn, and was feared as a destroyer of crops, and the fact that the Notus has a reputation as a hunter-killer of enemy cargo haulers and supply ships has not been lost on those who are familiar with Terran mythology.\n\nIn terms of specifications, the Notus is slower than its older brother, but boasts a heavier shielding array, substantially thicker hull-plating, a more powerful weapons-energy generator, and an additional front-turret. \n\nIn short, the Notus means business, and is the bane of many an unsuspecting pirate corvette.</t>
 <t id="80312">{17,11111}</t>
 <t id="80313">The M4 Eurus-Class Medium Fighter is designed to complement heavy fighters in the protection of OTAS facilities and transport ships, providing directed rapid-reaction intercept capabilities and fast-patrol operations across the expanse of Akeela's Beacon.\n\nNamed for the Greek deity who represented the unlucky east wind, the Eurus is faster than both the Argon Navy's M4 Buster and M4 Elite, though while it has better shielding than the Buster, it is substantially less well shielded than the Elite, and has a weaker hull than both of its Argon counterparts.\n\nHowever, the Eurus was designed for speed and not power, and is primarily intended to head off an incursion and tie up any enemies until larger ships - such as the M2 Boreas - can arrive on scene to mop up whatever is left.</t>
 <t id="80314">{17,11141}</t>
 <t id="80315">The M4+ Solano-Class Advanced Interceptor is a second-generation redesign of the M4 Eurus, and has been optimised for rapid closure on hostile intruders. \n\nIt has the ability to destroy similar-sized ships or hold larger ones until reinforcements arrive, and was intended to improve upon many of the apparent weaknesses that the Eurus had in similar engagements.\n\nDeviating from standard naming practices a little, the Solano is named for the south to south-easterly wind in the southern sector of the country of Spain on Earth, which is said to carry unbearably hot, dry, suffocating weather and cause exhaustion and dizziness to anyone unfortunate enough to be caught in it. \n\nThough slightly slower than its first-generation counterpart, the Solano houses a substantially more powerful shield array system, a weapons-energy generator that produces an output that is double that of the Eurus, and notably thicker hull-plating.\n\nImproving upon the Eurus's design flaws in every possible way, it is easy to see why the Solano was named as such.</t>
 <t id="80316">{17,11151}</t>
 <t id="80317">The offspring of the Argon Federation's TM Magnetar and OTAS's own Mistral Freighter, the TM Zephyrus-Class Military Transport provides important tactical flexibility to the OTAS fleet with its ability to carry, deploy, and retrieve a limited number of fighter craft into and out of any situation.\n\nNamed for the Greek god of the west wind, Zephyrus was known as the as the gentlest of the winds - a sentiment that any stranded pilot can relate to when one of these ships appears on their gravidar to rescue them.\n\nAlthough essentially developed from a retrofitted Mistral hull, in true OTAS fashion the Zephyrus has managed to become class-leading within Commonwealth space, and boasts higher speeds, greater shielding, and a higher weapons-energy output than its cousin, the Magnetar, though has a slightly weaker hull as a result.\n\nDocking Capacity: 4 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80318">{17,11161}</t>
 <t id="80319">The M6M Skiron-Class Assault Corvette represents a significant step forward in OTAS corvette design, with most areas of its capabilities having been enhanced compared to previous generations of M6, resulting in a well-rounded vessel capable of carrying out a number of different roles and assignments.\n\nIn Greek mythology, &quot;Skiron&quot; was the Greek god of the northwest wind, and represented the onset of winter; the Skiron's ability to launch a large array of missile types and mount boarding operations against other vessels may result in enemy pilots feeling that winter is creeping up on them as well.\n\nCompared to its cousin, the M6M Heavy Centaur-Class Corvette, the Skiron has a higher top-end speed and a more powerful shield array, although also has less hull-plating and a slightly weaker weapons-energy generator.\n\nUnlike the Heavy Centaur, however, the Skiron does afford its crew a few frills here and there, and those who have served aboard the Skiron as part of Argon Navy/OTAS crew-exchanges do not often want to return to life aboard the cold military hardness of the Heavy Centaur.\n\nAlthough it is not common knowledge, the improvements that the Heavy Centaur features when compared to the standard Centaur were also derived from the Skiron - at least in terms of system design, if not superstructure. \n\nThere is more than a little of the Skiron's soul in the Heavy Centaur, and when Argon naval draughtsmen spent months asking themselves how to improve the Centaur, the answer was to simply ask OTAS for help.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80320">{17,11171}</t>
 <t id="80321">The M7M Aquilo-Class Missile Frigate was the inspiration for other forays into the heavy-strike arena by the other races of the Commonwealth - not just the Argon Federation - and is considered to be a pioneering accomplishment and further proof that OTAS's revolutionary vision rivals that of even BalaGi Research.\n\nThe first ship of its kind to see service, the name &quot;Aquilo&quot; derives from Roman mythology, and was another name for the Greek god &quot;Boreas&quot; - the diety of the northern wind. That OTAS gave one of their vessels the same name as their light-destroyer should not be ignored, for the name carries the same kind of implications, albeit in a different context.\n\nWhile the M2 Boreas-class light destroyer was named as such due to its speed, the Aquilo is named due its launch/strike capabilities. It was the first to deploy the Flail Barrage Missile in combat, quickly causing other races to sit up and take note after one particularly over-confident Paranid M1 carrier captain lost most of his fighter support and escorts during a one-on-one engagement during a chance confrontation in an Unknown Sector.\n\nCompared to the Argon Federation's own M7M, the Minotaur, the Aquilo is slightly quicker and boasts a shield array that is twice as powerful as what the Minotaur is able to carry, though has roughly a third-less hull strength and overall power.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80322">{17,11181}</t>
 <t id="80323">The M8 Auster-Class Heavy Bomber provides OTAS with pin-point strike capabilities against both capital ships and installations, and excels at hit-and-fade operations behind enemy lines, and asset-denial assignments on trade lanes, in equal measure.\n\nThe Auster was developed alongside the M7M Aquilo-Class Frigate almost by accident while OTAS research and design were working on the various new systems that would be integrated into their pioneering missile platform. \n\nWhen some the advances and ideas failed to work on a frigate-size scale, OTAS engineers instead turned their attention to how those same systems might instead work on a smaller scale, the Auster was born soon after.\n\nThe name &quot;Auster&quot; is taken from Roman mythology: Auster was the embodiment of the sirocco wind who brought heavy cloud cover and fog or humidity, and was considered to be the Roman equivalent to Notus, the Greek god of the south wind. \n\nIt should be noted that the Argon Federation's M8 Gladiator-class bomber is the same ship as the Auster, and is one of the few examples of the Argon Navy buying an OTAS design directly and manufacturing it themselves instead of contracting them to be built on their behalf.\n\nHowever, compared to the Gladiator, the Auster is superior in many ways, featuring a substantially greater shield array, and boasting hull-plating that is twice as heavy as what the Gladiator sports, but at a relatively similar weight, thanks to integrated cooling systems and heat-dissipation sinks that offset some of the damage of energy-based weapons.\n\nConversely, the Auster is slightly slower than the Gladiator due to the drain from the shield array, but fields greater overall power thanks to the interlinks designed to deal with the strain the shields place on the energy core.</t>
 <t id="80324">{17,11191}</t>
 <t id="80325">The newly developed M6 Sirokos-Class Light Multi-Mission Corvette is a semi-experimental vessel with a distinctive hull design that has recently entered service as a more flexible and dynamic counterpart to the M6M Skiron.\n\nThough officially intended to be used in low-intensity missions or for humanitarian relief operations, the Sirokos was built according to both civilian and military standards to accommodate officers and dignitaries in equal measure, while also providing hospitable conditions for temporary passengers such as refugees and evacuees.\n\nWhere the Sirokos differs from conventional transport vessels, however, is that it manages to fill a niche in being able to operate in more hostile environments and complex zones than most civilian vessels would dare to tread, being able to swiftly navigate through flashpoint regions and promptly secure important extraction points before larger relief vessels can take control of the situation.\n\nOff-the-record, however, the Sirokos is considered to be an &quot;Experimental Light Stealth Corvette&quot; - the shape of the hull is devised for the optimal reduction of the ship's LIDAR signature; the vessel's superstructures are constructed from LIDAR-absorbent synthetic materials; and the ship's engines adopt a special heat dissipation system, granting the Sirokos a lower thermal signature than most other corvettes in Commonwealth space. \n\nThe name &quot;Sirokos&quot; itself derives from the Greek word for Earth's Mediterranean wind that comes from the Sahara and reaches hurricane speeds in North Africa and Southern Europe - the symbolism of which has not been lost on this swift and striking vessel.</t>
 <t id="80326">Military Transport</t>
 <t id="80328">zzPLACEHOLDER</t>
 <t id="80332">{1000,119} {17,80158}</t>
 <t id="80334">{17,6331}</t>
 <t id="80335">The M6+ Appallox-Class Heavy Corvette is a modified version of the Paranid M6+ Hyperion-Class Corvette, reverse-engineered and modified to suit the needs of the Yaki Syndicate.\n\nWhile its exact technical capabilities are not widely known, it is believe that the Appallox is just as capable of holding its own than the original Paranid version, with the added ability to mount weapons that are not specifically created for Paranid-designed vessels.\n\nAlthough only seen in limited numbers, rumors suggest that the Yaki Syndicate have begun producing vessels of this kind within deep-space shipyards in small quantities, indicating that they are not entirely reliant on capturing Hyperion-Class Corvettes to replace lost vessels within their fleets.\n\nHowever, the Paranid Empire flatly refuses to even acknowledge that such Yaki vessels exist, labelling any who would say otherwise as slanderous enemies of the Pontifex Maximus Paranidia. \n\nSuch denials are proving problematic, as failing to address that a problem exists is permitting the Yaki even great operational freedom... but towards what end?\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80336">{17,7041}</t>
 <t id="80337">The M6+ Hyperion-Class Heavy Corvette is an evolution of the prototype M7 Trinity-Class Yacht that originally bore the same name and was notably owned by the Pontifex Maximus Paranidia.\n\nAlthough its classification has changed over time to become a cheaper and more compact M6 to enable the Paranid Imperial Navy to manufacture it in larger numbers, the Hyperion still retains many of the features that made the original prototype so distinctive, and thus remains equally unique among its peers in terms of sheer prowess and innovation.\n\nWidely regarded as one of the finest ships in her class, the Hyperion is as deadly as it is sleek, and more than capable of taking the fight to just about any enemy - big or small. There are more than a few stories among Commonwealth pilots of these ships taking on M1- and M2-sized vessels without escort, and often coming out on top.\n\nWith a versatility that is virtually unmatched and the ability to run rings around ships far larger than itself in the hands of skilled pilots, the Hyperion is proving to be just as popular now that it is in mass production as it was when only a handful were being developed by Paranid Defence Directorate, and has provided the Paranid Empire with a tool of expansion that far surpasses any potential benefit that the once-secret jumpgate project may have held.\n\nIn Terran mythology, Hyperion was one of the twelve Titan gods of Ancient Greece, named as &quot;The Titan of the East&quot;. It is said that Hyperion was the first to understand &quot;the movement of both the sun and the moon and the other stars, and the seasons as well&quot;.\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80338">{1000,121} {17,13131}</t>
 <t id="80339">{17,13132}</t>
 <t id="80340">{17,3861} {17,80362}</t>
 <t id="80341">This weapon is designed specifically for use in laser towers. It delivers a powerful beam of plasma at a target and has the ability to refire much more rapidly than standard beam weapons of this size.</t>
 <t id="80342">{17,80360} {17,80361} {17,80362}</t>
 <t id="80343">This is a recently discovered Xenon beam weapon. Its origins and technology are currently under research by Argon military scientists. It delivers a powerful beam which can instantly vapourise smaller ships and render considerable damage to capital class ships.</t>
 <t id="80344">{17,80223} {17,80363}</t>
 <t id="80345">This mysterious weapon has been recently spotted on Xenon capital ships. Its technology is unknown, but it is believed to deliver a powerful shockwave of particles obliterating anything in its path.</t>
 <t id="80346">{17,80358} {17,80209} {17,80359}</t>
 <t id="80347">Xenon fighters have recently begun using a new class of weapon. It appears to fire bursts of Gamma radiation at high velocity. Its high speed makes it not only deadly, but also extremely accurate.</t>
 <t id="80348">{17,80208} {17,80364}</t>
 <t id="80349">The Fusion Bomb Launcher is a Teladi designed frigate-class weapon. When the Split military began to restrict other race usage of its Ion Shard Railgun, the Teladi were forced to rush through production of this new weapon. It launches several fusion bombs which detonate on impact with the target delivering a powerful blast.</t>
 <t id="80350">{17,80365} {17,80366} {17,80367}</t>
 <t id="80351">Using technology based on the Paranid HEPT and Split ISR, the High Energy Particle Railgun is a new Xenon development which makes their corvette class ships even more deadly.</t>
 <t id="80352">{17,80134} {17,80210} {17,80368}</t>
 <t id="80353">Based on technology stolen from Terran weapon designs, this new Paranid anti-fighter capital-class weapon has seen a rapid roll out to the fleet. Its high damage and extremely fast projectiles are unavoidable in a fighter and can rip through a wing of ships in minutes.</t>
 <t id="80354">{17,80369} {17,80370}</t>
 <t id="80355">After Argon and Teladi military started restricitng use of their capital-class weapons, the Split had no choice but to roll out a prototype weapon that was still in the design stages. Based on technology from pirate weapons, it hurls a ball of firey plasma at a target causing huge damage. Although the Split authorities insist the weapon is safe to use, there have been unconfirmed reports of several incidents where the firing of the weapon has resulted in radiation poisoning of the crew.</t>
 <t id="80356">{17,80371} {17,80372} {17,80373}</t>
 <t id="80357">The Phased Plasma Generator is a new Paranid development allegedly based on the CIG design. It delivers medium amounts of damage with relatively low energy usage and has rapidly become a favourite among Paranid Corvette pilots.</t>
 <t id="80358">Gamma</t>
 <t id="80359">Emitter</t>
 <t id="80360">Dark</t>
 <t id="80361">Matter</t>
 <t id="80362">Beam Cannon</t>
 <t id="80363">Shockwave Cannon</t>
 <t id="80364">Bomb Launcher</t>
 <t id="80365">High Energy</t>
 <t id="80366">Particle</t>
 <t id="80367">Railgun</t>
 <t id="80368">Array</t>
 <t id="80369">Plasma Burst</t>
 <t id="80370">Projector</t>
 <t id="80371">Phased</t>
 <t id="80372">Plasma</t>
 <t id="80373">Generator</t>
 <t id="80374">{17,80208} {17,80364} {17,80138}</t>
 <t id="80375">This factory produces the Fusion Bomb Launcher.</t>
 <t id="80376">{17,80134} {17,80210} {17,80368} {17,80138}</t>
 <t id="80377">This factory produces the Electro-Magnetic Disruptor Array.</t>
 <t id="80378">{17,80369} {17,80370} {17,80138}</t>
 <t id="80379">This factory produces the Plasma Burst Projector</t>
 <t id="80380">{17,80371} {17,80372} {17,80373} {17,80138}</t>
 <t id="80381">This factory produces the Phased Plasma Generator.</t>
 <t id="80382">{1000,150} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="80383">This is the headquarters of the Terran Dark Space Corporation. It primarily deals with hi-tech manufacturing and logistics, but has unconfirmed links with the Terran black market and several pirate organisations.</t>
 <t id="80384">{1000,133} {17,80227}</t>
 <t id="80385">Research Stations are corporate facilities for advanced scientific research into a variety of fields. Due to the often questionable nature of the research they tend to be found in remote areas of border sectors and frequently alter their location. One of the major fields of research currently being undertaken by several corporations is the advancement of exsiting ship technology. You may often find these prototype ship designs for sale at the right price from blackmarket dealers living on the station. Due to the extra commerce these dealers bring, they tend to be overlooked by the corporation sponsoring the research.</t>
 <t id="80386">{1000,108} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="80387">Pirate shipyards are facilities where stolen or salvaged ships are customised to better suit pirate activities. They tend to employ illegal technology to improve performance, often at the expense of safety.</t>
 <t id="80388">{17,16751}</t>
 <t id="80389">Although it is considered to be an older class of ship by most standards, the TL Polacca-Class Heavy Transport continues to see service in Terran space and remains a key cornerstone of the economical powerhouse of the Sol System to this day - albeit usually in the hands of capable civilian and military contractors, rather under the direct control of the United Space Command.\n\nThough it may not have the cavernous holds of its younger modern sibling, the Terran Mobile Mining Base Ship, the Polacca still boasts an impressive cargo capacity that remains on-par with many similar Commonwealth TL-grade vessels, and still manages to be able house and support more fighters and small transports than the MMBS.\n\nWhile it sports slightly weaker shields- and weapons-energy generators compared to the MMBS due to their relative ages, the Polacca does still retain one advantage: the price. The Polacca may not be able to hold its own as well as the MMBS when under attack, but it is cheaper, and it is somewhat swifter; and to a captain with commercial and economic interests at heart, those two factors can make all the difference.\n\nNamed for a type of seventeenth-century sailing vessel that cut across the waves in Earth's ancient past, the Polacca retains both a proud service history and a fond spot in the hearts of many a Terran economist, and that is something that neither age nor advancement will easily remove.\n\nDocking Capacity: 9 x Fighter Craft.</t>
 <t id="80390">{1000,60008} {17,80517}</t>
 <t id="80391">These independant docks buy and sell a varienty of goods. They have a reputation for not being too worried about the legality of the goods bought and sold and are a common hang out for rogues and pirates.</t>
 <t id="80400">{17,6733}</t>
 <t id="80401">With the increasing speed and manouverability of current fighters, Argon Military specialists decided to abandon dumbfire missiles. Rather than waste existing production lines, the Firefly has been redesigned with a basic guidance system and a proximity fuse. Although it cannot turn quickly, its high speed enables it to close within detonation range easily. It has a large blast radius for a missile of this size.</t>
 <t id="80402">{17,6513}</t>
 <t id="80403">The Rapier missile is primarily used to hit long range targets quickly and with pin point accuracy. Although it does little damage it has one of the largest ranges of any missile and can cross a sector in Sezuras.</t>
 <t id="80404">{17,6543}</t>
 <t id="80405">When a target absolutely must be killed, the Windstalker is the missile to do the job. A favourite of bounty hunters across the known universe, it is fast enough to catch all but the fastest fighter and carries a warhead powerful enough to destroy all but the most heavily armed corvette. Although its guidance systems are fairly basic, its proximity fuse means even a close call will result in the destruction of its target. It has a onboard target analysis system so will find a new target if the one it is tracking gets destroyed. </t>
 <t id="80406">{17,6011}</t>
 <t id="80407">Designed by the pirate faction The Yaki, the Disruptor missile is becoming increasingly popular in military circles. Its extremely high speed, excellent tracking systems and large payload makes it an ideal all-round missile. Its sophisticated guidance systems will automatically select a new target if its current target is eliminated.</t>
 <t id="80408">{17,6763}</t>
 <t id="80409">After some concern that this armament would be nothing more than a continuation of the SQUASH Mine's unethical usage, the Hurricane Missile firmly rooted itself in military circles as being the weapon-of-choice when dealing with large numbers of small targets. Although it has a relatively small payload, its large area of effect makes it perfect for both Kha'ak cluster engagements as well as Pirate raid units.</t>
 <t id="80410">{17,6823}</t>
 <t id="80411">The Aurora is a prototype, designed by the Paranid to counter advanced missile defence systems such as the Motion Analysis Relay System (MARS) by sheer speed. Though blindingly fast, its acceleration is mediocre and its guidance systems minimal. Its proximity fuse, good payload, fast refire speed and large blast radius makes it idealy suited to overwhelm heavily defended ships.</t>
 <t id="80412">{17,6523}</t>
 <t id="80413">The Firelance Missile was developed by the Paranid Military as an equaliser for M3 fighters against much larger ships. Its swarm capabilities means it can easily overwhelm a targets defences and its proximity fuse and good blast radius ensures damage to its target.</t>
 <t id="80414">{17,6533}</t>
 <t id="80415">The Wildfire missile is a prototype missile developed by the Industritech Corporation. Its heat-seeking guidance system and retargetting ability means it can literally be fired and forgot. Due to its huge range, it is common to see roaming Wildfire missiles which have run out of targets at the edge of sectors.</t>
 <t id="80416">{17,6783}</t>
 <t id="80417">The Cyclone Missile offers the ability to deal with multiple targets with one armament. The missile will split into several smaller units that will engage image recognition tracking to lock down confirmed enemies in the field of engagement. Once one target is eliminated, remaining warheads will lock onto a new target.</t>
 <t id="80418">{17,6793}</t>
 <t id="80419">The Tornado missile is an extension of the Aurora design. Although slightly slower it has a very large payload and a massive blast radius. Its proximity fuse makes it perfect for taking out fighters that are flying in close formation.</t>
 <t id="80420">{17,6553}</t>
 <t id="80421">A powerful military-grade medium range missile, the Banshee offers pilots the chance to show their enemies the true meaning of fear. Its yield, good speed and strong acquisition ability allow it to be used in a wide range of combat scenarios against heavy fighters, corvettes and even frigates.</t>
 <t id="80422">{17,6773}</t> 
 <t id="80423">The Blizzard Missile, with its distictive white tail, is primarily an anti-corvette/frigate missile. Its very slow turn rate means it is largly ineffectual against fighters, but it packs a very large punch in eight separte swarm warheads which can effectively get through a frigate's missile defence. Against Corvettes, the slow turning nature of the warheads cause them to form a white "blizzard" swarming around the target, keeping the enemy's defensive turrets distracted, enabling fighters to close in for the kill.</t>
 <t id="80424">{17,10021} {17,81112}</t> 
 <t id="80425">The Advanced Scanner increases the range of a ships scanner</t> 
 <t id="80426">{1000,30000} {17,81112}</t> 
 <t id="80427">The Military Scanner increases the range of a ships scanner</t> 
 <t id="80428">Missile</t>
 <t id="80429">{12,103} {17,80428}</t>
 <t id="80430">With the production costs of the Poltergeist Missile putting it beyond the reach of many Rapier pilots, the USC have comissioned a new, low-cost light missile. The new Delta Missile is a very fast and manoeuvrable low-yield missile which is cheap and easy to produce. It is extremely versatile and can be used to shoot down incoming heavier missiles. Its small cargo volume means that even scout ships can carry large numbers.</t>
 <t id="80431">{12,117} {17,80428}</t>
 <t id="80432">With an increase in AGI and pirate activity, and new threats from the Kha'ak making Terran space more and more dangerous, the two Terran military arms, historically fiercely opposed to working together, have been forced to pool resources. The Sigma Missile is a new ATF/USC joint design to give Terran fighter pilots an additional option to the traditional Spectre missile. It is much faster than the Spectre and can give even the most experienced pirate pilot a challenge. Best used in multiple salvos they can rapidly bring down a target's shields and are fast enough to catch most M5 ships.</t>
 <t id="80433">{12,105} {17,80428}</t>
 <t id="80434">The Zeta Missile is a development of the Poltegeist missile. Using the same swarm warhead, albeit with a larger yield, it has been fitted with a sophisticated target tracking system, enalbing a lone fighter to engage multiple enemies.</t>
 <t id="80435">{12,123} {17,80437}</t>
 <t id="80436">After seeing the Commonwealth Firestorm Torpedo in action, and much clamouring from their destroyer captains, the recently launched USC and ATF joint weapons design commission drew up plans for their own heavy torpedo. The result, the Omega Torpedo, is currently the most powerful warhead in production in the galaxy. Its massive yield can wipe out the shields of a capital ship or station in just a few salvos, although its slow speed makes it particularly vunerable to turret defence systems.</t>
 <t id="80437">Torpedo</t>
 <t id="80438">{12,118} {17,80428}</t>
 <t id="80439">The Tau Missile is a unique missile which forgoes any high manoeuvrability in favour of speed and destructive power. It is a modified Sigma Missile, which has had most of its target tracking circuits removed in order to fit in a larger warhead and propulsion system. It is of great use against slow moving, larger targets where turning ability is not so important. </t>
 <t id="80440">Fabrication Facility</t>
 <t id="80441">{17,80429} {17,80440}</t>
 <t id="80442">This facility manufactures the Delta Missile.</t>
 <t id="80443">{17,80431} {17,80440}</t>
 <t id="80444">This facility manufactures the Sigma Missile.</t>
 <t id="80445">{17,80433} {17,80440}</t>
 <t id="80446">This facility manufactures the Zeta Missile.</t>
 <t id="80447">{17,80435} {17,80440}</t>
 <t id="80448">This facility manufactures the Omega Torpedo.</t>
 <t id="80449">{17,80438} {17,80440}</t>
 <t id="80450">This facility manufactures the Tau Missile.</t>
 <t id="80451">{17,6251}</t>
 <t id="80452">The Daedalus-class Heavy Carrier is the new flagship of the Federal Argon Military. It improves on the old Colosus design, adding a formidable frontal turret array and better shielding. It also has an extended hanger with space for two more fighter wings than the Colosus.\n\nIn Terran Greek mythology, Daedalus was a skilful craftsman and artisan, perhaps best known for creating the Labyrinth on Crete, in which the Minotaur was kept - a labyrinth so cunning that even Daedalus himself could barely escape it after he built it. \n\nFor those on the receiving end of the Daedalus's fighter compliment, the streaking trails of their multiple engines make for a fitting labyrinth that few ships are able to escape from before the Daedalus brings its heavy weaponry to bear...\n\nThere is currently only one Daedalus in active service. It is stationed in Argon Prime and has been christened "Argon-One" in homage to the Argon Fleet's old flagship.\n\nDocking Capacity: 52 x Fighter Class; 3 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="80453">Oedipus</t>
 <t id="80454">The Oedipus-Class Heavy Carrier is the Paranid Military's answer to the increase in Kha'ak Carrier ship attacks in recent Jazuras. Built upon a Zeus frame, it has a much heavier shieling, armour and weapon capability. Although significantly slower than the Zeus, it has a much larger fighter capacity meaning the Oedipus is rarely required to enter battle itself and can easily fend off several waves of attacking fighters.\n\nNamed after the mythical Greek king of Thebes, death and destruction usually surround the Oedipus. To this end it is a fitting ship to defend the Paranid homeworld.\n\nDocking Capacity: 55 x Fighter Class; 3 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="80455">{17,4701}</t>
 <t id="80456">The Atlas-class Heavy Destroyer is the most recent ship to come off the Omicron Lyrae Shipwrights' drawing board. Its has a formidable array of offensive weaponry, easily the match for any other ship in its class. It was rushed into service to hold the line at Black Hole Sun after a new Xenon capital ship, codenamed "Z" by Argon Intelligence, was spotted just past the BHS north gate.\n\nNamed after the Greek Titan who supported the heavens, it is hoped that the Atlas will be able to hold its own against any sustained Xenon attack, no matter its strength.\n\nDocking Capacity: 4 x Fighter Class; 3 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="80457">{17,16891}</t>
 <t id="80458">Until recently ATF commanders were relatively complacent in the knowledge that nothing could out-gun the Tyr, despite warnings from their couterparts in the Argon military that a new class of AGI warship, which they were calling the "Z" had been spotted with more guns than even the Tyr.\n\nHowever, when an ATF Rearguard fleet in the sectors to the east of the lost colonies was almost completely wiped out by an AGI battle group led by this new "Z", ATF commanders finally realised almost too late that the Tyr had finally met its match. With the Valhalla being far too costly to produce in large numbers, it was decided a new battle ship was needed. The new ATF Bragi-Class Heavy Destroyer is the most advanced ship yet to roll off the production lines in ATF Forceti. Its weapon systems are a match even for the Valhalla, but with greater speed and manouevrability.\n\nNamed after the Norse God of poetry, watching a Bragi in battle and the ease at which is takes apart its opponents is indeed, like poetry in motion.\n\nDocking Capacity: 7 x Fighter Class; 3 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="80459">{17,16921}</t>
 <t id="80460">The first ship to come off the production lines in the ATF's new facility in ATF Forseti, it was decided to christen this Light Carrier after the sector of its birth.\n\nThe Forseti-Class is a new direction for ATF fleet design. Rather than relying on the firepower of the mothership, the Forseti forgoes some weaponry and armour in favour of a larger hanger deck. Able to hold a full five wings of fighters, the Forseti rivals the Woden in flexibility and has already been involved in several engagements with the AGI threat.\n\nNamed after the Norse god of justice, the Forseti has rapidly gained a reputation at being able to deal out its own justice in true ATF style against the AGI agressors. Its fighter pilots are renowned for their "no mercy" attitude towards hunting down enemy patrols.\n\nDocking Capacity: 25 x Fighter Class; 2 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="80461">{17,16861}</t>
 <t id="80462">After a recent AGI engagement, in which an Argon fleet was in desperate need of ATF assistance, ATF captains marvelled at the Argon Quaser M3 Bombers launching from the under-attack Collosus and nearly taking out one of the attacking AGI destroyers on their own. After debreifing the captains involved, ATF command decided that they too should develop some kind of carrier-bound bomber capability.\n\nThe Norns M3 Bomber has now become standard deployment for all carriers and most will have at least one bomber wing in their hanger. With ship-linked firing capabilities, each bomber in the wing is able to launch four missiles simultaneously, enabling them to rival even an M7M in destructive power.</t>
 <t id="80463">{17,16601}</t>
 <t id="80464">After an embarrasing forray into Terran space, in which the attacking Paranid fleet was fended off by a lone USC Heavy Destroyer, the Paranid Military began designing their own Heavy Destroyer.\n\nBased on the frame of the Odysseus, the Proetus-Class Heavy destroyer is a formidable warship. With weapon systems based on stolen Terran designs and shielding technology purchased from the Teladi, the Proetus has already proven its sheer strength after the captain of the maiden voyage disobeyed orders, took the prototype version into Kha'ak territory and managed to take out an Advanced Destroyer before being forced to retreat. This original prototype was rechristened "Dukes Redemption" and is currently stationed guarding "Dukes Citadel".\n\nDocking Capacity: 4 x Fighter Class; 3 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="80465">#{9,504}{9,505}{9,500}{9,500}</t>
 <t id="80466">#EFFA is one of the original CPU ships sent out by Earth's terraforming project. It was one of the first to recieve the bugged software update and it is assumed to be one of the main command ships for the entire Xenon fleet.\n\nATF scientists have speculated that #EFFA may well have attained self-awareness and there are several Terran political movements that say that wiping out #EFFA and its fleet would amount to genocide.</t>  
 <t id="80467">{17,16811}</t>
 <t id="80468">The USC TM Macana-Class Military Transport is the Terran answer to the Commonwealth's own long-serving Military Transport ships. \n\nAble to dock up to four fighters, the Macana excels at light-carrier support for larger vessels, or as a base of operations for expeditionary groups on long-range patrols.\n\nHowever, the Macana is not designed for combat situations, making it more suited to guide operations from a distance while its fighter-wing takes care of any hostiles it might encounter.\n\nDocking Capacity: 4 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80469">{17,10021} {17,16811}</t>
 <t id="80470">The Advanced variant of the USC TM Macana-Class Military Transport has similar abilities as the basic version, but with double the docking space. It is the Terran answer to the Commonwealth's own long-serving Military Transport ships. \n\nAble to dock up to eight fighters, the Macana excels at light-carrier support for larger vessels, or as a base of operations for expeditionary groups on long-range patrols.\n\nHowever, the Macana is not designed for combat situations, making it more suited to guide operations from a distance while its fighter-wing takes care of any hostiles it might encounter.\n\nDocking Capacity: 8 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80471">{17,16501}</t>
 <t id="80472">The Aquata-class Heavy Carrier is the Royal Boron Navy's answer to the Split Lotan. It is a formidable warship with space for several wings of fighters, without sacrificing its offensive capabilities, unlike the aging Shark.\n\nWith a weapon and targeting system taken straight from the Argon Daedalus, it is hoped that this ship will be the ultimate deterrant against any future Split aggression.\n\nDocking Capacity: 45 x Fighter Class; 3 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="80473">Oceanus</t>
 <t id="80474">A recent addition to the Boron Navy, the Oceanus light destroyer boasts an integration of cutting edge technology accumulated over decades of collaborated research with Argon Military scientists. Utilising the new Fangtooth MkIV targeting system, alongside a heavy array of weapon loadouts, the Oceanus is able to deliver heavy ordinance with unrivalled speed and precision, minimizing the possibility of collateral damage in combat.\n\nCurrently the most advanced Boron warship brought into service by the Boron Royal Navy, the Oceanus, although limited in numbers, stands as force of deterrence against an ever present threat of a Split invasion.\n\nDocking space - 3 x Fighter Class</t>
 <t id="80475">Mantis</t>
 <t id="80476">The Split Mantis is a fast, sleek and aggressive luxury cruiser. Initially designed to serve as a fleet coordination and recon corvette, the need for such a vessel in current Split military operations proved infinitely small.\n\n In order to avoid losing out on governmental funding, the design team quickly re-modelled the interior to accommodate several luxury suites and released the design to the general public.</t>
 <t id="80477">Blackbird</t>
 <t id="80478">The Teladi Blackbird is an unusual ship; a luxury liner designed by a race with very little sense for aesthetics or luxury in general.\n\nThe design and controls were modified for non-Teladi pilots, as even the manufacturers of the Geochen realized that the ship would have little marketability among the Teladi themselves. Even so, the ship is still built on the tried and tested basic Teladi principles of high shielding and relatively low speed. The huge cargo bay is another bonus, allowing it to hold months' worth of provisions for solitary exile voyages.</t>
 <t id="80479">Lance</t>
 <t id="80480">With the number of Terran billionaires and space-based entrepreneurs growing, the market for a strictly Terran-designed luxury cruiser was recognised. The Lance is the result.\n\nMade to fill the gap in the civil markets, it is reasonably heavily armed and adequately shielded, though the actual luxury aspect has taken a secondary role. Built to impress rather than please, the Lance is the posing vessel of the year as impractical as it is fashionable.</t>
 <t id="80481">USC Security License</t>
 <t id="80483">{17,16721}</t>
 <t id="80484">The Tenshi is the basic corvette-class ship employed by the Yaki Syndicate. It is a reverse-engineered Nemesis, which the Yaki have made far more fearsome than the Paranid mainstay.\n\nWhile it keeps many of the same abilities as the Nemesis, Yaki engineers have managed to significantly boost the speed output of the Tenshi's engines and have even improved the size of the cargo bays to better suit the needs of the Yaki Syndicate.</t>
 <t id="80485">Type IV</t>
 <t id="20001">{17,80485}</t>
 <t id="80487">Beryll</t>
 <t id="80488">Deployment Kit</t>
 <t id="80489">{17,3983} {17,80488}</t>
 <t id="80490">Jumpdrive Deployment  Kits are a new innovation being employed by many Corporations to quickly distribute jumpdrives to newly commissioned ships without having to send them to their HQ for outfitting. The kit contains everything required for remote deployment of a jumpdrive, including technical specifications of all major race power systems, so the kit can be deployed on alomst any ship that is capable of mounting a jumpdrive. Once deployed on a ship, the kit automatically reconfigures the included jumpdrive to integrate into the ship's systems and interfaces with the ships computer, bringing its jump functions online.</t>
 <t id="80491">{17,7021} {17,10001}</t>
 <t id="80492">The Medusa Vanguard is a new M3+ ship designed specifically to outlast an opponent. Based on the Bala Gi Research Inc. Medusa design, it has class leading shield systems for a ship of this size, while maintaining typical Paranid design traits of high speed, maneuovrability and powerful weapons systems.</t>
 <t id="80493">Hammerhead</t>
 <t id="80494">The latest result of the new Boron military diversification campaign, the Hammerhead is doubtlessly one of the most refined examples of speciality shipbuilding in Boron history.\n\nSleek, spacious and menacing, the Hammerhead is an excellent border patrol leader. Though it is not the leading vessel in any one characteristic when compared to other carrier frigates, the Hammerhead provides the most rounded and balanced performance. Although it is estimated to be almost twice as expensive to produce as regular frigates, the Hammerhead is still relatively affordable thanks to heavy government subsidisation. This ship has acquired a status in the industry, serving as the yardstick for its class.\n\nDocking space - 18 x Fighter Class</t>
 <t id="80495">Artemis</t>
 <t id="80496">Following the trend of employing frigate carriers in border patrol duty, a strategy established by the Argon with their successful Griffon M7 carrier, the Paranid Empire issued an order for a carrier frigate design of their own. Superior to the early Griffon variants in every way, the current Artemis, the result of several months of corporate espionage and outright plagiarism, is indeed a vastly improved version of the Argon prototype.\n\nUnfortunately, the Artemis is still considered very much a work in progress, and retains a number of issues that would not appear in a more polished, finalised version. Due to pressure from the Priest Kings, the prototype Artemis blueprints were sent to all major Paranid shipyards before the actual ship could be put through field tests. Nevertheless, the military has not reported any major issues with the ship as yet, so for all intents and purposes, it is a bona fide carrier frigate, well worth its price.\n\nDocking space - 24 x Fighter Class</t>
 <t id="80497">Heron</t>
 <t id="80498">The Heron is the Teladi Company's response to the recent carrier frigate trend that has taken the Commonwealth militaries by storm.\n\nCheap, rough, sturdy and completely devoid of any aesthetic embellishment, the Heron fulfils its major function of figher deployment without any unnecessary fuss. Though construction quality is estimated to be extremely low, there are as yet no known cases of these ships spontaneously exploding in flight. The Teladi military has purchased a number of Herons, but the main purpose of this ship is to fill a market niche, which is the one task it completely fulfils.\n\nDocking space - 25 x Fighter Class</t>
 <t id="80499">Shard</t>
 <t id="80500">After concerns in the Terran military that Tokyo and Solaris-class carriers were becoming far too expensive to deploy due to heavy losses in deep space missions, the USC commissioned a new carrier frigate design.\n\nTaking its design cues from the much larger Kyoto, the Shard-class M7 carrier is able to rapidly deploy almost as many wings of fighters as the larger M1 class, at a much lower production cost. Its speed and class-leading shielding has made it a popular choice for the top fighter pilots looking for reassignment to the "less safe" areas of Terran space.\n\nDocking space - 27 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="80501">Poseidon</t>
 <t id="80502">With tensions rising in sectors bordering Paranid and Argon space, and an increase in the deployment of the OTAS Boreas light destroyer, the Paranid Military decided they required a light destroyer to bridge the gap between the Agamemnon and the much slower Odysseus. The resultant Poseidon-Class light destroyer out-performs its design remit in almost every department.\n\nBoasting broadside firepower comparable to a much larger destroyer, and an excellent top speed and manoeuvrability, the Poseidon has seen rapid deployment in large sectors and in rapid response forces where speed is of the essence.\n\nThe Poseidon's agility and rapid delivery of fearsome firepower makes its naming after the Greek god of the sea and earthquakes very apt.\n\nDocking Capacity: 3 x Fighter Class</t>
 <t id="80503">{9,517}</t>
 <t id="80504">After taking heavy damage to their forces from commonwealth M3 bomber designs, the Xenon have refitted an LX design to mount similar missile launch systems. Code named "R" by ATF Intelligence, these bombers are not only able to delivery large payloads, but also have excellent defensive firepower in the form of two rear turrets.</t>
 <t id="80505">{9,523}</t>
 <t id="80506">Initially thought to be a new corvette design by the ATF fleet that first encountered the "X", it was soon realised, after the incoming-missile warning sounded on every ship in the fleet, that the Xenon had developed their own M8 bomber.\n\nAfter several engagements and a successful capture, ATF scientists found the missile launch system to be an almost identical copy of those found in the Argon Gladiator. This has fuelled speculation within the ATF that the Argon military has been secretly supplying Xenon forces in order to undermine the Terran way of life, despite the Argon claim that the Xenon have reverse engineered the launcher from captured Gladiators. It was only after a USC deep-space recon pilot witnessed the almost total obliteration of the Argon garrison in Black Hole Sun at the hands of three X's that the ATF finally relented in these accusations.</t>
 <t id="80507">Sector/Station Coordinates</t>
 <t id="80509">Ship Upgrades</t>
 <t id="80511">Ship Blueprints</t>
 <t id="80513">Weapon Blueprints</t>
 <t id="80515">Station Blueprints</t>
 <t id="80517">Trading Post</t>
 <t id="80519">Lance</t>
 <t id="80520">The Lance missile appears to be specfically designed to be launched from the Kha'ak Sentinel Bomber. Sentinel's can fire these simultaneously in large numbers, so if you hear that incomming missile "beep" - be somewhere else!</t>
 <t id="80521">Tempest</t>
 <t id="80522">The success of the joint Split/Argon alliance for Operation Final Fury also led to a closer relationship between the two major Argon ship building corporations, OTAS and Jonferco, and the specialist weapon development corporation, Strong Arms. Built in Legends Home, under the direct supervision of engineers from all three corporations, the first major development from this new three-way partnership is the Tempest-class battleship.\n\nThe Tempest is now the pinnacle of ship design and engineering in commonwealth space. Intended to be deployed by both Argon and Split militaries, it is a heavy battleship fitted with the most advanced combat systems and engine technology available to the Argon and Split militaries. The Tempest is capable of delivering heavy ordinance while still able to maintain engine power that can almost match that of the Split Taipan.\n\nFollowing its maiden voyage through "pirate alley", the first Tempest off of the production line was tasked with the defence of the OTAS home system. The second has been deployed to the recently discovered Albion systems. This has upset the Split authorities as they are yet to receive their first Tempest. The OTAS CEO has claimed this is due to difficulties refitting the internal habitation sections for the Split, although this claim is refuted by the Split who say their needs are much more basic than that of humans. This controversy has led to increased tensions within the Operation Final Fury task force and the recent "friendly-fire" incident in Argon Sector M148 has been seen in some quarters as an underhand move by the Split Military to undermine Argon defences in the face of increasing Terran hostilities.\n\nDocking space - 2 fighter class, 1 M6/M8/TP/TS</t>
 <t id="80523">{17,80533} {17,4031} {17,2911}</t>
 <t id="80524">These M3-class drones have recently been spotted undergoing tests in Albion Delta by the Beryll corporation.\n\nUsing Earth AGI technology allegedly passed to Beryll by the renegade Terran corporation, Dark Space, these automated ships represent a controversial new direction for the Argon military. The artificial intellegence in these fighers make them extremely deadly, with incredibly fast reaction times and a cold, ruthless and calculating attitude to battle.\n\nIt has been rumoured that some of the test ships had to be destroyed by the local defences when they turned on their Beryll controllers. However, this has been strongly denied by both Beryll and the Argon authorities.</t>
 <t id="80525">{17,80533} {17,4041} {17,2911}</t>
 <t id="80526">The Beryll Corporation are currently developing AGI combat drones using old Terraformer technology allegedly obtained from the Terran Dark Space Corporation after the outbreak of war between the Argon and Terrans. It is rumoured that many on the Dark Space Corporation board of directors consider trade with the Commonwealth to be essential for their future prosperity, so they approached the Argon Beryll Corporation with a deal to sell them the Terraformer tech in an attempt to level the playing field between the two races.\n\nThis M4-Class interceptor is extremely fast and well armed, and its AGI control systems give it response times far shorter than anything possible with a human pilot.</t>
 <t id="80527">{17,80533} {17,4051} {17,2911}</t>
 <t id="80528">With full AGI control systems, this M5-Class drone is currently being operated by the Beryll Corporation and it is increasingly seeing deployment on the Argon front lines as the main Argon military becomes increasingly stretched.\n\nIts AGI control system enables the ship to perform manoeuvres that would be impossible with a human pilot. It is currently one of the fastest ships in the Argon fleet, with only the Discoverer Explorer able to outrun it.</t>
 <t id="80529">{1000,126} {9,502}{9,515}{9,520} {17,80531}</t>
 <t id="80530">The Terraformer CPU ships were initially part of the terraforming fleet sent through the Sol system jumpgate to the alien gate system to terraform suitable planets ready for colonisation.\n\nA bugged software update affected the majority of CPU ships and led to the emergence of the xenon threat. When the gate system was reconfigured to form the Commonwealth of Planets, although the majority were trapped in remote systems outside of the main gate system, several remained in remote sectors within the commonwealth and began to build the main Xenon fleet.\n\nMost CPU ships within the gate system are suspected to be deep in the Xenon core sectors and heavily defended by the Xenon. However, there have been several reports that some have been captured, reprogrammed and deployed in a variety of defensive and offensive roles. It is unknown how many CPU ships are still operable and it is rumoured that the Dark Space Corporation have successfully reverse engineered a CPU ship that was captured in the Aldrin system.</t>
 <t id="80531">Ship</t>
 <t id="80532">Terraformer</t>
 <t id="80533">AGI</t>
 <t id="80534">{1000,126} {17,4031}</t>
 <t id="80535">This ship was first encountered in the Aldrin system, escorting the stolen #DECA CPU ship. Many were captured along with the CPU mothership and have been converted to be flown by a pilot.\n\nDue to the Terran deep mistrust of AGI technology, many of the original automated systems have been ripped out and replaced with standard Terran equipment, although it is rumoured that the Dark Space corporation is experiementing with putting some of the original AGI technology back, but with much more robust override systems.</t>
 <t id="80536">{1000,126} {17,4041}</t>
 <t id="80537">This M4-Class interceptor is based on an old Terraformer design that has been converted for human piloting. Although most of the AGI technology has been removed, this ship is still able to outperform most interceptors with manoeuvrability to match even the latest ATF designs.\n\nPrimarily deployed by the Dark Space Corporation, most Terrans do not agree with the use of this technology and many pilots refuse to fly them. In fact, it has been known for particularly paranoid Terran pilots to shoot down these ships while in the midst of battle, despite the screams of their fellow pilots over the intercom.</t>
 <t id="80538">{1000,126} {17,4051}</t>
 <t id="80539">When the #DECA CPU ship was captured, most of the escorting scout drones instantly became inoperable. It was thought that in order to maintain surveillance of the ensuing battle, the #DECA's automated systems had integrated all scout drones' sensors with its own sensor array, so when the main ship was disabled, the scouts no longer had any usable sensors. Some attempted to fire blindly, but most simply came to a halt. The Dark Space Corporation took responsibility for researching these ships and many were refitted for use by a human pilot.\n\nThis ship is rarely seen in Terran space as the use of Terraformer tech is treated with distrust by the majority of the Terran people. However, the Dark Space Corporation frequently use them to escort their intelligence operatives due to their superior AGI-based sensor systems.</t>
 <t id="80540">Paladin</t>
 <t id="80541">The Paladin-class destroyer was donated to the Goners by Terracorp, utilising a derelict hull from an early OTAS prototype of the ship that would become the Boreas. Terracorp regularly purchase derelict ships from OTAS to recycle the hulls, but their engineers loved this design so much, they decided to save it.\n\nThe Goners had been increasingly demanding of Terracorp, a company who share a long partnership with the Goners, to defend the Goner Temple from increasing Kha'ak attacks. With the outbreak of war with the Terrans on the Goner's doorstep, Terracorp decided it would be cheaper in the long run to give the Goners a deterrent - the Paladin. Initially the Goners were reluctant to accept a warship, but after assurances from Terracorp that its weaponry would be largly defensive and would only ever be used as a last resort, they reluctantly agreed.\n\nDue to their peaceful nature, the Goners refuse to man the weapons systems, so although the ship is mainly crewed by Goners, the weapons operators are usually Terracorp employees.\n\nAlthough this ship is only lightly armed, its powerful shield array means it can outlast most opponents. It is also an extremely fast destroyer and currently holds the record as the "Fastest in Class" in the Freedom's Reach time trials.</t>
 <t id="80542">Crusader</t>
 <t id="80543">With Goner Rangers increasingly coming under attack from pirates, Xenon and Kha'ak, the Goners commissioned Bala Gi Research Inc. to design them a new ship for their Rangers with a better defence system. To their dismay, Bala Gi delivered them a ship with offensive weapons!\n\nAfter intially rejecting the design, the Goners relented when they realised that the front mounted main guns were extremely light and barely enough to shoot down a space fly.\n\nThe Crusader is based on an early prototype design of the Argon Eclipse. Nick-named "The Slug", it is fast, agile and features cutting-edge defences and cargo bay sub-space extension technology. This huge cargo bay and upgraded power generator enables this M3-sized ship to be able to utilise the jumpdrive, giving this ship one of the largest ranges of any ship this size.</t>
 <t id="80544">Komodo</t>
 <t id="80545">Using schematics that were acquired at the end of the last Split civil war, the Split M2-Class "Komodo" was designed to be one of the most fearsome ships ever made, with a vast array of front facing weapons. This drew the attention of Patriarch Rhonkar who commissioned it for exclusive use as his flagship. However due to the increasingly hostile state of the galaxy these ships were put into production for use by the most trusted Split captains.\n\nAlthough its frontal firepower is formidable, little attention has been given to its defensive capabilities, with Captains forced to rely on the small contingent of fighters the Komodo can fit into its modest internal hanger.\n\nDocking space - 16x Fighter Class, 2x TS/TP Class</t>
 <t id="80546">Cheetah</t>
 <t id="80547">This Split prototype M6-class "Cheetah" was custom built to act as a testbed for newly developed technologies. It was designed completely from scratch to incorporate Ho t'Sht's prototype Matter/Anti-matter engine. Equipped with expanded laser generators for weapons testing and missile systems, which have been modified to launch bording pods, the Split Cheetah is a force to be reckoned with.</t>
 <t id="81000">zzPLACEHOLDER KOG</t>
 <t id="81004">zzPLACEHOLDER KOG</t>
 <t id="81100">zzPLACEHOLDER KOG</t>
 <t id="81102">zzPLACEHOLDER KOG</t>
 <t id="81104">zzPLACEHOLDER KOG</t>
 <t id="81106">zzPLACEHOLDER KOG</t>
 <t id="81108">zzPLACEHOLDER KOG</t>
 <t id="81110">Wing</t>
 <t id="81111">Bomber</t>
 <t id="81112">Scanner</t>
 <t id="81113">Station</t>
 <t id="81114">{17,13131} {17,81113}</t>
 <t id="81116">{1000,1012} {17,81113}</t>
 <t id="81118">{1000,121} {1000,30000} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="81120">{1000,101} {1000,30000} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="81122">Security</t>
</page>
<page id="1000" title="Jobs Names" descr="Naval and corporate designations" voice="yes">
 <t id="151">{9,500}{9,505}{9,513}</t>
 <t id="152">{9,517}{9,501}{9,513}</t>
 <t id="153">{9,518}{9,503}{9,502}{9,502}</t>
 <t id="154">{9,519}{9,502}{9,518}{9,505}</t>
 <t id="155">{9,515}{9,503}{9,503}</t>
 <t id="156">{9,500}{9,518}{9,503}{9,505}</t>
 <t id="5105091">{1000,151} {17,5091}</t>
 <t id="5140002">{1000,151} {1000,40002}</t>
 <t id="5140004">{1000,151} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="5140007">{1000,151} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="5160101">{1000,151} {1000,60101}</t>
 <t id="5201024">{1000,152} {1000,1024}</t>
 <t id="5240002">{1000,152} {1000,40002}</t>
 <t id="5240004">{1000,152} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="5240007">{1000,152} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="5260101">{1000,152} {1000,60101}</t>
 <t id="5301020">{1000,153} {1000,1020} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="5340002">{1000,153} {1000,40002}</t>
 <t id="5340004">{1000,153} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="5340010">{1000,153} {1000,40010}</t>
 <t id="5360008">{1000,153} {1000,60008}</t>
 <t id="5360101">{1000,153} {1000,60101}</t>
 <t id="5401050">{1000,154} {1000,1050}</t>
 <t id="5440004">{1000,154} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="5440007">{1000,154} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="5460101">{1000,154} {1000,60101}</t>
 <t id="5501042">{1000,155} {1000,1042}</t>
 <t id="5540004">{1000,155} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="5540007">{1000,155} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="5540009">{1000,155} {1000,40009}</t>
 <t id="5560101">{1000,155} {1000,60101}</t>
 <t id="5640004">{1000,156} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="102340004">{1000,1023} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="102430000">{1000,1023} {1000,30000}</t>
 <t id="103330000">{1000,1033} {1000,30000}</t>
 <t id="103340004">{1000,1033} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="103340010">{1000,1033} {1000,40010}</t>
 <t id="104030000">{1000,1040} {1000,30000}</t>
 <t id="104040004">{1000,1040} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="104060009">{1000,1040} {1000,60009}</t>
 <t id="104330000">{1000,1043} {1000,30000}</t>
 <t id="104340004">{1000,1043} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="104360004">{1000,1043} {1000,60004}</t>
 <t id="105130000">{1000,1051} {1000,30000}</t>
 <t id="105140004">{1000,1051} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="105160006">{1000,1051} {1000,60006}</t>
 <t id="120000001">{1000,138} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000002">{1000,1051} {1000,10009}</t>
 <t id="120000003">{1000,1051} {1000,10010}</t>
 <t id="120000004">{1000,1051} {1000,10012}</t>
 <t id="120000005">{1000,1051} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000006">{1000,150} {1000,10022}</t>
 <t id="120000007">{1000,150} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="120000008">{1000,150} {1000,3003}</t>
 <t id="120000009">{1000,150} {1000,3008}</t>
 <t id="120000010">{1000,137} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000011">{1000,1040} {1000,3008}</t>
 <t id="120000012">{1000,1040} {1000,30009}</t>
 <t id="120000013">{1000,1040} {1000,10012}</t>
 <t id="120000014">{1000,1040} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000015">{1000,144} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000016">{1000,146} {1000,10022}</t>
 <t id="120000017">{1000,146} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000018">{1000,133} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000019">{1000,1094} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000020">{1000,1098} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000021">{1000,1091} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000022">{1000,1033} {1000,10003}</t>
 <t id="120000023">{1000,1033} {1000,30009}</t>
 <t id="120000024">{1000,1033} {1000,10012}</t>
 <t id="120000025">{1000,1033} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000026">{1000,1043} {1000,3008}</t>
 <t id="120000027">{1000,1043} {1000,3003}</t>
 <t id="120000028">{1000,1043} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000029">{1000,1023} {1000,3010}</t>
 <t id="120000030">{1000,1023} {1000,3004}</t>
 <t id="120000031">{1000,1023} {1000,10012}</t>
 <t id="120000032">{1000,1023} {17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120000033">{17,4031} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000034">{17,4031} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000035">{17,4041} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000036">{17,4041} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000037">{17,4051} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000038">{17,4051} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000039">{1000,1040} {1000,10003}</t>
 <t id="120000040">{1000,120} {17,4031} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000041">{1000,120} {17,4031} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000042">{1000,120} {17,4041} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000043">{1000,120} {17,4041} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000044">{1000,120} {17,4051} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000045">{1000,120} {17,4051} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000046">{1000,132} {1000,20016}</t>
 <t id="120000047">{1000,1023} {1000,20016}</t>
 <t id="120000048">{1000,1043} {1000,20016}</t>
 <t id="120000049">{1000,1033} {1000,20016}</t>
 <t id="120000050">{1000,1051} {1000,20016}</t>
 <t id="120000051">Racer</t>
 <t id="120000052">{1000,146} {1000,60009}</t>
 <t id="120000053">{1000,150} {1000,30000}</t>
 <t id="120000054">{1000,150} {1000,40004}</t>
 <t id="120000055">{17,81111} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000056">{17,81111} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000057">{1000,40004} {17,81111}</t>
 <t id="120000058">{1000,124} {1000,30015}</t>
 <t id="120000059">{1000,120} {17,81111} {17,81110}</t>
 <t id="120000060">{1000,120} {17,81111} {17,81110} Leader</t>
 <t id="120000061">{1000,120}/{1000,121} {1000,40009}</t>
 <t id="120000062">{1000,120}/{1000,121} {1000,40008} &quot;{7,1023824}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000063">{1000,40008} &quot;{7,1023805}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000064">{1000,40008} &quot;{7,1023819}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000065">{17,80487} {1000,60010}</t>
 <t id="120000066">{17,80487} {1000,60003}</t>
 <t id="120000067">{17,80487} {1000,60012}</t>
 <t id="120000068">{17,80487} {1000,10001}</t>
 <t id="120000069">{17,80487} {1000,10009}</t>
 <t id="120000070">{1000,101} {1000,40008} &quot;{7,1023800}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000071">{1000,102} {1000,40008} &quot;{7,1023828}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000072">{1000,103} {1000,40008} &quot;{1000,1020} {17,4311}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000073">{1000,104} {1000,40008} &quot;{7,1023825}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000074">{1000,105} {1000,40008} &quot;{13,2101}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000075">{1000,118} {1000,40008} &quot;{7,1023818}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000076">{1000,2040006} &quot;{17,10771}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120000077">{17,80487}</t>
 <t id="120000078">{17,80487}</t>
 <t id="120000079">{1000,150} {1000,30005}</t>
 <t id="120000080">{17,81122}</t>
 <t id="120065000">{1000,2040006} &quot;{17,10771}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065001">ATF Flagship &quot;Valhalla&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065002">{1000,2040008} &quot;{17,16891}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065003">ATF Command Ship &quot;Freyja&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065004">{1000,140008} &quot;{17,4701}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065005">Argon Command Ship &quot;Atlas&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065006">{1000,140006} &quot;{17,5091}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065007">Argon Flagship &quot;Argon One&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065008">{1000,240006} &quot;{1000,1024}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065009">Boron Flagship &quot;Blue Storm&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065010">{1000,240008} &quot;{17,5521}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065011">Boron Command Ship &quot;Blue Arrow&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065012">{1000,440006} &quot;{1000,1042}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065013">Paranid Flagship &quot;Maximus's Pride&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065014">{1000,340008} &quot;{1000,1034} {1000,60005}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065015">Split Command Ship &quot;Whi's Assassin&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065016">{1000,340006} &quot;{1000,1020} {17,90208}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065017">Split Flagship &quot;Matriarch's Wolf&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065018">{1000,1050} {1000,40008} &quot;{17,6231}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065019">Talonfire Command Ship &quot;Penatron&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065020">{1000,540006} &quot;{7,30050}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065021">Teladi Flagship &quot;CEO's Investment&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065022">{1000,840008} &quot;{17,3811}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065023">Pirate Command Ship &quot;Orinoco&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065024">{1000,840006} &quot;{17,16751}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065025">Pirate Flagship &quot;Polacca&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065026">{1000,1940008} &quot;{17,6321}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065027">Yaki Command Ship &quot;Midnight Star&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065028">{1000,1940006} &quot;{17,13081}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065029">Yaki Flagship &quot;Shuri&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065030">{1000,1840008} &quot;{17,16441}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065031">Terran Command Ship &quot;Excalibur&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065032">{1000,1840006} &quot;{17,13131}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065033">Terran Flagship &quot;McCallum&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065034">{1000,640008} {9,525}</t>
 <t id="120065035">Xenon Command Ship Z \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065036">{1000,540008} &quot;{17,6271}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065037">Teladi Command Ship &quot;The Wise Guy&quot; \(XRM\)</t>
 <t id="120065038">{1000,440008} &quot;{1000,1096} {7,1021706}&quot;</t>
 <t id="120065039">Paranid Command Ship &quot;Duke's Redemption&quot;</t>
</page>
<page id="1266" title="Racenames" descr="0">
 <t id="16">Independant</t>
 <t id="216">I.</t>
</page>
<page id="1271" title="Misc" descr="Greetings, Warnings etc." voice="yes">
 <t id="102002">{17,10009}</t>
 <t id="102003">{17,10009}</t>
 <t id="80390">{1271,102038}</t>
 <t id="102055">{1271,102038}</t>
 <t id="102075">{1271,102038}</t>
</page>
<page id="1999" title="Ware Transport Class" descr="0">
 <t id="0">S</t>
 <t id="1">M</t>
 <t id="2">L</t>
 <t id="3">XL</t>
 <t id="4">XXL</t>
 <t id="6">NA</t>
 <t id="10">Small Containers S</t>
 <t id="11">Medium Containers M</t>
 <t id="12">Large Containers L</t>
 <t id="13">Extra Large Containers XL</t>
 <t id="14">Huge Containers XXL</t>
 <t id="16">Not Applicable</t>
</page>
<page id="3895" title="Character Lines [TEXT]" descr="0">
 <t id="640001">{player.name},\n\nThe Imperial Commission for Cartography and Sector Science has just informed us that the unholy entity's request to register a sector name, Case XU-246-20-03-PS, has been granted. The required fees have been paid and all forms properly completed and submitted.\n\nThe unworthy {player.name} is now a legal sector owner. A formal certificate has just been transmitted.\n\nThe lowerlife is now dismissed and should attend to his new duties as a sector owner.\n\n[center][select value='teladi']{7,1023007} Var. 1[/select][/center]\n[center][select value='split']{7,1023007} Var. 2[/select][/center]\n[center][select value='boron']{7,1023007} Var. 3[/select][/center]\n[center][select value='argon']{7,1023007} Var. 4[/select][/center]\n[center][select value='paranid']{7,1023007} Var. 5[/select][/center]\n\nReverend {actor.name@CSV_toplevel.CSVNotaractor}</t>
</page>
<page id="9950" title="XRM Scripts Text" descr="AL Plugin Text">
 <t id="1">XRM Core Functions</t>
 <t id="2">XRM Core Functions</t>
 <t id="3">[author]XRM[/author][center]_________________________\n\n[blue] ---EQUIP PAR SHIPS--- [/blue]\n_________________________\n\n[yellow]NOTE - The PAR equip operation will clear the cargo bays of all PAR ships selected.[/yellow]\n\n\n\nOn which object do you wish to perform the PAR Equip Operation?\n\n[select value="1"]Current Target[/select]\n\n[select value="2"]Select Station or Carrier from Universe Map[/select]\n\n[select value="3"]Abort PAR Equip Operation[/select]\n[/center]</t>
 <t id="4">SRM Shipyard Pack Enabled</t>
 <t id="5">SRM Shipyard Pack Disabled</t>
 <t id="6">\033ROFF\033X</t>
 <t id="7">\033GON\033X</t>
 <t id="8">\033Y---UPDATE NOW---\033X</t>
 <t id="9">Use the options below to configure SRM features. After choosing your options, you must hit "UPDATE NOW" for the changes to take effect.</t>
 <t id="10">Reinitialize SRM - \033RWARNING - this will clear and reset all features.\033X</t>
 <t id="11">\033B---REINITIALIZE NOW---\033X</t>
 <t id="12">Combat Mod 4 Factory Pack Enabled</t>
 <t id="13">Combat Mod 4 Factory Pack Disabled</t>
 <t id="14">Use the options below to configure Combat Mod 4 features. After choosing your options, you must hit "UPDATE NOW" for the changes to take effect.</t>
 <t id="15">Reinitialize CMOD4 - \033RWARNING - this will clear and reset all features.\033X</t>
 <t id="16">[center]\033CFEDERAL ARGON MILITARY COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nPilot, it is a grave time for the Argon people. We have been accused of a deplorable act of terrorism and all our attempts at a diplomatic solution have failed.\n\nWar is coming...\n\nWe have reports of a massive Terran fleet massing in McCallum Relay and military build up in Mars. Our operations centres in Farpoint Relay and Argon Sector M148 are coordinating our defence. Argon intellegence believes the Terrans will attack our main shipbuilding facilities in Omicron Lyrae and the support infrastructure in the surrounding systems. It is likely the attack will begin in Circle of Labour and move south into Omicron Lyrae itself.\n\nYour record as an Argon pilot speaks for itself. You have been issued with an Argon Military Law Enforcement License. With this you can connect to the Federal Argon Military Intelligence Network and gain up-to-date reports of our fleet status, current incursions by our enemies and where we are striking back. Simply assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nIf the Argon way of life is to continue, we must repel this threat. We need every pilot to perform to the ability we know you are capable of. Aid us in the defence of Circle of Labour, help repel diversary attacks in the surrounding systems, protect our main operations bases in Farpoint Relay and Argon Sector M148, or patrol our other borders against pirates, Xenon and even the Paranid, in case they look on this as an opportunity to settle some old scores.\n\nIf we can strike against the Terran bases of operations in McCallum Relay and Mars it may slow down or even stop their advance, but beware, these systems are heavily defended and you will need a substantial fleet to destroy one of these bases. Our fleet is spread thin so we cannot mount a large scale assault at this time.\n\nThis is our most desperate hour... Good luck pilot!\n\n[right]- Admiral Calon S. Danna[/right]</t>
 <t id="17">\033C- Authentication verified - \033XConnection to the Federal Argon Military Intelligence Network has been confirmed.</t>
 <t id="18">\033RCurrent Terran Incursions:-\033X</t>
 <t id="19">\033CCurrent Argon Military Strikes:-\033X</t>
 <t id="20">Access to the Federal Argon Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your notoriety is too low.</t>
 <t id="21">\033RStatus Of Main Terran Invasion Fleet:-\033X</t>
 <t id="22">\033GLocation:\033X</t>
 <t id="23">\033GStatus:\033X</t>
 <t id="24">\033ROther Enemy Race Activity:-\033X</t>
 <t id="25">\033RCurrent Xenon Activity:-\033X</t>
 <t id="26">\033RCurrent Kha'ak Activity:-\033X</t>
 <t id="27">\033RCurrent Pirate and Yaki Activity:-\033X</t>
 <t id="28">\033YClose connection to network\033X</t>
 <t id="29">\033YBack to main page\033X</t>
 <t id="30">Access to the Federal Argon Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your notoriety is too low.</t>
 <t id="31">Access to the Federal Argon Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your do not possess a valid law enforcement license.</t>
 <t id="32">Please select a race military network:-</t>
 <t id="33">\033C- Authentication verified - \033XConnection to the USC Military Intelligence Network has been confirmed.</t>
 <t id="34">\033RCurrent Argon Incursions:-\033X</t>
 <t id="35">\033CCurrent Terran Military Strikes:-\033X</t>
 <t id="37">\033CStatus Of Main Terran Invasion Fleet:-\033X</t>
 <t id="38">Access to the USC Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your notoriety is too low.</t>
 <t id="39">Access to the USC Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your do not possess a valid law enforcement license.</t>
 <t id="40">\033RParanid skirmishes detected in:-\033X</t>
 <t id="41">\033RCurrent Split Incursions:-\033X</t>
 <t id="42">Access to the Boron Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your notoriety is too low.</t>
 <t id="43">Access to the Boron Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your do not possess a valid law enforcement license.</t>
 <t id="44">Argon Military Intel Network</t>
 <t id="45">Boron Military Intel Network</t>
 <t id="46">Split Military Intel Network</t>
 <t id="47">Paranid Military Intel Network</t>
 <t id="48">Teladi Military Intel Network</t>
 <t id="49">USC Military Intel Network</t>
 <t id="50">\033C- Authentication verified - \033XConnection to the Boron Military Intelligence Network has been confirmed.</t>
 <t id="51">\033C- Authentication verified - \033XConnection to the Split Military Intelligence Network has been confirmed.</t>
 <t id="52">\033C- Authentication verified - \033XConnection to the Paranid Military Intelligence Network has been confirmed.</t>
 <t id="53">\033C- Authentication verified - \033XConnection to the Teladi Military Intelligence Network has been confirmed.</t>
 <t id="54">Access to the Split Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your notoriety is too low.</t>
 <t id="55">Access to the Split Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your do not possess a valid law enforcement license.</t>
 <t id="56">Access to the Paranid Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your notoriety is too low.</t>
 <t id="57">Access to the Paranid Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your do not possess a valid law enforcement license.</t>
 <t id="58">Access to the Teladi Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your notoriety is too low.</t>
 <t id="59">Access to the Teladi Military Intelligence Network has been denied. Your do not possess a valid law enforcement license.</t>
 <t id="60">\033RBoron skirmishes detected in:-\033X</t>
 <t id="61">\033RArgon skirmishes detected in:-\033X</t>
 <t id="62">\033RCurrent Yaki Incursions:-\033X</t>
 <t id="63">[center]\033CUNITED SPACE COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nPilot, as you know a deplorable act of terrorism has been commited against the Terran race and tens of thousands of innocent people lost their lives. Now we see our "brothers" true nature. The Argons are our enemies and we must retaliate.\n\nCoordinated by our bases in Mars and McCallum Relay, plans for a strike against the heart of the Argon race are nearing completion. A massive joint task force of both the USC and ATF is assembling in McCallum Relay. This fleet is tasked with securing the Terran way of life by eliminating all Argon military accets in the sectors south of Heretic's End. In addition the USC Military Command will be sending small interdiction battle groups to try and divert Argon defence forces away from the main route of the fleet.\n\nYour record with the United Space Command is second to none. You have been issued with an Terran Security License, which will enable you to connect to the USC Military Intelligence Network and gain up-to-date reports of our fleet status, current incursions by our enemies and where we are striking back. Simply assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nThe time has come for us to unite against this threat to our way of life. We need every pilot to perform to the ability we know you are capable of. Join up with the main task force in our push into Argon space, or keep the enemy distracted by making daring raids into other sectors. Aid us in the defence of our local sectors that are at risk from Argon strikes, protect our main operations bases in McCallum Relay and Mars, or patrol our other borders against pirates, Xenon and even the Kha'ak, who, thanks to our "brothers" in the Commonwealth of Planets, have started to take an interest in our space.\n\nIf we can strike against the Argon bases of operations in Farpoint Relay and Argon Sector M148, it may slow down or even stop their strikes in our space, but beware, these systems are heavily defended and you will need a substantial fleet to destroy one of these bases.\n\nThe time has come to defend our race once again from an alien threat - Godspeed pilot!\n\n[right]- Admiral William P. Santiago[/right]</t>
 <t id="64">\033CCurrent Split Military Strikes:-\033X</t>
 <t id="65">\033CCurrent Paranid Military Strikes:-\033X</t>
 <t id="66">\033CCurrent Boron Military Strikes:-\033X</t>
 <t id="67">\033CCurrent Teladi Military Strikes:-\033X</t>
 <t id="68">[center]\033CUNITED SPACE COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nPilot, as you know a deplorable act of terrorism has been commited against the Terran race and tens of thousands of innocent people lost their lives. Now we see our "brothers" true nature. The Argons are our enemies and we must retaliate.\n\nCoordinated by our bases in Mars and McCallum Relay, plans for a strike against the heart of the Argon race are nearing completion. A massive joint task force of both the USC and ATF is assembling in McCallum Relay. This fleet is tasked with securing the Terran way of life by eliminating all Argon military accets in the sectors south of Heretic's End. In addition the USC Military Command will be sending small interdiction battle groups to try and divert Argon defence forces away from the main route of the fleet.\n\nWe are sending this message to all pilots not yet registered to with the USC to answer the call to arms. Collect a Terran Security License as soon as you can from your nearest Orbital Defence Station. This will enable you to connect to the USC Military Intelligence Network and gain up-to-date reports of our fleet status, current incursions by our enemies and where we are striking back. Simply assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nThe time has come for us to unite against this threat to our way of life. We need every pilot to perform to the ability we know you are capable of. Join up with the main task force in our push into Argon space, or keep the enemy distracted by making daring raids into other sectors. Aid us in the defence of our local sectors that are at risk from Argon strikes, protect our main operations bases in McCallum Relay and Mars, or patrol our other borders against pirates, Xenon and even the Kha'ak, who, thanks to our "brothers" in the Commonwealth of Planets, have started to take an interest in our space.\n\nIf we can strike against the Argon bases of operations in Farpoint Relay and Argon Sector M148, it may slow down or even stop their strikes in our space, but beware, these systems are heavily defended and you will need a substantial fleet to destroy one of these bases.\n\nThe time has come to defend our race once again from an alien threat - Godspeed pilot!\n\n[right]- Admiral William P. Santiago[/right]</t>
 <t id="69">[center]\033CFEDERAL ARGON MILITARY COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nPilot, it is a grave time for the Argon people. We have been accused of a deplorable act of terrorism and all our attempts at a diplomatic solution have failed.\n\nWar is coming...\n\nWe have reports of a massive Terran fleet massing in McCallum Relay and military build up in Mars. Our operations centres in Farpoint Relay and Argon Sector M148 are coordinating our defence. Argon intellegence believes the Terrans will attack our main shipbuilding facilities in Omicron Lyrae and the support infrastructure in the surrounding systems. It is likely the attack will begin in Circle of Labour and move south into Omicron Lyrae itself.\n\nWe are relaying this message to all Argon pilots not yet registered with the Argon Military - We need you! Purchase an Argon Military Law Enforcement License at your nearest Free Argon Trading Station. With this you can connect to the Federal Argon Military Intelligence Network and gain up-to-date reports of our fleet status, current incursions by our enemies and where we are striking back. Simply assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nIf the Argon way of life is to continue, we must repel this threat. We need every pilot to do their bit if we are to survive! Aid us in the defence of Circle of Labour, help repel diversary attacks in the surrounding systems, protect our main operations bases in Farpoint Relay and Argon Sector M148, or patrol our other borders against pirates, Xenon and even the Paranid, in case they look on this as an opportunity to settle some old scores.\n\nIf we can strike against the Terran bases of operations in McCallum Relay and Mars it may slow down or even stop their advance, but beware, these systems are heavily defended and you will need a substantial fleet to destroy one of these bases. Our fleet is spread thin so we cannot mount a large scale assault at this time.\n\nThis is our most desperate hour... Good luck pilot!\n\n[right]- Admiral Calon S. Danna[/right]</t>
 <t id="70">[Ccenter]\033CTELADI COMPANY SECURITY FORCE\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nTo all Teladi Captains, now is time of great protit for all Teladis. The Argon and Terrans are warring, and war always bring great profitsss!\n\nThere is still danger in our sectorsss though from Xenon and Kha'ak, and even Yaki are making war in our space!\n\nWe need all Teladi Captains to be extra watchful and defend our profitsss whereever you can. To help, we have created an Intelligence Network which you can access through your shipsss computer to get news on where any enemies are. Purchase a Teladi Company Security License from you nearest Telaid Trading Station and assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nKeep you profitsss safe!\n\n[right]- Commander Yalos Hirussusis[/right]</t>
 <t id="71">[center]\033CPARANID HIGH COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nTo all Paranid Captains, it is a time of great fortune for our mighty Empire. The lesser beings are warring, and now the Paranid will be free from their interference.\n\nHowever, there are still some troublesome threats to the Empire from Xenon, Kha'ak, and those Yaki pirates!\n\nWe need all Paranid Captains to be extra watchful and defend our sectors for the glory of the Empire whereever you can. To help, we have created an Intelligence Network which you can access through your ships computer to get news on where any enemies are. Purchase a Paranid Police License from you nearest Paranid Trading Station and assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nFor the honour of Priest Emperor!\n\n[right]- Admiral Kelarsatatsalss[/right]</t>
 <t id="72">[center]\033CSPLIT HIGH COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nTo all Split Captains, the time for Split revenge has come. With the Argon and Terrans at war, now there is no one to save those cowardly Boron.\n\nBut before we can make our war, we must remove the threats to our great families from Xenon, Kha'ak, and those Yaki pirates!\n\nWe need all Split Captains to be extra watchful and attack our enemies whereever you can. To help, we have created an Intelligence Network which you can access through your ships computer to get news on where any enemies are. Purchase a Split Police License from you nearest Split Trading Station and assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nMay battle now begin!\n\n[right]- Commander Cai Fui Snt[/right]</t>
 <t id="73">[center]\033CROYAL BORON MILITARY COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nTo all Boron Captains, it is a time of great sadness for Queen Atreus. Our Argon allies have been accused of a terrible act and now the Terrans are invading their sectors, and if they are not stopped they may try to attack the Kingdom as well!\n\nAll Borons must be vigilant, not only to the Terran threat, but also the Xenon, Kha'ak, and the everpresent threat from the evil Split!\n\nTo help, we have created an Intelligence Network which you can access through your ships computer to get news on where any enemies are. Purchase a Boron Law Enforcement License from you nearest Royal Boron Trading Station and assign a hotkey in your ship's control configuration to access the military network.\n\nFor the love of the Queen.\n\n[right]- Commander Molo Go[/right]</t>
 <t id="74">Other Enemy Race Activity...</t>
 <t id="75">Current Xenon Activity...</t>
 <t id="76">Current Kha'ak Activity...</t>
 <t id="77">Current Pirate and Yaki Activity...</t>
 <t id="78">No military strikes in progress</t>
 <t id="79">No activity detected</t>
 <t id="80">No enemy invasions detected</t>
 <t id="81">ATF/USC Task Force Command Ship destroyed. Fleet is retreating.</t>
 <t id="82">Intelligence has reported the main fleet is gathering in McCallum Relay.</t>
 <t id="83">Advancing</t>
 <t id="84">Under attack</t>
 <t id="85">[author]XRM[/author][center]_________________________\n\n[blue] ---JUMPDRIVE DEPLOYMENT CONTROL--- [/blue]\n______________________________\n\n\n\n\n\nOn which object do you wish to deploy a jumpdrive?\n\nNote: Selecting a station or carrier will initiate deployment on any player owned, jumpdrive compatible docked ships, with a jumpdrive deployment kit in thier cargo bay in addition to the carrier.\n\n[select value="0"]Player Ship[/select]\n\n[select value="1"]Current Target[/select]\n\n[select value="2"]Select Station or Ship from Universe Map[/select]\n\n[select value="3"]Abort Jumpdrive Kit Deployment[/select]\n[/center]</t>
 <t id="86">\033Y$\033X</t>
 <t id="87">\033YPilot: \033X</t>
 <t id="88">\033BLast known location: \033X</t>
 <t id="89">\033GBounty: \033X</t>
 <t id="90">\033GBounties\033X</t>
 <t id="91">View Current Bounties...</t>
 <t id="92">\033GSelect range of bounties to view.\033X</t>
 <t id="93">Less than 150,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="94">150,000 - 400,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="95">400,000 - 1,500,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="96">Greater than 1,500,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="97">Current bounties offered less than 150,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="98">Current bounties offered 150,000 - 400,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="99">Current bounties offered 400,000 - 1,500,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="100">Current bounties offered greater than 1,500,000 Cr</t>
 <t id="101">\033YReturn to bounty range selection\033X</t>
 <t id="102">Bounties are paid to any pilot holding a valid police licence. In addition to the specific bounties offered below, minor bounties will be paid for the destruction of any enemy ships within our territory. Any enemy sectors that border our territory are also constantly monitored for activity. The destruction of our enemies in these sectors will also be rewarded with a minor bounty.</t>
 <t id="103">[center]\033CFEDERAL ARGON MILITARY COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Argon Federal Military would like to thank you for your aid in bringing an enemy of the Federation to justice.</t>
 <t id="104">[center]\033CROYAL BORON MILITARY COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Royal Boron Government would like to thank you in making an enemy of the Queen pay for their crimes.</t>
 <t id="105">[center]\033CSPLIT HIGH COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Family Rhonkar is pleased that you have terminated this enemy of the Split.</t>
 <t id="106">[center]\033CPARANID HIGH COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Paranid Empire looks favourably on unholy beings who aid the empire by destroying its enemies.</t>
 <t id="107">[center]\033CTELADI COMPANY SECURITY FORCE\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Teladi Company gives thanks for you killing our enemiesss and ssaving our profitsss.</t>
 <t id="108">[center]\033CUNITED SPACE COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe United Space Command would like to thank you for your aid the defence of Earth by destroying our enemies.</t>
 <t id="109"> In reward for your services we have transferred \033Y</t>
 <t id="110">\033X credits to your account.</t>
 <t id="111">A bounty of \033Y</t>
 <t id="112">\033X credits has been received from the </t>
 <t id="113">\033CFEDERAL ARGON MILITARY COMMAND\033X</t>
 <t id="114">\033CROYAL BORON MILITARY COMMAND\033X</t>
 <t id="115">\033CSPLIT HIGH COMMAND\033X</t>
 <t id="116">\033CPARANID HIGH COMMAND\033X</t>
 <t id="117">\033CTELADI COMPANY SECURITY FORCE\033X</t>
 <t id="118">\033CUNITED SPACE COMMAND\033X</t>
 <t id="119">\033CARGON/SPLIT OPERATION FINAL FURY TASK FORCE\033X</t>
 <t id="120">Bounty Check</t>
 <t id="121">\033YStatus: \033X</t>
 <t id="122">Clean</t>
 <t id="123">\033RWanted\033X</t>
 <t id="124">\033YCurrent Bounty Offered: \033X</t>
 <t id="125">\033YTarget: \033X</t>
 <t id="126">\033YCrimes: \033X</t>
 <t id="139">\033GPerform bounty check on ship\033X</t>
 <t id="140">\033GSelect new target for check\033X</t>
 <t id="141">XRM Bounty System</t>
 <t id="142">XRM Bounty System</t>
 <t id="143">\033GReturn to bounty list\033X</t>
 <t id="144">\033YLast known location: \033X</t>
 <t id="145">\033Y</t>
 <t id="146">\033B</t>
 <t id="147"></t>
 <t id="148">I have the following sector and station coordinates available for purchase:</t>
 <t id="149">I have the following ship upgrades available for purchase:</t>
 <t id="150">I have the following blueprints available for purchase:</t>
 <t id="151">Hmm... It appears you do not have enough cash - stop wasting my time!</t>
 <t id="152">It looks like you already have this upgrade installed in your ship.</t>
 <t id="153">No thanks.</t>
 <t id="154">Buy Sector Co-ordinates</t>
 <t id="155">Buy Ship Upgrades</t>
 <t id="156">Buy Ship Blueprints</t>
 <t id="157">Would you like to purchase something else?</t>
 <t id="158">Message from merchant:-</t>
 <t id="159">Yes please.</t>
 <t id="160">\033GReply:-\033X</t>
 <t id="161">A pleasure doing business with you.</t>
 <t id="162">The data upload has been rejected by your ship computer. It seems you already have this ship blueprint at your HQ.</t>
 <t id="163">You don't even own a HQ - stop wasting my time!</t>
 <t id="164">I'm afraid this upgrade is not compatible with your ship.</t>
 <t id="165"> is currently located in sector </t>
 <t id="166">The location has been added to your universe map.</t>
 <t id="167">[center]\033CFEDERAL ARGON MILITARY COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Argon Federal Military would like to thank you for your aid in destroying this enemy installation.</t>
 <t id="168">[center]\033CROYAL BORON MILITARY COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Royal Boron Government would like to thank you in destroying an installation belonging to an enemy of the Queen.</t>
 <t id="169">[center]\033CSPLIT HIGH COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Family Rhonkar is pleased that you have destroyed this enemy installation.</t>
 <t id="170">[center]\033CPARANID HIGH COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Paranid Empire looks favourably on unholy beings who aid the empire by destroying its enemies' installations.</t>
 <t id="171">[center]\033CTELADI COMPANY SECURITY FORCE\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Teladi Company gives thanks for you killing our enemiesss stationss and ssaving our profitsss.</t>
 <t id="172">[center]\033CUNITED SPACE COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe United Space Command would like to thank you for your aid the defence of Earth by destroying this enemy installation.</t>
 <t id="173">[center]\033CARGON/SPLIT OPERATION FINAL FURY TASK FORCE\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Argon Military/Split High Command "Operation Final Fury" joint task force would like to thank you for your aid the defence of all free peoples by destroying this Kha'ak installation.</t>
 <t id="174">Initiating ship systems override.</t>
 <t id="175">Override complete - the target's computer systems are now under your control.</t>
 <t id="176">Target is too far away to begin override sequence.</t>
 <t id="177">Target is still under pilot control - systems override is not possible.</t>
 <t id="178">Target's systems are still more than 50% operational - override will take another two minutes.</t>
 <t id="179">Ship board computer uplink established... Beginning level one encryption hack.</t>
 <t id="180">Level one encryption layer accessed... Beginning level two hack.</t>
 <t id="181">Target's shields are still up - systems override is not possible.</t>
 <t id="182">Target's shields are back on-line - systems override has been interrupted.</t>
 <t id="183">Target has moved out of range - systems override has been interrupted.</t>
 <t id="184">Target Board Computer central functions accessed... Beginning final override sequence.</t>
 <t id="185">Ship systems uplink has been severed by target's ship board computer. Override sequence has failed.</t>
 <t id="186">Target has been destroyed - Override sequence aborted.</t>
 <t id="187">Not a valid target - Override sequence aborted.</t>
 <t id="188">System Override Software not installed.</t>
 <t id="189">System Override Software is already running.</t>
 <t id="190">Level two encryption layer accessed... Beginning level three hack.</t>
 <t id="191">Level three encryption layer accessed... Beginning level four hack.</t>
 <t id="192">Level four encryption layer accessed... Beginning level five hack.</t>
 <t id="193">Not enough hackerchips in cargo bay - systems override is not possible. </t>
 <t id="194">Not enough energy cells in cargo bay - systems override is not possible. </t>
 <t id="195"> more required for this class of target.</t>
 <t id="196">[center]\033CARGON/SPLIT OPERATION FINAL FURY TASK FORCE\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe Argon and Split special forces would like to thank you for the elimination of a Kha'ak Hive Queen.</t>
 <t id="197"> In recognition of this astounding feat we have trasferred a reward of \033Y</t>
 <t id="198">\033X credits to your account. Well done pilot!</t>
 <t id="199">[center]\033CAGI TASK FORCE COMMAND\033X\n\033GIncoming Message...\033X[/center]\n\nThe ATF would like to thank you for the elimination of one of the primary CPU ships of the AGI menace - #EFFA.</t>
 <t id="200">[author]XRM[/author][center][blue]XRM WAR DISSABLING[/blue]\n\nDo you wish to disable the XRM Argon-Terran war?\n\n[select value="1"]Yes[/select]\n\n[select value="2"]No[/select]\n\n[/center]</t>
</page>


<page id="9950" title="XRM Scripts Text" descr="AL Plugin Text">
 <t id="10201">Weapons Violations</t>
 <t id="10202">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="10203">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Inciting Civil Disorder</t>
 <t id="10204">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Inciting Civil Disorder, Murder</t>
 <t id="10205">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Inciting Civil Disorder, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="10301">Weapons Violations</t>
 <t id="10302">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="10303">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Assault</t>
 <t id="10304">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Assault, Murder</t>
 <t id="10305">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Assault, Murder, Mass Murder</t>
 <t id="10401">Weapons Violations</t>
 <t id="10402">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="10403">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Hate Crimes</t>
 <t id="10404">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Hate Crimes, Murder</t>
 <t id="10405">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Hate Crimes, Murder, Religious Terrorism</t>
 <t id="10501">Weapons Violations</t>
 <t id="10502">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="10503">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Extortion</t>
 <t id="10504">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Extortion, Murder</t>
 <t id="10505">Weapons Violations, Destruction of Property, Extortion, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="10601">Insurgency</t>
 <t id="10602">Insurgency, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="10603">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Xenophobia</t>
 <t id="10604">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Xenophobia, Murder</t>
 <t id="10605">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Xenophobia, Murder, War Crimes</t>
 <t id="10701">Piracy</t>
 <t id="10702">Piracy, Smuggling</t>
 <t id="10703">Piracy, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="10704">Piracy, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="10705">Piracy, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Extortion</t>
 <t id="10801">Insurgency</t>
 <t id="10802">Insurgency, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="10803">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Murder</t>
 <t id="10804">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Murder, Bioterrorism</t>
 <t id="10805">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Murder, Bioterrorism, Genocide</t>

 <t id="20101">Breach of the Queen's peace</t>
 <t id="20102">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="20103">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Inciting Civil Disorder</t>
 <t id="20104">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Inciting Civil Disorder, Murder</t>
 <t id="20105">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Inciting Civil Disorder, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="20301">Breach of the Queen's peace</t>
 <t id="20302">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="20303">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Hate Crimes</t>
 <t id="20304">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Hate Crimes, Murder</t>
 <t id="20305">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Hate Crimes, Murder, Mass Murder</t>
 <t id="20401">Breach of the Queen's peace</t>
 <t id="20402">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="20403">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Assault</t>
 <t id="20404">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Assault, Murder</t>
 <t id="20405">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Assault, Murder, Religious Terrorism</t>
 <t id="20501">Breach of the Queen's peace</t>
 <t id="20502">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="20503">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Extortion</t>
 <t id="20504">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Extortion, Murder</t>
 <t id="20505">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Extortion, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="20601">Breach of the Queen's peace</t>
 <t id="20602">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="20603">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Xenophobia</t>
 <t id="20604">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Xenophobia, Murder</t>
 <t id="20605">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Xenophobia, Murder, War Crimes</t>
 <t id="20701">Breach of the Queen's peace, Piracy</t>
 <t id="20702">Breach of the Queen's peace, Piracy, Smuggling</t>
 <t id="20703">Breach of the Queen's peace, Piracy, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="20704">Breach of the Queen's peace, Piracy, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="20705">Breach of the Queen's peace, Piracy, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Extortion</t>
 <t id="20801">Breach of the Queen's peace</t>
 <t id="20802">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="20803">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Murder</t>
 <t id="20804">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Murder, Bioterrorism</t>
 <t id="20805">Breach of the Queen's peace, Criminal Damage, Murder, Bioterrorism, Genocide</t>

 <t id="30101">Privateering</t>
 <t id="30102">Privateering, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="30103">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Mayhem</t>
 <t id="30104">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Mayhem, Murder</t>
 <t id="30105">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Mayhem, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="30201">Privateering</t>
 <t id="30202">Privateering, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="30203">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Mayhem</t>
 <t id="30204">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Mayhem, Murder</t>
 <t id="30205">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Mayhem, Murder, Mass Murder</t>
 <t id="30401">Privateering</t>
 <t id="30402">Privateering, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="30403">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Assault</t>
 <t id="30404">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Assault, Murder</t>
 <t id="30405">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Assault, Murder, Religious Terrorism</t>
 <t id="30501">Privateering</t>
 <t id="30502">Privateering, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="30503">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Extortion</t>
 <t id="30504">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Extortion, Murder</t>
 <t id="30505">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Extortion, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="30601">Privateering</t>
 <t id="30602">Privateering, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="30603">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Xenophobia</t>
 <t id="30604">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Xenophobia, Murder</t>
 <t id="30605">Privateering, Destruction of Property, Xenophobia, Murder, War Crimes</t>
 <t id="30701">Piracy</t>
 <t id="30702">Piracy, Smuggling</t>
 <t id="30703">Piracy, Smuggling, Espionage</t>
 <t id="30704">Piracy, Smuggling, Espionage, Murder</t>
 <t id="30705">Piracy, Smuggling, Espionage, Murder, Extortion</t>
 <t id="30801">Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="30802">Destruction of Property, Mayhem</t>
 <t id="30803">Destruction of Property, Mayhem, Murder</t>
 <t id="30804">Destruction of Property, Mayhem, Murder, Bioterrorism</t>
 <t id="30805">Destruction of Property, Mayhem, Murder, Bioterrorism, Genocide</t>

 <t id="40101">Blasphemy</t>
 <t id="40102">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire</t>
 <t id="40103">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy</t>
 <t id="40104">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder</t>
 <t id="40105">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="40201">Blasphemy</t>
 <t id="40202">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire</t>
 <t id="40203">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy</t>
 <t id="40204">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder</t>
 <t id="40205">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="40301">Blasphemy</t>
 <t id="40302">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire</t>
 <t id="40303">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy</t>
 <t id="40304">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder</t>
 <t id="40305">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder, Mass Murder</t>
 <t id="40501">Blasphemy</t>
 <t id="40502">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire</t>
 <t id="40503">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy</t>
 <t id="40504">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder</t>
 <t id="40505">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="40601">Blasphemy</t>
 <t id="40602">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire</t>
 <t id="40603">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy</t>
 <t id="40604">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder</t>
 <t id="40605">Blasphemy, Crimes Against the Empire, Heresy, Murder, War Crimes</t>
 <t id="40701">Piracy</t>
 <t id="40702">Piracy, Crimes Against the Empire</t>
 <t id="40703">Piracy, Crimes Against the Empire, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="40704">Piracy, Crimes Against the Empire, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="40705">Piracy, Crimes Against the Empire, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Extortion</t>
 <t id="40801">Insurgency</t>
 <t id="40802">Insurgency, Crimes Against the Empire</t>
 <t id="40803">Insurgency, Crimes Against the Empire, Murder</t>
 <t id="40804">Insurgency, Crimes Against the Empire, Murder, Bioterrorism</t>
 <t id="40805">Insurgency, Crimes Against the Empire, Murder, Bioterrorism, Genocide</t>

 <t id="50101">Anti-Competitive Practices</t>
 <t id="50102">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud</t>
 <t id="50103">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Corporate Espionage</t>
 <t id="50104">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Corporate Espionage, Corporate Manslaughter</t>
 <t id="50105">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Corporate Espionage, Corporate Manslaughter, Grand Larceny</t>
 <t id="50201">Anti-Competitive Practices</t>
 <t id="50202">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud</t>
 <t id="50203">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Corporate Espionage</t>
 <t id="50204">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Corporate Espionage, Corporate Manslaughter</t>
 <t id="50205">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Corporate Espionage, Corporate Manslaughter, Grand Larceny</t>
 <t id="50301">Anti-Competitive Practices</t>
 <t id="50302">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud</t>
 <t id="50303">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement</t>
 <t id="50304">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement, Corporate Manslaughter</t>
 <t id="50305">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement, Corporate Manslaughter, Mass Murder</t>
 <t id="50401">Anti-Competitive Practices</t>
 <t id="50402">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud</t>
 <t id="50403">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement</t>
 <t id="50404">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement, Corporate Manslaughter</t>
 <t id="50405">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement, Corporate Manslaughter, Grand Larceny</t>
 <t id="50601">Anti-Competitive Practices</t>
 <t id="50602">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud</t>
 <t id="50603">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement</t>
 <t id="50604">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement, Corporate Manslaughter</t>
 <t id="50605">Anti-Competitive Practices, Credit Fraud, Embezzlement, Corporate Manslaughter, War Crimes</t>
 <t id="50701">Anti-Competitive Practices</t>
 <t id="50702">Anti-Competitive Practices, Piracy</t>
 <t id="50703">Anti-Competitive Practices, Piracy, Racketeering</t>
 <t id="50704">Anti-Competitive Practices, Piracy, Racketeering, Corporate Manslaughter</t>
 <t id="50705">Anti-Competitive Practices, Piracy, Racketeering, Corporate Manslaughter, Extortion, Grand Larceny</t>
 <t id="50801">Anti-Competitive Practices</t>
 <t id="50802">Anti-Competitive Practices, Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="50803">Anti-Competitive Practices, Criminal Damage, Corporate Manslaughter</t>
 <t id="50804">Anti-Competitive Practices, Criminal Damage, Corporate Manslaughter, Bioterrorism</t>
 <t id="50805">Anti-Competitive Practices, Criminal Damage, Corporate Manslaughter, Bioterrorism, Genocide</t>

 <t id="60101">Insurgency</t>
 <t id="60102">Insurgency, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="60103">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Conspiracy</t>
 <t id="60104">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Conspiracy, Murder</t>
 <t id="60105">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Conspiracy, Murder, War Crimes</t>
 <t id="60201">Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="60202">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="60203">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Conspiracy</t>
 <t id="60204">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Conspiracy, Murder</t>
 <t id="60205">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Conspiracy, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="60301">Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="60302">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="60303">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Assault</t>
 <t id="60304">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Assault, Murder</t>
 <t id="60305">Criminal Damages, Destruction of Property, Assault, Murder, Mass Murder</t>
 <t id="60401">Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="60402">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="60403">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Hate Crimes</t>
 <t id="60404">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Hate Crimes, Murder</t>
 <t id="60405">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Hate Crimes, Murder, Religious Terrorism</t>
 <t id="60501">Criminal Damage</t>
 <t id="60502">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="60503">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Extortion</t>
 <t id="60504">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Extortion, Murder</t>
 <t id="60505">Criminal Damage, Destruction of Property, Extortion, Murder, Terrorism</t>
 <t id="60701">Piracy</t>
 <t id="60702">Piracy, Espionage</t>
 <t id="60703">Piracy, Espionage, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="60704">Piracy, Espionage, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="60705">Piracy, Espionage, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Extortion</t>
 <t id="60801">Insurgency</t>
 <t id="60802">Insurgency, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="60803">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Murder</t>
 <t id="60804">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Murder, Bioterrorism</t>
 <t id="60805">Insurgency, Destruction of Property, Murder, Bioterrorism, Genocide</t>

 <t id="10901">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials</t>
 <t id="10902">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling</t>
 <t id="10903">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="10904">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="10905">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Arms Trafficking</t>
 <t id="20901">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials</t>
 <t id="20902">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling</t>
 <t id="20903">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="20904">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="20905">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Arms Trafficking</t>
 <t id="30901">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling</t>
 <t id="30902">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="30903">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="30904">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="30905">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Mass Murder</t>
 <t id="40901">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling</t>
 <t id="40902">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="40903">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="40904">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="40905">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Arms Trafficking</t>
 <t id="50901">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials</t>
 <t id="50902">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling</t>
 <t id="50903">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Corporate Espionage</t>
 <t id="50904">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Corporate Espionage, Murder</t>
 <t id="50905">Improper Transport of Hazardous Materials, Smuggling, Corporate Espionage, Murder, Arms Trafficking</t>
 <t id="60901">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling</t>
 <t id="60902">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property</t>
 <t id="60903">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking</t>
 <t id="60904">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking, Murder</t>
 <t id="60905">Biohazardous Materials Smuggling, Destruction of Property, Drug Trafficking, Murder, Arms Trafficking</t>
</page>
<!-- Repair Ships Command (command only) (DrBullwinkle) -->
<!-- Requires Repair Laser from ASS-AP or other mod -->

<!-- Note: The following commands intentionally conflict with ASS-AP because they do exactly the same thing. -->
<page id="2008">
<t id="530">COMMAND_BW_REPAIR_SHIP</t>
<t id="531">COMMAND_BW_REPAIR_SHIP_SECTOR</t>
</page>
<page id="2010" title="Script Cmd Names (Long)" descr="This name appears in the menu.">
<t id="530">Repair Ship...</t>
<t id="531">Repair Ships in Sector...</t>
</page>
<page id="2011" title="Script Cmd Shorts" descr="Abbreviation">
<t id="530">Repair</t>
<t id="531">Rep.Sec</t>
</page>
<page id="2022" title="Command Info" descr="">
<t id="530">Command this ship to repair another ship.</t>
<t id="531">Command this ship to repair all damaged ships in sector.</t>
</page>
</language>
