<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<language id="49">
<page id="17" title="" descr="">
 <t id="16562">The Teladi M7 Raven-Class Heavy Assault Frigate is designed as a vessel suited to guarding gate network chokepoints from hostile sectors, and maintaining a greater presence across all-important trade lanes.\n\nIts heavy capital-class weapons, thick armor, and optimal shielding, more than make up for its relatively slow speed.\n\nDocking Capacity: 3 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="16572">A new favorite of the Teladi Company Space Fleet and Private Military Companies alike, the M1 Cormorant-Class Carrier was designed to be able to carry and maintain large numbers of fighter groups. \n\nOften acting as a mobile-base of operations due to its relatively slow speed, the Cormorant can provide its owners with a sector-wide fighter protection and still hold its own in capital-class engagements.\n\nDocking Capacity: 46 x Fighter Class; 4 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="16582">The M2+ Pteranodon-Class Battleship is the Teladi's answer to the increasing Xenon threat on its trade routes: a heavy battleship armed with a large arsenal of weapons, thick armour, and an impregnable shield array.\n\nDue to its size, the Pteranodon rivals the Split M2+ Taipan-Class Heavy Destroyer in terms of military might, and offers the Teladi Company a much-needed deterrence force against potential aggression from both the Xenon and other Commonwealth races alike.\n\nDocking Capacity: 4 x Fighters; 2 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="16602">The Proteus Attack Cruiser is a new addition to the Paranid Imperial Fleet, designed to bridge the gap between the destroyer and the frigate class. It is equipped with a number of turrets as well as an array of frontal weapon mounts, making this ship a force to be reckoned with. Docking space - 1 fighter class.</t>
 <t id="16642">The M6 Drake-Class Heavy Corvette is an evolution of the original M6 Dragon-Class Corvette and boasts excellent turret coverage and speed, making it an ideal anti-fighter vessel when escorting larger vessels.\n\nTaking inspiration from Paranid designs, the Drake epitomizes the Split's desire for power and speed in their vessels, turning what should be a slow support class into a vessel that can give most M3 and M4 fighters a run for their money in terms of both agility and interception ability.\n\nDue to these elements of the design, the Drake is quickly becoming popular with Split captains who started their careers as fighter pilots, allowing them to &quot;get up close and personal&quot; with enemies like they used to.\n\nDocking Capacity: None.</t>
 <t id="16652">The M7 Ocelot-Class Heavy Assault Frigate was developed in tandem with, and as a counterpart to, the M7 Tiger-Class Frigate, and has been designed to complement its older brother to be able to provide excellent escort capabilities for carriers and larger cruisers, or to patrol quieter sectors without additional support.\n\nWhile the Ocelot is slightly slower and less agile than the Tiger, it boasts much thicker hull armor plating, allowing it to out-last an enemy instead of attempting to out-gun it - although the Ocelot is capable of doing just that as well.\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="16662">Following the success of the Asp and Chimera, the Split Military approved the production of the M3 Cougar-Class Heavy Fighter - a new &quot;3rd Generation&quot; vessel designed for the pre-emptive protection of their borders from &quot;Insidious Boron Cultural Influence&quot;.\n\nIn this regard, the Cougar series was designed to maximize one of the two Split combat principles: overwhelming power and deadly speed \(often in large numbers, and accompanied by a chorus of weapons fire\).\n\nIn line with being designed as a ruthless fighter-killer and a general menance to Boron pilots everywhere, it is only available in Vanguard or Raider variants.</t>
 <t id="16672">The M2+ Taipan-Class Battleship is one of the biggest and most heavily armed vessels in service within the Commonwealth today, and a true testament to the Split's predatory nature. \n\nBoasting a large array of forward and broadside guns, the Taipan is capable of dealing with even the most formidable of threats without concern, projecting a formidable amount of military might in any sector it is assigned to.\n\nTaking cues from the M7 Wolf-Class Frigate, the Taipan also features integrated systems that are set out across the ship via the &quot;two-island&quot; principle, and equally distributes its phased-array systems over pyramidal deck-houses to accomplish the same improved survivability as the Wolf itself. \n\nThe aerials of these phased-array systems are distributed over the two pyramids, ensuring that the ship remains operational in case of severe damage, such as accidents or enemy action, and allowing them to keep station if needed when something breaks down and no immediate replacement is available.\n\nPrimarily designed to deal with Xenon threats, the Taipan also plays host to an impressive shield array, and holds enough hangar space to host a single wing of fighters as well as dedicated support ship.\n\nDocking Capacity: 5 x Fighter Class; 1 x M6/M8</t>
 <t id="16802">The end of the Terran Conflict and the reclamation of old sectors brought many improvements and innovations to Terran technology and military thinking. \n\nOne such innovation was the M3B Falchion-Class Strike Bomber - a hybrid Terran/ATF design created as a countermeasure against enemy carrier groups and AGI/Xenon hive ships.\n\nNamed for the Terran one-handed, single-edged sword of European origin, the Falchion is able to strike a foe much like its ancient namesake: hard, deep, and precise.</t>
 <t id="16812">The USC TM Macana-Class Military Transport is the Terran answer to the Commonwealth's own long-serving Military Transport ships. \n\nAble to dock up to eight fighters, the Macana excels at light-carrier support for larger vessels, or as a base of operations for expeditionary groups on long-range patrols.\n\nHowever, the Macana is not designed for combat situations, making it more suited to guide operations from a distance while its fighter-wing takes care of any hostiles it might encounter.\n\nDocking Capacity: 8 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="16842">Fresh out of the Phobos Dry-dock, the M3 &quot;Verdandi Sentinel&quot;-Class Heavy Fighter is one of the newest additions to the ATF Vanguard Squadrons. \n\nLike its predecessor the Thor, the Verdandi packs a heavy punch without sacrificing speed and manoeuvrability, while its innovative designs also permits it to conduct atmospheric operations.\n\nThe name &quot;Verdani&quot; is taken from one of the Norns of Norse mythology. She was one of the three who decide the fates of humans - much like the fighter than has adopted her name.</t>
 <t id="16872">Although the M2 Tyr-Class Destroyer represents the pinnacle of ATF technology and military might, the Terran Government determined that it was far too expensive a craft to operate in large numbers. \n\nThe M7 Kvasir-Class Heavy Assault Frigate provides a solution to this problem, condensing much of what made the Tyr a ship to be feared into a smaller frame and allowing the ATF to project their military might at a substantially lower cost without sacrificing much in the way of operative capability.\n\nArmed with an advanced arsenal of weapons as well as the most cutting edge technology the ATF has to offer, the Kvasir is one of the finest vessels in the Terran fleet.\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="16882">The M4 Hel-Class Advanced Interceptor is one the latest additions to the ATF fleet, designed to deliver firepower to the frontlines as quickly as possible and to stall an enemy until the rest of the fleet can arrive to finish the job. \n\nNamed for the entity in Norse mythology who presided over a realm of the same name where she received a portion of the dead, the Hel is also the first of the 6th Generation fighters to integrate broad wings for atmospheric operations.</t>
 <t id="16902">A new addition to the ATF fleet, the M5 Mani-Class Multirole Light Fighter was designed for heavy recon missions or light interception. \n\nCurrently one of the fastest ship of its size in the fleet, the Mani is employed as part of the fleets rapid respond fighters, although many details regarding its capabilities remain classified by the ATF.</t>
 <t id="16912">The ATF TM Lofn-Class Specialized Military Transport is able to carry a wing of six fighters.\n\nNamed for the goddess of Adultery and Forbidden Love in Norse mythology, much of the Lofn's capabilities remains as classified information.\n\nDocking Capacity: 6 x Fighters.</t>
 <t id="90000">{17,16741}</t>
 <t id="90001">The first of its kind, the TL+ Tepukei-Class Multi-Role Support Frigate is an advanced fleet tender and mobile operating platform that is quickly establishing itself as the new backbone of USC logistics, swiftly replacing the aging Mobile-Mining Base Ship in both economic and military operations throughout Terran space.\n\nWhile primarily used for strike-craft refuel and repair, the Tepukei is also adept as a capital-ship and station repair vessel due to its impressive repair capabilities, and as a economic-and-expansion support vessel due to its ability to deploy new stations in appropriate sectors.\n\nAt the heart of the Tepukei rests the USC's innovative Forward Operations and Maintenance \(FOAM\) system - a logistical counterpart to the Hayabusa M7's &quot;MODS&quot; array - that provides much of the vessels modular flexibility in terms of practicable service capabilities.\n\nWhile notably more expensive to produce than a conventional TL, the Tepukei TL+'s reinforced ablative armor, dynamic anti-breaching systems, and sweeping anti-fighter/frigate weapon systems, more than make up for the cost, allowing them to take part in battle and keep other ships alive as needed, instead of merely watching from the sidelines.\n\nThe motto of the Tepukei-class is &quot;Arrectis Auribus&quot; - &quot;With Ears Pricked Up&quot;* - and is indicative of the class's forward-looking design methodology.\n\nDocking Capacity: 23 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90002">{17,16731}</t>
 <t id="90003">Now considered a cornerstone of the Terran Fleet, the M7 Hayabusa-Class Heavy Assault Frigate was designed as a rival to the ATF M7 Aegir-Class Frigate that would fill the role of a militarized heavy frigate for USC operations.\n\nArmed with a built-in Modular Ordnance Delivery System \(MODS\), the Hayabusa is capable of mounting a flexible array of USC ordinance, allowing it to conduct many different operations depending on the situation.\n\nThe name &quot;Hayabusa&quot; is the Japanese word for the the Peregrine Falcon, a Terran bird-of-prey.\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90004">{17,16781}</t>
 <t id="90005">The M1+ Solaris-Class Heavy Carrier is a newly designed &quot;command and control&quot; capital ship that was designed as a potential future replacement for the aging Tokyo M1 Carrier.\n\nAlthough slower than the Tokyo, the Solaris is able to carry and deploy a larger number of fighters, making it potentially ideal for &quot;secure and control&quot; operations in sectors under threat of invasion, and to quickly bring order to chaos without the need of larger support vessels.\n\nHowever, the true effectiveness of the Solaris has yet to be determined, and this new M1 will have to do a lot of work to convince USC veterans that it is a suitable heir to the Tokyo's established legacy.\n\nDocking Capacity: 50 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90006">{17,16761}</t>
 <t id="90007">A lighter-weight ship used for evading Commonwealth naval blockades of jump gates and trade-lanes, the M7 Logich-Class Frigate is the USC's primary vessel for transporting military-grade cargo and marines to flashpoints both within and without Terran space as the reach of Earth's influence begins to extend its grasp.\n\nMissions assigned to the Logich tend to be quite risky since any blockading forces will often not hesitate to fire upon them. However, the potential profits from successful blockade runs often far exceed the danger, and thus the Logich is typically known for having some of the most talented crew members the USC can train.\n\nWhen not assigned to high-risk operations that require speed and subtlety, the Logich is often employed in general escort and anti-fighter roles, and has become a favourite of Terran Special Forces due to its flexibility and notable legacy.\n\nCompared to the older M7 Yokohama-Class Frigate, the Logich is slower, but bristles with a full array of flak turrets and reinforced ablative armour, allowing it take more of a beating from whatever it may encounter and making it ideal for expeditionary roles - especially those that are not as innocent as they seem.\n\nDocking Space: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90008">{17,16691} Type-{9,500}</t>
 <t id="90009">The M2 Tobosaku-Class \(A\) Light Destroyer is a new USC &quot;2nd Generation&quot; capital ship design that seeks to adopt all that has been learned in recent conflicts with both AGI and Commonwealth foes and package it into a modern vessel that is flexible enough to meet the demands of a new era of potential threats, while remaining solid enough to protect Earth's assets from within - rather than without.\n\nTo this end, it features many of the advanced systems that have found their way onto the M2+ Nagoya-Class Battleship, reproducing them in a manner that befits a swifter grade of destroyer that is better suited to escorting carriers and missile frigates than leading heavy assaults.\n\nDubbed the Tobosaku-A, it is also larger than its M7M counterpart - the Tobosaku-B - although shares many similarities in hull design and relative scale, though lacks of missile-strike capabilities of its &quot;little brother&quot;. However, the two are often seen in tandem all the same.\n\nThe name &quot;Tobosaku&quot; is derived from Japanese mythology. Tobosaku was a &quot;happy old prankster&quot; who stole three peaches from the garden of Seiobo - the &quot;Queen Mother of the West&quot; - and become immortal.\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90010">{17,16691} Type-{9,501}</t>
 <t id="90011">The M7M Tobosaku-Class \(B\) Torpedo Frigate is a new USC &quot;2nd Generation&quot; capital ship design that seeks to adopt all that has been learned in recent conflicts with both AGI and Commonwealth foes and package it into a modern vessel that is flexible enough to meet the demands of a new era of potential threats, while remaining solid enough to protect Earth's assets from within - rather than without.\n\nTo this end, it features many of the advanced systems that have found their way onto the M2+ Nagoya-Class Battleship, resulting in a missile-cruiser that has been equipped with multiple vertical launch tubes designed for destroying stations and enemy capital ships from range.\n\nDubbed the Tobosaku-B, it is also smaller than its M2 counterpart - the Tobosaku-A - although shares many similarities in hull design and relative scale with its &quot;big brother&quot;, and the two are often seen in tandem.\n\nThe name &quot;Tobosaku&quot; is derived from Japanese mythology. Tobosaku was a &quot;happy old prankster&quot; who stole three peaches from the garden of Seiobo - the &quot;Queen Mother of the West&quot; - and become immortal.\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90012">Longsword Mk2</t>
 <t id="90013">A recon and special ops vessel, fast and maneuverable for a ship of its class. A favorite of the USC special forces, the Longsword Mk2 is usually used to launch surgical strikes on space facilities or to deploy covert ops marines in boarding operations. Docking space - 1 fighter class.</t>
 <t id="90014">Longsword</t>
 <t id="90015">The Longsword class corvette was designed by the USC for deep reconnaissance. Docking space - 1 fighter class.</t>
 <t id="90016">{17,16831}</t>
 <t id="90017">Built on a modified chassis of the Logich, the USC M7 Morrigu-Class Carrier Frigate has smaller engine and weapon systems in order to accomodate a moderate internal docking bay. Its role in the USC fleet is to deploy fighter cover for deep space operations where a full carrier's slow speed would render it vulnerable.\n\nDocking Capacity: 15 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90018">{17,16701}</t>
 <t id="90019">The M4 Chikyu-Class Advanced Interceptor represents the next incarnation of USC fighter craft design and methodology, integrated with a superior engine design for increased speed and manoeuvrability in space operations. \n\nThe swept wing design also allows this craft to operate with excellent manoeuvrability in atmospheric flights.\n\nIn the Japanese language of Earth, &quot;Chikyu&quot; is the name of the Terran homeworld.</t>
 <t id="90020">Phalanx \(SOWP\)</t>
 <t id="90021">The Phalanx-Class Light Orbital Weapons Platform \(OWP\) is a stationary defense platform armed with two turrets, often deployed to defend an area of strategic importance, and able to act as a small fire-base for local forces.\n\nIt was named after a formation of infantry carrying overlapping shields and long spears, developed by Philip II of Macedon and used by Alexander the Great.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90022">Longinus \(MOWP\)</t>
 <t id="90023">The Longinus-Class Medium Orbital Weapons Platform \(OWP\) is a stationary defense platform armed with numerous turrets, often deployed to defend an area of strategic importance, and is able to direct regional force and guide local traffic.\n\nIt is named after a Roman soldier in Terran theological scripture.\n\nDocking Capacity: None.</t>
 <t id="90024">Gungnir \(LOWP\)</t>
 <t id="90025">The Gungnir-Class Large Orbital Weapons Platform \(OWP\) is a stationary defense platform armed with numerous turrets, often deployed to defend an area of strategic importance, and is able to act as a base of operations for a number of fighter squadrons.\n\nIn Terran Norse mythology, Gungnir \(Old Norse &quot;unswaying one&quot;\) was Odin's magical spear; it always hit its mark and alway killed its prey.\n\nDocking Capacity: 25 x Fighters.</t>
 <t id="90026">{17,12861}</t>
 <t id="90027">The M2+ Nagoya-Class Heavy Battleship stands as a hallmark of USC engineering capability and military might, developed and equipped with the biggest guns and most sophisticated systems that the Terran people have to offer.\n\nDesigned in response to intelligence that the Split and Teladi were both constructing their own improved M2-class vessels, and unwilling to rely on the ATF for support, the Nagoya borrows from all the lessons learned from the Tyr while building upon them with new innovations and design ethics.\n\nTo this end, the Nagoya has class-leading turret armaments which more than make up for its general lack of speed; and combined with a dedicated wing of fighters, there is often little left of an enemy to finish off when its escorts finally come into range.\n\nThe battleship is named after the Japanese city of the same name, which was the capital of Aichi Prefecture and the principal city of the Nobi plain in the early 21st Century.\n\nDocking Capacity: 6 x Fighters.</t>
 <t id="90028">{17,16821}</t>
 <t id="90029">The TP Setanta-Class Military Personnel Transporter was designed to be a multi-purpose gunship and troop carrier for general boarding operations and the assault and capture of hostile vessels in Terran space that need to be taken intact.\n\nThe name &quot;Setanta&quot; is derived from the Irish mythological figure Cuchulainn, who was named Setanta as a child, and adopted the name Cuchulainn \(&quot;Hound of Culain&quot;\) after becoming a knight of the Red Branch.\n\nDocking Capacity: None.</t>
 <t id="90034">{17,16791}</t>
 <t id="90035">The M6CS Shamshir-Class Littoral Combat Ship is a fortified refit of the older M6 Katana-Class Corvette, designed to provide the USC with a lightly-armed warship that is capable of projecting heavier patrol and convoy escort support power than its older cousin.\n\nAlthough similar to a corvette in many ways, the Shamshir's larger hull permits space for mission modules to be installed as USC Operations deems fit, allowing them to undertake tasks formerly assigned to specialist classes such as minesweepers, as well as easily handle general escort missions like normal corvettes, albeit with added capability.\n\nIn terms of fire-power, the Shamshir is armed with four bow-mounted hardpoints capable of supporting corvette-grade weaponry, as well as a number of anti-fighter mounts that are spread across the hull in a formation that offers impressive coverage across a wide area of space, making it ideally suited for use against strike-craft when assigned as an escort to a carrier vessel or group.\n\nIn Terran history, the &quot;Shamshir&quot; was a type of Persian sabre with a curve that was considered somewhat radical for a sword, which often measured between five- to fifteen-degrees from tip to tip. In many ways, the Shamshir-class maintains the somewhat radial nature of its namesake, and many would agree that its name is well suited to the role that this vessel plays within the modern USC fleet.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90036">{17,10021} {17,10871}</t>
 <t id="90037">{17,10872}</t>
 <t id="90038">{17,16441}</t>
 <t id="90039">The M3 Excalibur-Class is a tri-engine, canard-delta wing, advanced multi-role combat fighter designed as the USC's answer to the ATF Verdani.\n\nThough similar to the M3 Scimitar in design and weapon capacity, the Excalibur incorporates a new generation of lighter-weight polymer construction for its internal systems, allowing it to achieve high-levels of agility in both deep space and atmospheric conditions. \n\nA relaxed-stability design and quadruplex digital fly-by-wire control systems provide artificial stability to further enhance the vessel's innate agility while compensate for the inherent instability that arises when the Excalibur is under the effects of gravitational stresses.\n\nWhile it is unlikely to replace the Scimitar as the USC's primary strike fighter, the Excalibur is never-the-less making a name for itself within certain pilot circles and cliques, and there are rumours that specialist &quot;elite&quot; squadrons of these fighters have been have been assembled in recent mazuras.</t>
 <t id="90050">{17,16551}</t>
 <t id="90051">The M7 Geochen-Class Light Patrol Frigate is a support vessel that has been mass produced by the Teladi Company to provide strong anti-fighter cover along trade routes.\n\nIt can mount a large selection of anti-fighter weaponry and has well-rounded turret coverage making it a prime resource against Pirate and Yaki raiders.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90060">{17,16851}</t>
 <t id="90061">The M7 Snotra-Class Fast Patrol Frigate is a new addition to the ranks of the AGI Task Force, and has been designed as an attempt to create an alternative to the more-expensive M7 Aegir for general border-patrol operations.\n\nAlthough not as heavily armed as its forerunner, the Snotra follows the same design principles as the M7 Aomori-class Patrol Frigate which has resulted in a patrol vessel that is as fast, flexible, and capable of mounting anti-fighter and anti-frigate loadouts as the situation requires.\n\nIn Terran Norse mythology, &quot;Snotra&quot; is a goddess associated with wisdom, and is cited as being the thirteenth of the sixteen Asynjur (or goddesses), who &quot;should be seen as a female protective goddess&quot; and is &quot;wise and courtly&quot;.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90102">{17,12881}</t>
 <t id="90103">The M7C Tern-Class Light Carrier is a vessel that is as popular among private contractors and mercenary groups as it is with the Teladi Company itself.\n\nArmed with advanced anti-fighter weaponry and equipped with heavy hull plating like other Teladi designs, the Tern is often tasked with maintenance and repairs of fighters and can also be seen sweeping through wrecks after a battle looking for anything salvageable.\n\n Its six external docking ports also make this vessel an ideal mobile trading base.\n\nDocking Capacity: 14 x Fighter Class; 6 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="90104">{17,6471}</t>
 <t id="90105">The M7 Talon-Class Light Frigate designed to give the Teladi Military a faster capital ship for rapid-response and policing duties.\n\nThe Talon boasts a speed that is comparable with anti-fighter frigates but features a much heavier array of weapons, albeit at the expense of shielding.\n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class</t>
 <t id="90112">{17,16541}</t>
 <t id="90113">The M3 Emeus-Class Multi-Role Combat Interceptor is a recent Teladi vessel that shares many of the methodologies and technological progressions that were incorporated into the design of the M5 Advanced Kestrel-Class Scout.\n\nAn advanced hybrid of the M3 Kea and the M3 Falcon, the Emeus is considered to be an all-environment capable, heavy class, long-range space-superiority fighter which can also act as a strike fighter aircraft. \n\nRumoured to have been somewhat inspired by modern Terran fighter designs, the Hawk is tailor-made for Teladi specifications and integrates Teladi systems and avionics as well as Paranid and Split subsystems under strict allowances of the Profit Guild.\n\nCompared to other vessels in its class, the Emeus sacrifices a good portion of cargo space for a higher engine output while still maintaining the Teladi's core emphasis on armour and shields, making it the fastest Teladi M3 to date and a primary choice as a modern carrier-based heavy interceptor in core sectors.\n\nWhile currently under limited active service within Teladi space, it is thought that the Teladi Company have plans to have an operational fleet of Hawks within the next few jazuras, with expectations to have it form the backbone of the Teladi fleet into the near future and beyond.</t>
 <t id="90150">{17,16481} {17,10011}</t>
 <t id="90151">The Quasar is a well armed troop transporter used by the Argon military to transport marines for boarding operations and planetary assaults.</t>
 <t id="90152">{17,16611}</t>
 <t id="90153">The M7 Cyclops-Class Support Cruiser is the newest addition to the Argon Federal Navy, designed as a weapons-platform that is similar in scope to the M2 Titan-Class Destroyer, but at a much lower cost of production.\n\nAs suited to general rear-guard duties as it is to front-line escort roles, the Cyclops is in its element when assigned to patrol against Xenon and Khaak threats, and has also been designed to respond to any emergent threats from the Paranid Empire should they arise.\n\nAlthough it features with a fewer number of guns when compared to other ships of its class, the Cyclops should not be underestimated. Its left and right turret mounts were designed with an inter-link system to provide an overlapping field of fire, making the area in front of the Cyclops a deadly kill zone. \n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90200">{17,16641}</t>
 <t id="90201">The Drake is a complete redesigned of the original Dragon. Unlike previous Split M6, this one is equipped with well rounded turret coverage allowing it to act as an anti-fighter gunboat when escorting larger ships. Docking space - 1 fighter class.</t>
 <t id="90202">{17,16651}</t>
 <t id="90203">After it was decided that the M7 Tiger was too cumbersome a design to manoeuvre, Split military drew up plans for the Ocelot, a slightly smaller but more aggressive ship of the line. Unlike the Tiger, the Ocelot has no main guns and relies entirely on its frontal and broadside turrets. Docking space - 2 fighter class.</t>
 <t id="90204">{17,16661}</t>
 <t id="90205">Following the success of the Asp and Chimera, the Split military approved the production of the M3 Cougar series a new 3rd generation heavy fighter for the pre-emptive protection of their borders from the Boron menace. The Cougar series was designed to maximize one of the two Split combat principle; attack power and speed. It is only available in the Vanguard or Raider Variant.</t>
 <t id="90206">{17,16671}</t>
 <t id="90207">An incarnation of the Split predatory nature, the Taipan is bigger and more heavily armed than most commonwealth battleships currently in service. Boasting a large array of forward and broadside turrets, it can handle even the most formidable, unfortunately it suffers from the same design oversight as all Split ships. Docking space - 8 fighter class, 2 M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="90208">Wolf</t>
 <t id="90209">The M7 Wolf-Class Multi-Role Frigate is the result of continuous development in Split frigate chassis research, aimed primarily towards the destruction of larger Kha'ak vessels and assets, though just as well suited to conventional operations as well.\n\nAn evolution of the M7 Tiger and the M7 Ocelot, and designed in tandem with the Argon M7 Griffon-Class for Final Fury Operations, the Wolf is equipped with a large number of anti-fighter and anti-corvette weaponry, coupled with a high-performance engine-cluster array that makes for a formidable Split warship.\n\nTo enhance survivability of the Wolf, important systems are laid out in the &quot;two-island&quot; principle. This is also visible in the superstructures, which are split in two larger pyramidal deck-houses. \n\nThe aerials of the phased-array systems are distributed over the two pyramids, ensuring that the ship remains operational in case of severe damage, such as accidents or enemy action, and allowing them to keep station if needed when something breaks down and no immediate replacement is available.\n\nAs with most Split warships, the Wolf also possesses a sizeable crew, and can act for weeks on end by itself unsupported without losing any of its battle-readiness or combat efficiency. \n\nWhen an enemy charges straight on towards a Wolf, they are not likely to live to regret it.\n\nDocking Capacity:2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90210">{17,10281}</t>
 <t id="90211">The M2 Krait-Class Light-Destroyer is Family Rhyk's answer to the M2+ Taipan-class Battleship \(which was developed by the Great Family Rhonkar\).\n\nIntended as a highly-mobile weapons platform that is able to deliver a fearsome array of firepower without sacrificing speed and manoeuvrability, the Krait is perhaps the finest example of Split military methodology: shoot them before they can shoot you. \n\nTo that end, while boasting considerable advances in high-end velocity and agility that rivals that of even the OTAS M2 Boreas-class Light-Destroyer, the Krait suffers from the same design flaw that many Split vessels harbour and has relatively weaker shields than most comparable Commonwealth cruisers.\n\nHowever, the Krait does boast a few other remarkable features all the same: its primary weapons system consists of dual AMAC 10 &quot;Venom-class&quot; Quad-Mount Turrets on the bow of the hull in addition to the dual AMAC 6 &quot;Predator-class&quot; Tri-Mount turrets along its broadsides, resulting in an accumulated fire-power equivalent to that of larger M2 Python-class Destroyer. \n\nThe Krait also features a number of systems that are notable for their innovation as well, such as its low-LIDAR profile, fully integrated power system, hardware-independent total ship computing environment infrastructure, and automated fire-fighting and isolation systems.\n\nIt also requires a substantially smaller crew capacity to operate than other Split M2s and maintains the hard-angle hull design of all Split vessels, but does not feature the system level of system/segment redundancy that larger warships and some Split M7s have built into their design.\n\nBe that as it may, the Krait is tough, durable, aggressive, and impressive enough that whatever the intentions of Family Rhyk were in building it, it has since gained the notice of Family Rhonkar has been adopted into wider service across all of Split space. \n\nDocking Capacity: 2 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90212">{17,16451}</t>
 <t id="90213">The M1 Lotan-Class Heavy Carrier is a next-generation evolution of the older M1 Raptor-Class Carrier, designed in Rhonkar's Trial in part from research recovered during the Terran Conflict and from advances made during preparations for Operation Final Fury.\n\nAlthough larger and slightly slower than the M1 Raptor, the Lotan is armed with a number of AMAC 6 &quot;Predator&quot; tri-mounted turrets on the front and broadsides of the ship, allowing this carrier to do more than hold its own in a fight.\n\nEnhanced CATOBAR and STOVL support systems add further credence to the Lotan's intended role within the fleets of the Great Family Rhonkar and beyond.\n\nThe name &quot;Lotan&quot; derives from Terran mythology. Lotan was a seven-headed dragon of Ugaritic myth, representing the mass destruction of floods, oceans, and winter. \n\nThat the Split gave a carrier capable of wreaking considerable havoc even before launching a single fighter wing speaks volumes about how apt the Lotan's name really is.\n\nDocking Capacity: 25 x Fighter Class; 3 x M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="90250">{17,16601}</t>
 <t id="90251">The Proteus Attack Cruiser is a new addition to the Paranid Imperial Fleet, designed to bridge the gap between the destroyer and the frigate class. It is equipped with a number of turrets as well as an array of frontal weapon mounts, making this ship a force to be reckoned with. Docking space - 1 fighter class.</t>
 <t id="90252">{17,16631}</t>
 <t id="90253">Ariadne description</t>
 <t id="90254">{17,16591}</t>
 <t id="90255">The M3 Patroclus-Class Strike Fighter is the first of a new generation of Paranid fighter-craft intended as a counter-measure against USC and ATF fighters, rather than against their traditional foe of the Argon Federation. \n\nTo this end, the Patroclus shares more than a little in common with the USC's M3 Excalibur-class fighter in both technological and - coincidentally - air-frame design, marking it as a heavy multi-role fighter that is well suited to reconnaissance, forward control, and electronic warfare, though is especially equipped for fighter interdiction.\n\nNeither the USC nor the Commonwealth have yet been able to determine the exact details on the inner workings of these fighters, nor have there been many reasonable speculations as to why the Paranid Empire have geared the design of the Patroclus towards the intended interdiction of Terran strike-craft. \n\nHowever, rumours persist that the Cardinal of the Second Duchy has been related to the project, and there are even suggestions that the Paranid Secret Service have had a hand making sure the Patroclus saw the light of day. \n\nWhether such rumours have any truth to them remains to be seen...\n\nIn Terran Greek mythology, &quot;Patroclus&quot; was the King of Opus, and was Achilles's beloved comrade and brother-in-arms.</t>
 <t id="90350">{9,502}</t>
 <t id="90351">The Xenon &quot;C&quot; appears to be a much larger and heavier version of the Q - roughly the size of a Commonwealth M7 in relative scope.\n\nInitial reports indicate that the &quot;C&quot; is, however, faster and more heavily armored than an average Commonwealth cruiser and sports heavy anti-capital weaponry upon its frontal turrets. \n\nIn combat, the &quot;C&quot; has been seen to adopt heavy flanking tactics, often hunting down and stalling carriers and support vessels while larger Xenon capital ships engage heavier combat units.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90352">{9,525}</t>
 <t id="90353">Recently sighted leading Xenon incursion fleets into eastern Commonwealth space, the &quot;Z&quot; is believed to be a command and control vessel for the greater Xenon fleet, although its actual purpose is still as-yet unknown. \n\nPilots and ship captains are advised to avoid this vessel at all costs.\n\nDocking Capacity: 20 x Fighter Class.\n\n</t>
 <t id="90354">{9,506}</t>
 <t id="90355">The &quot;G&quot; is a Xenon Missile Frigate that is capable of deploying an advanced array of warheads against Commonwealth assets and is believe to function as the Xenon's long-range strike vessel.\n\nEven with its slow speed and light armor, these ships present an imminent danger to all stations and trade routes within proximity of Xenon space.\n\nDocking Capacity: 1 x Fighter Class.</t>
 <t id="90400">Repair Drone</t>
 <t id="90401">The Repair Drone is a remote guided robotics unit used to conduct field repairs.</t>
 <t id="90450">{17,10021} {17,4051}</t>
 <t id="90451">This variant of the Kha'ak M5 Scout - codenamed &quot;Lilith&quot; by Sector M-148 - appears to fulfil a forward-recon role within the Hive's operational structure, often seen arriving mizuras before a main Kha'ak invasion fleet jumps into a sector. \n\nRegional Commanders are advised to consider sightings of this vessel to be a prelude to attack and respond accordingly.</t>
 <t id="90452">{17,10021} {17,4041}</t>
 <t id="90453">This variant of the Kha'ak M4 Interceptor - codenamed &quot;Ifrit&quot; by Sector M-148- is believed to be a recent additional to the Kha'ak Hive that is making more frequent appearances since preparations for Operation Final Fury began. \n\nSuspected to be an assault-fighter, in it theorized that the Kha'ak have developed this type of ship in direct response to recent Commonwealth probes into Kha'ak space.</t>
 <t id="90454">{17,10021} {17,4031}</t>
 <t id="90455">This variant of the Kha'ak M3 Fighter - codenamed &quot;Ahriman&quot; by Sector M-148 - has been recently sighted in limited numbers alongside appearances of the newer Kha'ak M4 Interceptors.\n\nIt is theorized that these vessels may be piloted by Kha'ak &quot;Overseers&quot; who &quot;possess&quot; the individual drones of a local cluster to &quot;boost&quot; the will of the Hive in regions of space where the Kha'ak have a weaker influence.\n\nIt is equally posited that these &quot;Overseers&quot; are themselves being possessed by an even greater Hive power, although this remains subjective theory with little evidence to back it up.</t>
 <t id="90456">{17,80326}</t>
 <t id="90457">The Kha'ak TM - codenamed &quot;Incubus&quot; by Sector M-148- is believed to be a recent addition to the Kha'ak Hive Fleet, and apparently demonstrates a level of adaptive reasoning that has not been seen before. \n\nIt is believed that the Kha'ak's TM has been developed as a response to encounters with Commonwealth TMs - and perhaps even Xenon TMs.\n\nThe vessel itself appears to be a small &quot;swarm&quot; carrier capable of carrying up to 12 Kha'ak fighters in some form of shielded stasis field - perhaps as an advancement of the conventional &quot;Cluster&quot;.\n\nThe &quot;core&quot; ship does not appear to be at all armed, but pilots are advised to remain alert as the danger of being overwhelmed by a &quot;drone swarm&quot; is very real.\n\nDocking Capacity: 12 x Kha'ak Drones.</t>
 <t id="90458">Frigate</t>
 <t id="90459">The Kha'ak M7 Frigate - codenamed &quot;Rakshasa&quot; by Sector M-148 - represents a new threat to Commonwealth space and shipping lanes. \n\nThe ship appears to be an M7-sized vessel equipped with an array of Kha'ak beam emitters and as-yet unverified heavy anti-capital ship class weapons.\n\nExtreme caution is advised.</t>
 <t id="90460">{17,10021} {17,4021}</t>
 <t id="90461">The Kha'ak M2+ Advanced Destroyer - codenamed "Asura" by Sector M-148 - is a new and intimidating addition to the Kha'ak scourge.\n\nNamed after the sinful and materialistic group of power-seeking deities from Terran Hindu mythology, the Asura is considered to be the theoretical pinnacle of Kha'ak evolutionary conversion, and a dismaying prospect for anyone who thought they had seen the worse that the Kha'ak have to offer.\n\nHowever, even with the potential of such a great threat lingering upon the minds of those who have engaged the Kha'ak in combat, there are many within the Commonwealth who believe this vessel is little more than a myth; that it is a revenant conjured up by pirates and brigands to scare merchants and vulnerable civilians into hiring questionable entities as escort, or as a tool created to distract from the real political issues that plague the universe.\n\nWhatever the case, the truth behind the reality of the Kha'ak M2+ is likely one that will be written in blood and fire as words so bold and terrible that very few will be left who can doubt that it stalks the trade-lanes...</t>
 <t id="90462">{17,10021} {17,4011}</t>
 <t id="90463">The Kha'ak M1+ Advanced Carrier - codenamed "Tiamat" by Sector M-148 - has only been encountered by a handful of craft on deep space reconnaisance. Only two lived to report back fully on what they enountered.\n\nAlthough sketchy, pilots have reported a fearsome array of offensive weapons with docking space for several wings of the new advanced Kha'ak fighters. It is recommended to avoid contact at all costs.</t>
 <t id="90464">{17,10021} {17,10901}</t>
 <t id="90465">The Kha'ak M6M Advanced Corvette - codenamed "Tannin" by Sector M-148 - is a new ship that has recently been employed by the Kha'ak in engagements with deep space Paranid patrols. With the mining of Nvidium still going on in some Paranid sectors, it is thought the Kha'ak have developed this new ship to enable them to quickly respond and eliminate any threat to their home.\n\nThis new corvette sized ship is extremely well armed, with a decent top speed. Employed in groups, they can easily take down a frigate and even threaten a destroyer.</t>
 <t id="90466">{17,16511}</t>
 <t id="90467">A recent addition to the Boron Navy, the Megalodon heavy destroyer boasts an integration of cutting edge technology accumulated over decades of collaborated research with Argon Military scientists. Utilising the new Fangtooth MkIV targeting system, alongside a heavy array of weapon loadouts, the Megalodon is able to deliver heavy ordinance with unrivalled precision, minimizing the possibility of collateral damage in combat.\n\nCurrently the most advanced Boron warship brought into service by the Boron Royal Navy, the Megalodon, although limited in numbers, stands as force of deterrence against an ever present threat of a Split invasion.\n\nDocking space - 5 fighter class, 1 M6/M8/TP/TS.</t>
 <t id="90500">Orbital Freight Dock</t>
 <t id="90501">This dock provides a resource drop-off and storage point for nearby stations and planets.</t>
 <t id="90502">Orbital Shipyard</t>
 <t id="90503">This space dock facilitates the construction and maintainance of all fleet ships. The shipyard can conduct repairs, recycling, reverse-engineering and ship construction at a faster rate and at a lower cost compared to a HQ station.</t>
 <t id="90504">Asteroid Base</t>
 <t id="90505">Often built out of husks of a mining outpost, an Asteroid Base can act as a stagging base well hidden in the cover of an asteroid field and often used to resupply ships passing through the sector. This base can conduct repairs or recycle salvaged ships.</t>
 <t id="90510">Communications Facility</t>
 <t id="90511"></t>
</page>
</language>
