<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<language id="07">
<page id="7" title="Boardcomp. Sectornames" descr="Names of all sectors (spoken by Boardcomputer)" voice="yes">
 <t id="1020108">{1000,140} {17,4061}</t>
 <t id="1020113">{7,30052}</t>
 <t id="1020115">{17,5581}</t>
 <t id="1020116">{17,6211}</t>
 <t id="1020117">{7,1020000} 16 - 0</t>
 <t id="1020119">{7,1020000} 18 - 10</t>
 <t id="1020318">{7,1023008}</t>
 <t id="1020320">{17,16501}</t>
 <t id="1020411">{1000,120} {17,16921}</t>
 <t id="1020420">{1000,1054} {17,10002}</t>
 <t id="1020508">{17,6291}</t>
 <t id="1020509">{17,6301}</t>
 <t id="1020516">{1000,1033} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="1020520">{7,30035}</t>
 <t id="1020608">{17,13131} {1000,40005}</t>
 <t id="1020609">{17,6311}</t>
 <t id="1020610">{7,30040}</t>
 <t id="1020613">{13,1339}</t>
 <t id="1020618">{1000,1032}</t>
 <t id="1020621">{12,111} {12,104}</t>
 <t id="1020710">{17,5501}</t>
 <t id="1020711">{17,5591}</t>
 <t id="1020717">{7,1023000}</t>
 <t id="1020718">{1000,1011}</t>
 <t id="1020719">{1000,1096} {17,4411}</t>
 <t id="1020810">{1000,1014} {1000,20019}</t>
 <t id="1020813">{1000,1012} {1000,40005}</t>
 <t id="1020815">{12,106} {12,122}</t>
 <t id="1020903">{1000,1040}' {12,121}</t>
 <t id="1020905">{1000,106} {1000,40005} {1951,340111}{1951,340114}{1951,340107}</t>
 <t id="1020909">{7,20000}</t>
 <t id="1020913">{17,3831}</t>
 <t id="1020921">{1000,60008} {17,3731}</t>
 <t id="1021011">{12,113}</t>
 <t id="1021019">{17,16881}l {17,80138}</t>
 <t id="1021102">{17,16621}</t>
 <t id="1021103">{1000,1051}</t>
 <t id="1021105">{7,30050}</t>
 <t id="1021106">{17,6201}</t>
 <t id="1021109">{17,6351}</t>
 <t id="1021119">{13,2101}</t>
 <t id="1021201">{17,16771}</t>
 <t id="1021206">{17,6221}</t>
 <t id="1021219">{17,6153} {13,56}</t>
 <t id="1021301">{17,5511}</t>
 <t id="1021302">{1000,1020} {17,4923}</t>
 <t id="1021308">{1000,1043} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="1021320">{1000,1013} {17,6471}</t>
 <t id="1021408">{7,30021}</t>
 <t id="1021420">{1000,1050}</t>
 <t id="1021501">{1000,1023} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="1021504">{1000,1024}</t>
 <t id="1021505">{17,5521}</t>
 <t id="1021506">{1000,138}' {17,16531}</t>
 <t id="1021508">{1000,106} {1000,40005} {1951,340108}{1951,340114}{1951,340111}</t>
 <t id="1021520">{12,118} {12,117}</t>
 <t id="1021602">{1000,1097}' {12,103}</t>
 <t id="1021604">{7,1020000} 3 - 15</t>
 <t id="1021605">{7,1020000} 4 - 15</t>
 <t id="1021606">{12,105} {12,116}</t>
 <t id="1021607">{7,1020000} 6 - 15</t>
 <t id="1021608">{7,1020000} 7 - 15</t>
 <t id="1021612">{7,20005}</t>
 <t id="1021613">{17,6331}</t>
 <t id="1021614">{1000,1020} {17,10001}</t>
 <t id="1021706">{7,20002}</t>
 <t id="1021708">{7,1020000} 7 - 16</t>
 <t id="1021711">{1000,147} {17,6161}</t>
 <t id="1021714">{1000,106} {1000,40005} {1951,340108}{1951,340111}{1951,340114}</t>
 <t id="1021719">{7,1020000} 18 - 16</t>
 <t id="1023008">Spires of Illusion</t>
 <t id="1021924"> </t>
 <t id="1020124"> </t>
 <t id="1020224"> </t>
 <t id="1020324"> </t>
 <t id="1020424"> </t>
 <t id="1020524"> </t>
 <t id="1020624"> </t>
 <t id="1020724"> </t>
 <t id="1020824"> </t>
 <t id="1020924"> </t>
 <t id="1021024"> </t>
 <t id="1021124"> </t>
 <t id="1021224"> </t>
 <t id="1021324"> </t>
 <t id="1021424"> </t>
 <t id="1021524"> </t>
 <t id="1021624"> </t>
 <t id="1021724"> </t>
 <t id="1021824"> </t>
 <t id="1020123"> </t>
 <t id="1020223"> </t>
 <t id="1020323"> </t>
 <t id="1020423"> </t>
 <t id="1020523"> </t>
 <t id="1020623"> </t>
 <t id="1020723"> </t>
 <t id="1020823"> </t>
 <t id="1020923"> </t>
 <t id="1021023"> </t>
 <t id="1021123"> </t>
 <t id="1021223"> </t>
 <t id="1021323"> </t>
 <t id="1021423"> </t>
 <t id="1021523"> </t>
 <t id="1021623"> </t>
 <t id="1021723"> </t>
 <t id="1021823"> </t>
</page>
<page id="12" title="Boardcomp. greek" descr="Spoken greek letters" voice="yes">
 <t id="100">Alpha</t>
 <t id="101">Beta</t>
 <t id="102">Gamma</t>
 <t id="103">Delta</t>
 <t id="104">Epsilon</t>
 <t id="105">Zeta</t>
 <t id="106">Eta</t>
 <t id="107">Theta</t>
 <t id="108">Iota</t>
 <t id="109">Kappa</t>
 <t id="110">Lambda</t>
 <t id="111">Mu</t>
 <t id="112">Nu</t>
 <t id="113">Xi</t>
 <t id="114">Omicron</t>
 <t id="115">Pi</t>
 <t id="116">Rho</t>
 <t id="117">Sigma</t>
 <t id="118">Tau</t>
 <t id="119">Upsilon</t>
 <t id="120">Phi</t>
 <t id="121">Chi</t>
 <t id="122">Psi</t>
 <t id="123">Omega</t>
 <t id="124">Omega</t>
 <t id="501">{9,518}(S)</t>
 <t id="502">{9,512}(M)</t>
 <t id="503">{9,511}(L)</t>
 <t id="504">{9,523}{9,511}(XL)</t>
 <t id="505">{9,523}{9,523}{9,511}(XXL)</t>
</page>
<page id="13" title="Boardcomp. Misc" descr="Various fragments spoken by shipboard comp. voice" voice="yes">
 <t id="56">Denied</t>
 <t id="1339">Credits Received</t>
 <t id="2101">Transaction Denied</t>
</page>
<page id="17" title="Boardcomp. objects" descr="Quad line groups for ware factory pairs or twins (spoken by Boardcomputer)" voice="yes">
 <t id="75000">{1000,122} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="75001">Seperate from AGI Headquarters, AGI Task Force Command is responsible for all fleet operations and logistics within the Sol System, as well as taking assignment of all extra-solar missions and action that may be required within Commonwealth space.</t>
 <t id="75002">{1000,122} {1000,20010}</t>
 <t id="75003">The AGI Task Force Flight School is a central hub of learning and discipline for pilots who have risen up through the ranks of the United Space Command and have caught the attention of the AGI Task Force. Pilots stationed at this airbase are instructed in how to handle the advanced fighters and ships of the ATF, as well as tactics and strategy to counter the ever-present AGI threat.</t>
 <t id="75004">{1000,122} {1000,50202}</t>
 <t id="75005">AGI Task Force Station Defense ensure that ATF Forseti remains a highly secure installation and military starbase.</t>
 <t id="75006">{1000,119} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="75007">The Yaki Shipyard provides fleet construction and logistics support for the growing Yaki Flotilla and ensures that they will continually return to the fight no matter how great the victory nor how severe the loss.</t>
 <t id="75008">{1000,119} {1000,40011} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="75009">Yaki Flotilla Command is the nerve center of all Yaki operations within the universe. While the shell of the station is that of a Paranid Trading Dock, the internals have been entirely stipped of Paranid influence and converted to suit the Yaki's needs and requirements.</t>
 <t id="75010">{1000,119} {1000,40010} {1000,40007}</t>
 <t id="75011">Yaki Battle Group Command is a converted Paranid Trading Station that serves as a regional base of operations for supporting and coordinating Yaki operations in the local area. It has also been established to provide additional avenues of commerce and provisions for freelancers and privateers working for the Yaki cause.</t>
 <t id="75020">{1000,118} {1000,30003}</t>
 <t id="75021">Terran Border Control handles all intended transit and immigration to and from Terran Space by Commonwealth travellers and visitors.</t>
 <t id="75022">{1000,122} {1000,30000} {1000,30002}</t>
 <t id="75023">The AGI Task Force Military Police are a section of the AGI military who are solely responsible for policing the armed forces and ensuring that their conduct meets the high standards of Terran protocol.</t>
 <t id="75024">{1000,123} {1000, 30000} {1000,30002}</t>
 <t id="75025">The USC Military Police are a section of the USC who are solely responsible for policing the armed forces and ensuring that their conduct meets the high standards of Terran protocol.</t>
 <t id="75026">{1000,108} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="75027">The Pirate Shipyard provides the means and resources by which the many pirate clans and factions can continue to build and develop their loose coalition of ships and corsairs, as well as providing the tools to dismantle any vessels that they have captured to be used to further the flotilla's strength.</t>
 <t id="75028">{1000,137} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="75029">Duke's Shipyard is a well-funded and well-organized operation that constructs and sells vessels to the pirate factions to their desired specifications and requirements.</t>
 <t id="75030">{1000,137} {1000,10006}</t>
 <t id="75031">Duke's Scrap Iron Merchant is less an actual salvage yard than a front for the somewhat illicit equipment-providing activities that take place upon this station. Though to have actually been installed an funded by the Paranid Government itself, the "front" is required to ensure that the tendrils of corruption can never be traced between The Duke and his many contacts within Paranid power.</t>
 <t id="75032">{1000,122} {1000,30014}</t>
 <t id="75033">AGI Task Force Disaster Control remains on-station to provide logistics and humaniatarian relief in the event of disasters within Terran space - be they natural or otherwise.</t>
 <t id="75034">{1000,122} {1000,20032}</t>
 <t id="75035">The AGI Task Force Technical Emergency Service stands ready to offer technical support to any stricken vessel within Terran space that requires immidiate assistance for emergencies that go beyond the scope of what local patrols can offer.</t>
 <t id="75536">{1000,109} {17,16041}</t>
 <t id="75537">Goner Shipyard</t>
 <t id="75538">{1000,122} {1000,30005}</t>
 <t id="75539">The AGI Task Force Intelligence Service is the intelligence agency of the AGI Task Force, reporting to the Director of Solar Intelligence, responsible for providing national security intelligence assessment to senior Terran policymakers. The ATFIS also engages in covert activities at the request of the President of Earth.</t>
</page>
<page id="19" title="Sectordescription" descr="Long descriptions of all sectors">
 <t id="1030108">At the furthest edges of the Solar System, beyond the reach of both the Oort Cloud and the McCallum Relay, sleeps a part of Earth's history that the Terran people would rather forget about than remember. \n\nIt is here, in the rocky fringes of Terran space, that Earth's first functional Jump Gate was located; and it was here that Earth suffered its first retreat from the AGI forces, and vowed never to do so again.\n\nHowever, among the broken remnants of the past and the beyond the sundered remnants of that first historic departure from the Sol System, it is said that there are even more secrets to be found than merely lost legacies and lives; a secret that the United Space Command would rather the Terran people were kept... in the dark... about.\n\nThe lack of sufficient lighting in this corner of the Solar System coupled with the various navigational hazards that flights in this region may encounter has so far sufficed at keeping the more shadowy side of Terran affairs quiet. \n\nAnyone navigating this area should remain cautious.</t>
 <t id="1030113">When the Teladi Space Company first made motions to lay claim to the Sector that is now known as CEO's Wellspring, they made a considerable amount of hosility from the Split Dynasty who accused the Teladi of attempting to &quot;strangle them from two fronts&quot;. in an attempt to annex Family Whi in an effort to bridge the territorial gap between The Vault and Teladi Gain.\n\nThe case was deffered to the Profit Guild who ruled in favor of the Split Dynasty and declared that the Teladi Space Company's expansionism was a threat to the Split Dynasty's sovereignity.\n\nThe resolution was to leave the sector unclaimed rather than contested, and while the name still bears the mark of the Teladi Space Company's intent to claim it for their own, it now remains open to independent development from interested neutral parties.</t>
 <t id="1030115">Deciding to work &quot;top down&quot; instead of &quot;bottom up&quot; and hoping to shift the paradigm while pushing the envelope in regards to local trading operations, Pyramid Income is a wealthy high-tech industrial system that has seen funding primarily from the Profit Guild rather than the Teladi Company with the aim of providing technological support to the mining operations currently taking place in Mines of Fortune and the adjacent sectors.\n\nNow home to a number of high-tech businesses, Pyramid Income has become leading hub for high-tech innovation and development, accounting for a small but noticeable percentage of all of the venture capital investment in Teladi space.</t>
 <t id="1030116">Believed to be situated on the edges of Kha'ak space, Soulstar is an unusual sector that is as ominously beautiful as it is quietly threatening. \n\nPirate activity in this region has lead to it being declared an anarchy sector by the Teladi Space Company, and numerous explorers and cartographers have reported coming under attack from hostile forces, leading many to believe that there is a hidden pirate base in this area.\n\nWhile the Teladi Space Company do have plans to expand into this sector, there is substantial concern that there may be far darker secrets lurking within the shadows of this sector than just pirate bases...</t>
 <t id="1030117">Sector Is Not Recognised in the Database.</t>
 <t id="1030318">It is said that &quot;Spires of Illusion&quot; was discovered by a lost Lar of Boron Kingdom after a jumpdrive malfunction left him and a contingent of the Boron Royal Family stranded in unfamilar space. \n\nTo everyone's surprise \(and subsequent relief\), the Lar and his Princess passenger appeared in Hila's Joy one month later with tales of undiscovered territories, adventures upon the cold black seas, and a blossoming romance that spawned a number of popular holodramas across Boron space.\n\nThe Lar was eventually knighted, and it is said that he and the Princess eventually married as a result of their misadventures.\n\nAs for Spires of Illusion, the sector remains unclaimed while the Royal Boron Navy focus their attention and resources on developing the nearby sector of Aquata, leaving it open to development by independent parties.</t>
 <t id="1030320">Originally discovered by Bala Gi Research Inc. shortly after Venturer's Sentinel was founded by the Argon Federation, Aquata was billed as the solution to many of the Boron Kingdom's resource problems in the north-eastern territories, as well as a haven of many interesting discoveries - a deactivated gate among them, leading researchers to marvel at what new sectors might sleep behind it.\n\nWhen the gate abruptly became active and Xenon began to pour out in force, many of the dreams of those Bala Gi scientists were quickly shattered once it became clear that they had stumbled upon a &quot;back door&quot; into Xenon Sector 597, and the area was promptly abandoned.\n\nHowever, in recent jazuras, the Royal Boron Navy have taken it upon themselves to revive Aquata in an attempt to follow the original vision set forth by Bala Gi Research Inc. when they first claimed the area in the name of Queen Atreus. \n\nSince that time, a hastily constructed Military Outpost has been established near to the northern gate in an attempt to intercept any Xenon threats before they become a problem, while the rest of the sector has been geared towards energy production to fuel the rest of the local economy.\n\nWith Boron forces tied up defending Menelaus' Paradise from major Xenon incursions and guarding Hila's Joy from Split aggression, very few military assets have been assigned to Aquata to help defend it should it face a Xenon invasion, leading many to wonder just how successful - and wise - the plan to develop this area will be.</t>
 <t id="1030411">Situated in proximity to Uranus's largest moon, Titania, ATF Forseti is the AGI Task Force's main conventional base of operations within the Solar System, and is equipped to deal with every operation or contingency that the ATF may have to commit to as part of their operational scope.\n\nAside from housing ATF Command, ATF Forseti is also home to the ATF Military Flight School and ATF Central Intelligence Service stations, and is host to a Goner Trading Port as part of the Terran's commitment towards furthering trade-relations with the Goner sect.</t>
 <t id="1030420">Situated between Ringo Moon on the western edges of the galaxy and Ocean of Fantasy on the eastern edges, Venturer's Sentinel is a dark yet vitally important trade link between two previously distant regions of the Boron Kingdom and the Argon Federation.\n\nWhile host to a number of military contractors and their weapon producing facilities, the sector is also home to a Goner Trading Station preaches Gunne's Legacy to any and all that will listen, be they Argon or otherwise. \n\nVenturer's Sentinel has also recently started to come under increasing attack from Yaki forces who believe that annexing and subsequently blockading the system will force the Argon Federation to sit up and take notice of their demands.</t>
 <t id="1030508">&quot;Gamma I&quot; is located roughly two-fifths of the way into the Oort Cloud within the disc-shaped inner &quot;Hill Cloud&quot; region</t>
 <t id="1030509">&quot;Gamma II&quot; is located roughly three-fifths of the way into the Oort Cloud within the disc-shaped inner &quot;Hill Cloud&quot; region.</t>
 <t id="1030516">Keen to take full advantage on the ongoing internal conflict between the Split Families of Nyj, Tkr, Ryk, and Zyarth, and happy to exploit the greater hostilities between the Split Dynasty and the Boron of the &quot;North-East Territories&quot;, Thuruk's Incorporated have chosen to settle in this system and convert it into their main base of operations within the Commonwealth, providing arms and equipment to any who have the desire - and financial backing - to afford them.</t>
 <t id="1030520">Discovered by elements of the Argon Navy's 506th Space Expeditionary Group based out of Venturer's Sentinel, this sector was found to contain a second jump gate that linked to a previously deactivated gate in the Split Sector of Zyarth's Dominion.\n\nQuick to latch on to anything that might give them an advantage over their enemies \(especially those within the Split Dynasty itself\), the Split Family Zyarth laid claim to this sector as their own, and skirmishes between warriors of Family Zyarth and the Argon Navy soon broke out, earning the sector its name of &quot;Twisted Skies&quot;.\n\nWhile both sides have since withdrawn from the area, the sector remains contested.\n\nHowever, to date neither the Split Dynasty nor the Argon Federation have actually formally attempted to claim it for themselves in an official capacity, leaving the area open to independent development.</t>
 <t id="1030608">Located on the furthest reaches of the Oort Cloud, the McCallum Relay is home to the United Space Command's Main Operating Base \(MOB\) and central supply depot, as well as a number of other support stations essential to the Terran economy.\n\nIt is interesting to note that the McCallum Relay exists at the furthest point from the Sun within the Sol System. At a distance of roughly 50,000 AU, this places McCallum Relay at nearly a quarter of the distance to Proxima Centauri, the nearest star to the Sun.\n\nAs with the USC Flagship, the McCallum Relay is named after a Terran pilot who died in the line of duty attempting to salvage a Xenon prototype jumpship, and has since become symbolic of the valor of the men and women of the United Space Command.</t>
 <t id="1030609">&quot;Gamma III&quot; is located roughly four-fifths of the way into the Oort Cloud within the spherical outer region.</t>
 <t id="1030610">Tharka's Ravine is a relatively quiet system that the liberal Split Family Thi have established under authority from Family Rhonkar mostly as a means by which to prevent the Teladi from advancing further towards their territory from the direction of Pilgrim's Casino, and to try to curb some of the unwanted cultural influences that tend to drift into Split space from that direction from time to time.\n\nIt is thought that Family Thi are considering developing this system into a major trade hub at some point in the future that will take full advantage of traffic passing through the adjacent sectors in an effort to avoid Xenon Sector 347; but for the moment Tharka's Ravine exists as a sector that the Split Dynasty can send wounded warriors to recover in relative peace.</t>
 <t id="1030613">In the days when the Nividium Mining and Manufacturing Corporation were still known as PTNI and the legal battle with the Teladi Chamber of Commerce, PTNI did all that it could to generate additional revenue so that it could cover the oncoming legal costs without having to dip into the core profits of their on-going mining operation.\n\nOne of the ways in which they accomplished this was to auction off a recently discovered sector east of PTNI Headquarters in the wake of the initial expedition finding little of profitable interest. PTNI found a buyer, but the Profit Guild raised concerns when the entrepreneur in question turned out to be a notable Teladi pirate lord. \n\nBlinded by profit, PTNI downplayed this description of their client, and even went so far as to receive a non-binding legal agreement that their new pirate friend would not cause mischief or permit the sector to be used for pirate operations. True to his word, the sector has remained loosely &quot;Independent&quot; to this day, and in return PTNI \(and now NMMC\) have turned a blind eye to any openly illegal activities that may or may not be taking place in that sector.\n\nIt is unknown who registered the sector name of &quot;Credits Received&quot;, but it is a name that tells a story - a story about how much the Teladi will do for the sake of profit.</t>
 <t id="1030618">Though it was once named &quot;Dynasty's Fire&quot; and intended as a future area of expansion for the Split Family Njy, the on-going feud between Family Njy, Family Ryk, and Family Zyarth saw any attempt to colonize this sector thwarted, and then any subsequent attempt to colonize the sector by another family thwarted in turn time and time again.\n\nThis is the legacy of Skullweaver as it is now: a sector perpetually contested by three families who are all actively seeking to claim the sector as their own, oblivious to the fact that the sector has descended into anarchy around them.</t>
 <t id="1030621">&quot;Mu Epsilon&quot; was the first sector detected by Family Zyarth deep space reconnaissance after the settling of &quot;Zyarth's Dominion&quot; and &quot;Zyarth's Stand&quot;. However, due to large graviational forces being detected and initial scans reporting nothing particularly out of the ordinary in the near-gate asteroids, further expansion into this sector was abandoned in favour of the more promising &quot;Twisted Skies&quot;.\n\nIt is thought that there may be a black hole near to this sector which would account for the unusually high gravitational forces. This puts extra strain on a ship or station's manoeuvring thrusters in order to remain at station-keeping relative to the sector. The lack of a significant number of mineral-rich asteroids, the extra strain put on a ship's engines due to the gravitational forces, and possibility of a Xenon incursion should the Zyarth family defences be overwhelmed, means that this sector is likely to remain unclaimed for the forseable future. However, these &quot;features&quot; of Mu Epsilon will discourage pirates from venturing into this sector, so it may make a suitable home for a pilot seeking a quiet life - at least until Family Zyarth are defeated and the Xenon start to poor through the west gate!</t>
 <t id="1030710">Saiien II is named for the second major planet in the Saiien System, with the sector itself being named for the yellow dwarf at the center. It is a recently discovered system that no Commonwealth race currently has plans to develop, even though it is situated in a potentially strategic location that bridges the gap between Split and Teladi space without the need to travel through Xenon Sector 347.\n\nIt is also rumoured that there is a third gate in this part of the Saiien System that leads to Saiien III, although such claims have yet to be founded.</t>
 <t id="1030711">Located in orbit of the third major planet in the Saiien System, Saiien III, this sector is home to a a pirate syndicate faction known as the Cabal. \n\nSaiien III is a remarkable for being a hellish region of the Saiien System that is saturated by radiation from the solar flares that Saiien occasionally unleashes upon the system. That the Cabal care little for such cosmic events should give pause to anyone thinking of crossing their path.</t>
 <t id="1030717">Discovered by a Goner Ranger while seeking out potential locations for a second home for the Goner Faction, Guiding Star was dismissed in favor of the sector of Lightseeker due to it being &quot;too close to Elysium of Light&quot; and equally &quot;too close to hostile elements&quot; - namely those of Xenon Sector 427, the pirate Sectors of Scionfire and Skullweaver, and the Paranid Empire to the south.\n\nWhile the Goner retain some degree of ownership upon the Sector, they do so only to prevent other Commonwealth races from laying claim to the area, and the region remains open to development from independent parties should they wish to take on the responsibility for themselves.</t>
 <t id="1030718">Named for the yellow dwarf main sequence star at the heart of this sector, Scionfire was once host to the flourishing mining colony of &quot;President's Gambit&quot; that was established following a successful expedition lead by the Plutarch Mining Corporation.\n\nThe colony quickly expanded and established itself a profitable venture that in-part helped to develop the economy of Interworlds, but was ultimately evacuated and abandoned ten Jazuras ago when Scionfire began to emit deadly solar flares of an unprecedented and entirely unanticipated magnitude. It has since fallen into anarchy.</t>
 <t id="1030719">Duke's Nemesis is a relatively young but generally thriving independent mining community that was established in the same spirit as locations such as Herron's Nebula. \n\nThe people of this Sector are known as &quot;Cuffs&quot; \(a play on the word &quot;Duke&quot; also being a term for fighting\) and are known to be a hardy, pragmatic, and generally welcoming group who are suspicious of outsiders but loyal to those who have earned their trust.\n\nThey also have the reputation of being able to down enough Space Fuel to kill an Argnu and still be able to operate mining equipment. In fact, a lot of those who work on the asteroids in this Sector are often drunk while doing so.\n\nThe Sector itself is named after the ship that originally bore the name: &quot;Duke's Nemesis&quot; - a Titan Mk I that was said to have faced down vastle superior Paranid foes, and defeated them all before succumbing to its wounds.\n\n</t>
 <t id="1030810">What started as an overspill sector of New Income eventually blossomed into something of an anomaly for the Teladi when a number of influential members of the Profit Guild decided to build a number of dens of vice upon the main planet of Zuzuamis.\n\nBilling itself as The Entertainment Capital of the Universe, Pilgrim's Casino is famous for its casino resorts and associated entertainment and the sheer amount of avarice and lasciviousness that takes place here. \n\nIt should also be noted that this sector has become exceptionally popular with the Paranid more than any other race - especially those who claim to be &quot;ultra-conservative&quot; in their normal lives. Still, what happens in Pilgrim's Casino stays in Pilgrim's Casino... most of the time.</t>
 <t id="1030813">Established as an operating base for the Argon Federation's Seventh Expeditionary Air Wing, Farpoint Relay has quickly been developed into a general equipment supply region for the Federal Argon Navy as whole, with a local economy geared towards providing logistics and provisions for forces active in Black Hole Sun.</t>
 <t id="1030815">Situated between the Argon territory of Nathan's Voyage and the Operation Final Fury staging area of Argon Sector M148, &quot;Eta Psi&quot; is a relatively large Sector that hosts a number of untapped resources, and is likely to be essential in supporting the nearby operation against the Kha'ak menace. \n\nWhile this sector is generally accessible, very few details about its existence are actually available to the public domain due to a media blackout being enforced by both the Argon Federal Navy and the Split Dynasty, and extending to their allies within the Foundation Guild and the Profit Guild alike.</t>
 <t id="1030903">Under pressure and scrutiny from the Paranid Government to explain their rumoured links to the Yaki Syndicate, Holy Dimensions have established this sector - allegedly with the blessing and backing of the Pontifus Maximus - as a base of operations in an attempt to turn the negative attention to their advantage.\n\nProviding local Paranid sectors with various high-tech equipment and supplies, Holy Dimensions hope to use the recent interest to highlight all the &quot;good&quot; that the corporation does for the Paranid Empire and her people - after all, no publicity is bad publicity, and if people are watching their every move then that just makes it all the easier to showcase products that those same people might be interested in.\n\nThe word &quot;Chi&quot; has been borrowed from old Argonian vernacular and means &quot;Life Energy&quot;. Thus, thus Sector is the &quot;Life Energy&quot; of the Holy Dimensions Corporation - a concept that many within the Paranid Church seem please with. \n\nWhile the Paranid do have their own word for &quot;Life Energy&quot;, semantic drift since the first Xenon War has seen the term become an offensive slur in over 427 different languages across the Commonwealth, and does not really make for good PR material.</t>
 <t id="1030905">While the Paranid Empire has always considered itself lucky to be free of most Xenon aggression, the discovery of Xenon Relay 479 adjacent to Preacher's Refuge came as such a shock that the Priest Duke refused to believe it was anything but an elaborate hoax until an entire squadron of the Priest Duke's own scouts went missing without a trace. \n\nThe Priest Duke has since vowed that the Paranid Imperial Navy will wrest control of this sector from the Xenon - but is a threat that the Xenon pay little heed to as they slowly and surely draw their plans against the Paranid.</t>
 <t id="1030909">Having once been auctioned by the Teladi Space Company and then subsequently purchased and developed by a private corporation, Avarice has an interesting history linked to the exploits of Julian Brennan, Don Toni Marani, various Goner legends, the Kha'ak invasion, and an entity known as Sargon.\n\nSituated between the Argon sector of Montalaar and the Teladi sector of New Income, the opportunity for a private corporation to develop this region of space remains high, and while other privateers may have come and gone \(leaving relics of their passing in their wake\), it is likely that Avarice will continue to see interest from independent parties for many jazuras to come.</t>
 <t id="1030913">Shrouded by the shadows of the dark diffuse nebula of Mayonaka, this sector was originally claimed by the Profit Guild in the hope of emulating a project of shared ownership similar to those of Getsu Fune and Nikkonofune. \n\nHowever, every construction vessel that has been sent to this system has either been hijacked or destroyed, forcing the Profit Guild to abandon their plans rather than commit a military force to the region.\n\nActing as a convenient route between Farpoint Relay and Homily of Perpetuity that allows traders to avoid Xenon Sector 347, it is advised that anyone travelling through this sector does so with extreme caution.</t>
 <t id="1030921">An independent system located on the outskirts of Teladi space, Privateer Gate is host to the planet of the same name, and is populated by a wide selection of races from across the galaxy who have \(for whatever reason\) become disillusioned with life in the Commonwealth and have seen fit to try and &quot;go it alone&quot; without their assistance. \n\nWhile the path of many systems that follow this route often ends in anarchy, the population of Privateer Gate are notable for having made a very good show of things, boasting a strong planetary-based economy, a relatively high GDP rating, and comparatively low rates of crime and illness.\n\nThere is an underlying question of just how the people of Privateer Gate have managed to become so prosperous, however, for the space between the main gates of this sector is unusually safe and free of the usual detritus that independent systems seem to attract. \n\nThere are many who speculate that Privateer Gate may be under the protection of a mysterious benefactor...</t>
 <t id="1031011">An unusual sector in nature if otherwise unremarkable in content, &quot;Xi&quot; has been ear-marked as a possible location for future Teladi Space Company expansion, but is mostly held as an area of scientific interest at the moment. \n\nIt is home to a curious sight: in the relative &quot;middle&quot; of the Sector rests a broken Jump Gate surrounded by what appears to be a cluster of asteroids that were evidently caught in some kind of gravitational pull and subsequent orbit during whatever event caused the Jump Gate to be destroyed.\n\nThe effects of that gravitational pull have long since subsided, with the asteroids now &quot;stuck&quot; in place; however, the investigation into what could have caused such an unusual local stellar event are still on-going.</t>
 <t id="1031019">Burning within the fires of the protoplanetary nebula that it is named for, Hell Forge makes up roughly one-third of area known as the Gaian Badlands.\n\nAs dangerous to traverse as it is treacherous to navigate, the region is fully under the control of the Gaian Star pirate factions who guard their territory with all the fervour of a pack of rabid dogs, lashing out at anyone who would dare encroach upon their domain.\n\nPilots who seek to use Hell Forge as a short-cut between Merchant Haven and Credits Denied should do so with utmost care, for any vessel that enters this system is considered by the pirates to be their property, and they will not hesitate to take it should you be unfortunate enough to attract their attention...</t>
 <t id="1031102">A veritable maze of asteroids and debris set within the depths of the Hades nebula, the Paranid believe that this sector is where the souls of the unclean and unfaithful are condemned to once they are are purged from this life, and as such consider this sector to be cursed.</t>
 <t id="1031103">A substantially &quot;White Collar&quot; sector of the universe if ever there was one, Creditania is the &quot;Home Sector&quot; of the Creditania Property Holdings and Shares Corporation - specialists in &quot;High-Quality Office, Retail, Industrial and Trade Counter Properties and Stations&quot;, among other things.\n\nThe main eponymously named world of &quot;Creditania&quot; is known a haven of financial and investment opportunity and success, and boasts some of the most influential labour unions and solicitors and attorneys in the universe. The surface of the planet is mostly dominated by glittering financial districts that comprises the offices and headquarters of many of the Profit Guild's major financial institutions, including the Teladi Stock Exchange and the Imperial Reserve Bank of Paranidia. \n\nThe area in orbit of Creditania is mostly dedicated to &quot;high-tech&quot; industry, offering a very &quot;clean&quot; and &quot;innocent&quot; public face to try and subvert \(or even cover up\) claims of corporate skulduggery. Beyond Creditania's own sales in the area, the Corporation has also begun investing in small-scale and private operations and business - especially those wishing to make a start in the mining industry.</t>
 <t id="1031105">Attempting to prevent a potential economical downturn in the region due to poor investments in Bad Debt, the Teladi Space Company have invested heavily in this Sector in an effort to promote continual economic stimulus.\n\nOriginally named &quot;CEO's Invoice&quot;, the Sector was initially only concerned with minor agriculture and produce production, with the inhabitants of the original colonies content to eke out a relatively humble life away from the profitable adventures of their fellow Teladi.\n\nHowever, since the Teladi Space Company's substantial investment in the defence contractor sector, CEO's Investment has experienced an economic boom that has quickly seen it turn into the bustling core system it is today.\n\nNotable for its Teladi-based weapons development trade and as being a main through-fare between Split and Paranid Space, the Sector also offers logistics, technical support and training communications support, and in some cases team-based engineering services in cooperation with the Profit Guild, as part of what it offers to the Commonwealth as a whole.</t>
 <t id="1031106">Solitas is an unusual and somewhat foreboding sector with an equally dramatic history. It is said that the Royal Boron Navy engaged and ultimately destroyed a large Xenon vessel of an unknown design as it was attempting to build a relay station within the debris field of the sundered planet for which the sector is named.\n\nThe Boron suffered heavy losses, but succeeded in preventing the sector from falling to the Xenon and being used to launch further strikes against nearby Boron sectors.\n\nWhile many vessels and fallen Boron were recovered and repatriated in the wake of the conflict, a few vessels have been left behind as a silent memorial to the battle that took place here.</t>
 <t id="1031109">Concerned about the increasing unrest in the region, the Paranid Defence Directorate established Age of Oedipus and its dedicated Communications Facility to monitor pirate activity in the local region and to provide security for the fledgling mining operations within Clarity's End, Third Redemption, and Perdition's End.\n\nRumours whisper that the many military-based facilities that this sector holds are also infested with agents of Duke's Buccaneers, and that worry that the Argon Federation may use local pirate activity as an excuse to annex Clarity's End in the name of national security is fuelling a level of paranoia that may eventually lead to unforeseen consequences...</t>
 <t id="1031119">It is said that the Gaian Star pirates have substantial influence within the sector known as &quot;Transaction Denied&quot;, and have used this influence to counter the pressure that the Profit Guild have been exerting in an attempt to have the local independent populace amalgamate with the Teladi Space Company.\n\nThe name of the sector can therefore be considered a taunt aimed at the Teladi Space Company itself; a taunt that states, &quot;you'll never get your scaly claws on this territory!&quot; \n\nThat the name is so similar to the nearby Teladi sector of &quot;Credits Denied&quot; is no coincidence either...\n\nWith the population of Nasilia \(the main planet of the sector\) being mixed race, the eyes of the rest of the Commonwealth are upon the Teladi Space Company to see how they will react, for under such intense scrutiny it seems that a military-based annexation of the system is out of the question. \n\nCultural and diplomatic courting remains from the Teladi side of the equation - but with the Gaian clans holding as much sway as they do, and with the cautionary tale of Talonfire fresh in the minds of the populace, it is unlikely that the people of Nasilia and Transaction Denied on the whole will ever succumb to Teladi rule.</t>
 <t id="1031201">With the help of both the Argon Federation and the Royal Kingdom of Boron, the Goner have established this sector as their &quot;Home Away From Home&quot;, and have directed their operations here towards the pursuit of knowledge and exploration. \n\nHere one can find a number of satellite production facilities for use in future expeditions, as well as a shipyard to provide those who wish to further the Goner's cause with the tools with which to do just that.\n\nWhile Elysium of Light remains the hub from which the Goner seek to preach the truth of Gunne's Crusade to ensure it lives on for all eternity, their colony upon Lightseeker is dedicated to the preservation of much of their written history and lore, and to that end is host to a number of impressive archives and libraries.</t>
 <t id="1031206">Tempestine is a recently discovered sector between the Split sector of Rhonkar's Trial and the Paranid sector of Clarity's End that neither race have yet seen fit to expand into, in part due to a disagreement over who should actually take control of it.\n\nIt is notable for having gates that are in close proximity to the eponymously named star of the sector, and the three planetoids it has captured within close orbit that now burn within the sundering tumults of blinding heat and unforgiving solar radiation. \n\nWhile initial attempts to settle within this sector have mostly ended in disaster, reports of increased pirate activity in the area some have been more successful than others in gaining a foothold under these conditions.</t>
 <t id="1031215">Sector Is Not Recognised in the Database.</t>
 <t id="1031217">Sector Is Not Recognised in the Database.</t>
 <t id="1031219">Established in the aftermath of the Talonfire Rebellion, Credits Denied stands as the counterpart to Merchant Haven - the second set of gates on the southern side of the Gaian Badlands aimed at keeping the local pirate factions contained and out of Teladi space - and as such is usually bustling with military traffic or repair crews waiting to receive transports that have dared to brave the Maelstrom to bring supplies in from Grand Exchange.\n\nWhile also acting as a southern aegis against the pirate threat, Credits Denied has also been developed to become the main staging area for the Teladi Space Company should it ever wish to push through the Gaian Badlands and eradicate the corsair presence there, as well as being the hub for all of the Profit Guild's attempts to have the nearby independent sector join the fold.\n\nIt should also be noted that while the name &quot;Credits Denied&quot; was originally chosen as a symbolic message to the Gaian Pirates that they would find little profit in piracy in this sector, the name has since been hijacked and used against the Teladi Space Company via the registration of the name &quot;Transaction Denied&quot; for the independent sector to the north. \n\nSuch mockery has done little to weaken the resolve of the Teladi who are stationed in this area, however, who are notable for being a substantially harder and less personable breed than their counterparts.</t>
 <t id="1031301">Following the relative success of Getsu Fune, the Argon Federation and Royal Kingdom of Boron sought to try and emulate the same kind of mutual cooperation on a smaller scale.\n\nThe result of that project was Nikkonofune - a sector that is considered to be within Boron territory, but also plays host to a number of stations belonging to the Argon Federation that retain sovereign diplomatic status free of Boron authority.\n\nThe sector itself is named after a notable Boron Barracuda that an Argon pilot by the name of Saya once flew in the service of Terracorp. The name of a Boron ship flown by an Argon seemed sufficiently symbolic of this sector's intent.</t>
 <t id="1031302">Since its discovery several Jazuras ago, Matriarch's Thorn has become something of an enigma to the neighbouring Boron authorities. It is populated with many "liberal-minded" Split who think that the constant hostilities with the Boron Kingdom are damaging the Split Empire. Boron patrols in Nikkonofune were shocked when Split traders began to come through the Matriarch's Thorn gate asking for permission to dock and trade.\n\nAs one of the furthest sectors from the Split homeworld, military patrols have been relatively light, and even some Boron traders have been brave enough to attempt to cross the border.\n\nUntil recently the Split military have had little interest in this sector. However, as the Boron have redirected resources to other, more volatile areas, rumours have begun to surface to suggest that this sector is now being seen by the military as a relatively undefended backdoor into Boron territory.</t>
 <t id="1031308">Eager to exploit the many natural and mostly untapped resources that are so abundant in the surrounding regions, the Trinity Corporation - with support from the Paranid Government - has established this headquarters as a main base from which to stage mining operations in the area, and to continually supply their fleet \(and any private contractors on their payroll\) with all necessary equipment in the process.\n\nIt is also hoped that the Trinity Corporations efforts in this area will stimulate regional economies and stabilize the region in an effort to make &quot;honest&quot; work and profit more lucrative to the local populace instead of the avarice and penuriousness offered by the pirate factions and clans who are also vying for control of the local Gate systems.</t>
 <t id="1031316">Sector Is Not Recognised in the Database.</t>
 <t id="1031320">Primarily populated by refugees from the former colony of CEO's Reach, the Teladi Space Company used this sector to launch the hasty and ill-planned attempts to reclaim Talonfire after it fell to rebellion.\n\nNow that the dust has settled, the sector has become a popular tourist destination due to the estimated collision between the two planets of Hohindras and Rurandis, with the Teladi Space Company billing Overmaster's Talon as being &quot;the only place in the galaxy where you can watch worlds collide from the safety* of your own ship&quot;!\n\nThe legal documentation and disclaimers that follow the * are impressive even by Teladi standards.</t>
 <t id="1031408">This sector was originally known as &quot;Eternal Tide&quot;, and for much of its initial history was of little interest to anyone other than the Boron Kingdom, who used it primarily for scientific study and cartographic equipment testing.\n\nHowever, all of this changed when a Priest King of the Paranid Empire \(while travelling through the sector\) declared that he saw messages from Xaar written in the way the asteroids and planets had been aligned.\n\nSo sure was he of this revelation that he petitioned the Priest Emperor specifically ask that the Paranid Empire request that the Boron Kingdom do not lay claim to the sector \(which should remain free of taint\) - and, in exchange, neither would the Paranid Empire itself.\n\nTo everyone's astonishment, the Priest Emperor agreed, and a &quot;non-development&quot; pact was established between the two races. To this day, the sector has remained a &quot;buffer zone&quot; between the eastern Paranid Empire and the south-western Boron Territories as a result.\n\nHowever, an interesting legal loophole exists in that the pact only mentions the five Commonwealth races; no mention is made of independent parties claiming the sector as their own, leaving this &quot;Cathedraal of Xaar&quot; free to develop.</t>
 <t id="1031415">Sector Is Not Recognised in the Database.</t>
 <t id="1031417">Sector Is Not Recognised in the Database.</t>
 <t id="1031420">The Teladi Space Company lost control of this sector after a successful rebellion instigated by a female Teladi by the name of Raelisora Denarius III. \n\nWhile the establishment of a trade link between CEO's Reach and the previously distant Boron sector of Depth's of Silence promptly caused the sector's economy to flourish, with wealth came corruption of the kind that was perpetually fuelled by the avarice that spawned it; and as the distribution of that wealth shifted more and more to the minority, so did the division between the rich and the poor deepen. \n\nSeeking to end the huge divide and injustice between the rich and the poor once and for all, Raelisora lead her supporters in such a swift and glorious revolution that took the Teladi Space Company entirely by surprise. The population of CEO's Reach annexed the sector soon after, renaming it &quot;Talonfire&quot; in honour of the uprising that birthed it.\n\nWith Governor Raelisora III now in charge of the administration of the sector, Talonfire is defiantly independent, and intends to remain that way.</t>
 <t id="1031501">Located within the misty reach of the Mijukumono Nebula, this sector is the base of operations for the Boron Waverider Corporation - a company who specialise in the manufacturing of water reprocessing and filtration units for Boron Starships.\n\nWhile this sector was originally held by the Atreus' Shipbuilding Currents Corporation, Atreus was petitioned by the Royal Kingdom of Boron to gift the sector to the Waverider Corporation in an effort to promote harmony and continued serendipity between otherwise rival companies.\n\nReeling from their losses in Atreus' Delta, the Atreus' Shipbuilding Currents Corporation agreed to the request under the agreement that the Waverider Corporation would provide them with reprocessing and filtration units free of charge, and the Sector is now jointly governed by representatives from both corporations and the Royal Kingdom of Boron.\n\nWhile the orbital economy is mostly geared towards providing equipment required by interested parties in Depths of Silence and Blue Arrow as part of the Boron's continuing conflict with the Split Dynasty, the main planet in the system - Heiwakokka - is primarily concerned with scientific research and development of technologies of importance to agriculture and terraforming.\n\nThe oceans of Heiwakokka of notable for their strange emerald luminescence at night - a feature caused by algae in the water that has, over the centuries, adapted to feed off the ionized radiation emitted by the Nebula that is absorbed into the ocean once it passes through the atmosphere.</t>
 <t id="1031504">Skirting the fringe of the Buru-Burakku Nebula, Blue Storm has been established in support of the adjacent sector of Blue Arrow, and features both a Royal Boron Shipyard and Research Station that work in tandem to build new vessels for the Royal Boron Navy \(should any be lost in combat\) and to repair and re-equip any that have suffered damage.\n\nWhile Blue Storm's local economy is mostly dedicated to ship-building, scientific research, and the production of energy-cells for Blue Arrow, the gas giant of Rosutoboru makes for a remarkable bright landmark within the otherwise cold depths of the blue nebula.</t>
 <t id="1031505">Established as a &quot;Rear Guard&quot; sector in the wake of notable Split Aggression in the sectors of Barren Shores and Reservoir of Tranqulity, the Royal Kingdom of Boron quickly developed Blue Arrow into a staging- and supply-area for the Royal Boron Navy.\n\nThe planet of Daiamondo itself is something of an untouched paradise, with breath-taking vistas and incredible ocean scenes to be found virtually everywhere.\n\nA gemstone known as the Suta-Safaia is also a notable feature of Daiamondo, and it is said that there is an entire mountain that has formed of the substance. It is thought Daiamondo will one day become an affluent tourist destination.</t>
 <t id="1031508">There is little recorded history of who once called this sector home, nor any memory of the people or race that inhabited this independent sector. \n\nWhat is known, however, is that those who once lived here stood little chance against the Xenon who invaded; the silent relics of their stations are now the only testament to their existance and subsequent passing.</t>
 <t id="1031520">Believed to be part of Kha'ak space, Tau Sigma is a mysterious and foreboding sector that it as once both terrifying as it is breath-taking. Thought to be hiding dark and terrible secrets within its nigh impenetrable depths, this is one region of space that even angels are reluctant to tread.</t>
 <t id="1031602">What was once merely &quot;Unknown System 1-15&quot; took on the name &quot;Atreus's Delta&quot; following an expedition into the Sector that told of a promise of an unactivated Gate that would lead to Kingdom's End and &quot;seams of untapped Nividium&quot; of the kind that would make even the Kha'ak jealous.\n\nThe Atreus' Shipbuilding Currents Corporation took advantage of the report, discovered the gate \(which connected to Rolk's Drift\), and began to develop the Sector in earnest - only to discover that the promise of &quot;more Nividium than you can handle&quot; was hollow and little more than a lure used by Thuruk's Incorporated to bring vessels belonging to Atreus into neutral ground in order to sabotage their assets without penalty from the Profit Guild.\n\nThe ruse worked, and Atreus quickly lost a number of stations and personnel to a hit-and-fade strike that involved a number of M7Ms and little in the way of counter-attack.\n\nChoosing to cut their losses and learn from their mistake, the Atreus' Shipbuilding Currents Corporation chose to withdraw from the sector entirely and seek safer waters to swim.\n\nEven though the sector is now prime retail estate for any would-be entrepreneur to take advantage of \(sitting, as it does, on a vital trade-link between the northern and southern Boron Territories\), the Boron Kingdom on the whole seems to be giving the area a wide berth for the moment, fearing that it might conceal more Split elements just waiting for the chance to ambush any bright-eyed and glossy-tentacled naive enough to stray into their crosshairs.\n</t>
 <t id="1031605">{19,1030000}</t>
 <t id="1031606">Believed to exist somewhere within an area of the universe that is - or was - part of Kha'ak Space, &quot;Zeta Rho&quot; is an omious yet mysteriously beautiful Sector of Commonwealth space that few explorers dare travel. \n\nWhile its main feature is the dense violet photo-luminescence from the dust particles and stellar gases that dominate the region, Zeta Rho is also notable for the thick density of asteroids that have apparently been caught and clustered together over thousands of millennia.\n\nAlthough these asteroids could potentially be exploited by an intrepid privateer or corporation and turned into a lucrative base of power, there are few within Commonwealth Space who even know this sector exists - and even fewer who are willing to risk their assets with the threat of the Kha'ak looming in every shadow. \n\nDauntless pioneers are advised to take care in this sector due to the poor levels of visibility caused by the nebula, and the large number of navigational hazards equally present in the area.</t>
 <t id="1031607">While it is thought that this region is located on the fringes of the Zeta Rho Nebula and is also potentially situated within the reach of Kha'ak Space, there is insufficient data in the navigational database to provide any further details about this Sector.</t>
 <t id="1031612">The Paranid Defence Directorate established a Communications Facility in this sector after the Priest Xaar foretold that it would become a location of exceptional importance in relation to future developments between the Split Dynasty and the security of the Paranid Empire.\n\nOne jazura after the Communications Facility was deemed operational, the Split Dynasty discovered the gate to Xenon Relay 741 in Matriarch's Vanguard.\n\nThe Paranid in Prophecy Fulfilled are now monitoring the situation closely; for if Matriarch's Vanguard were to fall to the Xenon, this sector would quickly become the aegis that would either hold the Xenon tide back, or break under its mighty force.</t>
 <t id="1031613">Said to have been the independent home sector of Kailan Weaver \(considered to be the founder of the Yaki faction as it is known today\), Appallox is a relatively unimportant yet potentially strategically important sector situated within the fringes of the Midori nebula.\n\nWhile primarily used as a thoroughfare between the eastern Paranid Empire and the Split, neither race have much interest in claiming it as their own, as both are happy to allow it to remain as a neutral buffer between their respective territories. \n\nThe Yaki, however, are actively seeking to annex this sector for the glory of Kailan Weaver; they believe that the colonies of Appallox are sympathetic to their cause, and eager to have the Yaki swoop into the sector to shield them from potential alien conquest.</t>
 <t id="1031614">Having once been little more than a basic outpost and staging area for forces heading into Contorted Dominion, Matriarch's Vanguard is swiftly becoming a developing sector in its own right, with the influx of military personnel attracting a number of prospective military contractors eager to take advantage of the resources in the region.\n\nSince the discovery of the gate leading to Xenon Relay 741, the dynamic in this sector has shifted from general rear-guard operations to prepare for a potential second-front situation against Xenon aggressors - something the Split assigned here are curiously thrilled about.</t>
 <t id="1031706">After securing their base of power within Weaver's Tempest, the Yaki allocated some of its resources towards securing a new sector isolated from the rest of the galaxy from which they could continue to fortify their infrastructure and develop their fleet further without harassment.\n\nFar removed from the trade-lanes and military patrols of the Commonwealth, the Yaki Sector of Redemption is the result of that goal, and has been quickly developed into a second fortified system from which the Yaki can plan further reprisals against their foes.\n\nContrary to popular conceptions about the Yaki dynamic, the main planet of Fortuna is a bastion of law and order. Their strict policy of governance values honor and dignity and community spirit above all else, and any crime that erodes these ideals - no matter how minor - is punishable by death.\n\nIt could be said that Fortuna - if not the entire sector itself - harbours more stability and security than even some of the most affluent Commonwealth systems do, with those living under Yaki rule experiencing both security and the benefits of high-technology regardless of their wealth or status.</t>
 <t id="1031708">{19,1030000}</t>
 <t id="1031711">Although most official records refuse to acknowledge that this sector is anything but an empty with absolutely nothing of interest to anyone in it, it is a poorly-kept secret that it is the home of Duke's Buccaneers.\n\nAs well as being neutral territory for varying pirate captains to gather and hear each other out, the main habitable planet in this sector - Arcadia by name - is a den of avarice and debauchery of the kind that would do the legacies of Tortuga and Port Royal proud. \n\nThere is a pirate legend that states that the oceans of Arcadia are filled not with water, but with Space Fuel; and that the only authority that anyone respects is a bottle of Jon Kayean's and the business-end of a trusty side-arm.</t>
 <t id="1031714">Discovered exactly a jazura to the day that the Communications Facility in the Paranid sector of Prophecy Fulfilled became fully operational, initial reports suggest that Xenon Relay 741 is being used as a staging area from which the Xenon can strike at the neighbouring Split Dynasty territories and beyond.</t>
</page>
</language>
